can I get rich if I just have a salary
如果我只拿工资，我能致富吗？
yeah if you want to make a couple
是的，如果你想做一对
million dollars 100% And can everybody
一百万美元，100%，而且人人都能做到
do that yes it's only not accessible to
是的，这样做只是无法访问。
you if you're a lazy piece of that wants
如果你是个懒惰的家伙，那你就是那种人。
to do nothing none of this is rocket
什么都不做，这一切都不是火箭。
science what you do so start with Cody
科学就是你所做的，所以从科迪开始吧。
Sanchez has taken her experience from
桑切斯从中汲取了她的经验
Wall Street to become a
华尔街将成为
multi-millionaire investor and business
身价数百万美元的投资者和企业
owner and now teaches millions of people
创始人，现在教授数百万人。
how to make money and be financially
如何赚钱并实现财务自由
free Cody if I set you the challenge of
如果你接受我的挑战，就释放科迪。
building your wealth from scratch what'
白手起家积累财富是什么？
you do okay step one you get with the
第一步你做得很好，你和……
biggest baddest guy or gal you can find
你能找到的最厉害的坏蛋
who's already successful and you do
谁已经成功了，而你……
everything possible to provide value to
尽一切可能创造价值
them and by the way it sucks but the
他们，顺便说一句，这很糟糕，但是
best advice for 20-year-old is to
给20岁年轻人的最佳建议是
realize that your 20s do suck but
要知道，你的二十几岁确实很糟糕，但
everybody focuses on how much money you
大家都在关注你有多少钱
make and start doing entrepreneurship
创业并开始创业
too early oh you can be a 20-year-old to
太早了，哦，你也可以是20岁的人
drive a Bugatti and play around with
开着布加迪到处玩玩
crypto huge mistake focus on learning
加密货币领域的巨大错误，应该专注于学习
and you're going to have no time for
你将没有时间……
anything except what your boss asks of
除了老板要求的以外，其他任何事都可以。
you but if you want to win and be
你，但如果你想赢，并成为
successful in life upfront pain always
人生成功之道在于克服前期的痛苦
leads to long-term gain how could I
如何才能带来长期收益？
manipulate or motivate you into giving
操纵或激励你给予
me a shock if you want to get in front
如果你想领先一步，我会很震惊的。
of a rich powerful person start with
一个富有的权势人物的开头是
where' you go from there make as much
你接下来要去哪里才能赚到这么多钱？
money as humanly possible from your
尽可能从你那里获得金钱
salary and invest in other side deals
薪水和投资其他副业
such as what I call gateway drug
例如我所说的入门毒品
businesses the business so simple that
企业经营如此简单，以至于
you can run it even if you've never run
即使你从未运行过，你也可以运行它。
a business before but how can I buy a
我以前拥有一家企业，但我该如何购买一家企业呢？
business I'm going to have to wait till
生意上我得等到……
I'm rich well there's actually way more
我很富有，其实远不止如此。
opportunity than anybody realizes
机会比任何人意识到的都要大。
because there's three ways to buy a
因为有三种购买方式
business one
商业一
is this is a sentence I never thought
这是我从没想过的一句话。
I'd say in my life um we've just hit 7
我想说，在我的人生中，我们刚刚到了7岁。
million subscribers on YouTube and I
我在YouTube上有数百万订阅者，而且我
want to say a huge thank you to all of
我要对所有人表示衷心的感谢。
you that show up here every Monday and
你们这些每周一都来这里的人
Thursday to watch our conversations um
周四观看我们的对话
from the bottom of my heart but also on
发自内心，但也……
behalf of my team who you don't always
代表我的团队，你并不总是……
get to meet there's almost 50 people now
见面的时候，现在差不多有50个人了。
behind the dire of a CEO that work to
在一位首席执行官的糟糕领导下，他努力工作
put this together so from all of us
我们把这一切汇集在一起​​。
thank you so much um we did a raffle
非常感谢！我们搞了个抽奖活动。
last month and we gave away prizes for
上个月我们送出了奖品
people that subscribed to the show up
订阅该节目的观众
until 7 million subscribers and you guys
直到700万订阅者，还有你们
love that raffle so much that we're
我们太喜欢那次抽奖活动了！
going to continue it so every single
将继续这样做，所以每一个
month we're giving away money can't buy
这个月我们送出千金难买的东西。
prizes including meetings with me
奖品包括与我见面。
invites to our events and £1,000 gift
活动邀请函及1000英镑礼品卡
vouchers to anyone that subscribes to
订阅者均可获得优惠券
the DI CE there's now more than 7
DI CE 现在有超过 7 个
million of you so if you make the
你们当中有数百万人，所以如果你做到了
decision to subscribe today you can be
今天决定订阅，您就可以……
one of those lucky people thank you from
其中一位幸运儿向我表示感谢
the bottom of my heart let's get to the
我发自内心地想，让我们开始吧。
[Music]
[音乐]
conversation
对话
Cody if you could encapsulate your
科迪，如果你能概括一下你的
message into a sentence what would that
将信息转换成句子会是什么？
sentence be but also
句子是，但也
though who exactly would that sentence
但究竟是谁会说出这句话呢？
be
是
for it would be the only way to have
因为那将是唯一能做到这一点的方法。
freedom is through ownership and the
自由源于所有权和
world doesn't want to give it to you and
世界不想把它给你，
that message is
那条信息是
for every human who's felt
对于每一个感受过这种感觉的人来说
disenfranchised and is a little bit of
被剥夺了权利，而且有点……
tired of other people directing their
厌倦了别人指挥他们
lives and wishes that they had their
他们的生活和愿望
hand on the helm
手放在舵上
instead and I think in today's day and
相反，我认为在当今时代，
age
年龄
ownership is something that people on
所有权是人们……
high say is bad you know [__] the big
说高是坏事，你知道去他妈的大
guys the rich people the owners and in
伙计们，有钱人，老板们，还有
reality that's just them saying they
实际上，那只是他们的说法而已。
want to be in charge instead of
想当老大而不是
you who isn't your message for who will
你，不是你的信息，对谁来说？
it just not resonate with and work for
它就是无法引起共鸣，也行不通。
Black Rock black stone most billionaires
黑石集团（Black Rock）是亿万富翁中的佼佼者。
who already know this I mean I think
知道这一点的人，我的意思是，我认为
that is the answer though the the
答案就是这个。
message will not resonate with people
这条信息不会引起人们的共鸣。
who think that they should own
那些认为他们应该拥有
everything and other people should ask
一切以及其他人应该问
for permission it won't res with people
获得许可不会与人有关
who um don't want to work kind of hard
那些不想努力工作的人
it sucks to be an owner anybody who's
当老板真够糟的，任何……
ever run a business has felt inside that
凡是经营过企业的人，内心都会有这种感觉。
horrible feeling on Friday when you
星期五那种糟糕的感觉，当你
don't have enough cash and payrolls
现金和工资支出不足
coming and you've got to figure out what
来了，你得弄清楚什么
to sell or what to give up in order to
为了什么而出售或放弃
pay your employees that's an awful
给员工支付过低的工资太糟糕了。
feeling um so it's not for people that
感觉……所以它不适合那些……
aren't willing to do the hard thing but
他们不愿意做难事，但
you know it kind of goes back to what
你知道，这其实又回到了什么问题上。
what we know to be true it sucks being
我们都知道，事实是，这很糟糕。
broke just as much as it sucks working
工作既糟糕又让人崩溃。
hard and so choose your heart your
艰难，所以选择你的心
message has resonated really profoundly
这条信息引起了我深刻的共鸣。
with millions and millions and millions
数以百万计，数以百万计
and millions of people you've built an
你为数百万人建立了一个
audience of millions of people across
数百万观众遍布各地
all of your social media channels it it
你的所有社交媒体渠道
appears that you've hit culture and the
看来你已经触及了文化和……
Zeitgeist with a particular message at a
时代精神及其特定信息
particular time do you spend much time
你会在特定时间段花费大量时间吗？
reflecting on why your message is so
反思为什么你的信息如此重要
resonant um right now that's interesting
共鸣，嗯，现在这很有意思。
it's hard right now to not think about
现在很难不去想这件事。
politics in some way shape or form and
政治以某种方式或形式存在
so I think when I think about politics
所以我觉得，当我思考政治的时候……
today what I really think about is who's
今天我真正想的是，谁是
in charge right and so I do think about
负责这件事，所以我确实会考虑这个问题。
why does one politician hit a cord why
为什么一位政治人物能引起共鸣？
does one not and and I think when I
难道没有人不这样吗？而且我觉得当我
think about my
想想我的
message what hits me closest to home is
最让我感同身受的信息是
that for some reason um a message right
不知为何，嗯，收到一条消息
now is is feeling true for many people
现在很多人都有这种感觉。
in the world that there's a lack of
在这个缺乏……的世界里
trust like trust in institutions trust
信任，就像对机构的信任一样。
in governments and big corporations in
在政府和大公司中
in the media you know I saw yesterday an
你知道，我在媒体上昨天看到了……
article about CNN this is fascinating
这篇关于CNN的文章真精彩
how many views do you think CNN got in
你觉得CNN的报道获得了多少点击量？
prime time for one week three hour
黄金时段，持续一周，三小时
segments every day prime time for one
每天黄金时段都有片段
week in
一周
May what do you think one show one show
五月，你觉得一场演出怎么样？一场演出
three hours for a week the cumulative of
每周累计三小时
three three hour show correct five
三小时节目正确五
million maybe I don't know
或许有百万，我不知道
83,000 that's crazy lowest level of all
83000，这简直太疯狂了，最低水平！
time Fox the highest was
狐狸最高纪录是
186,000 think about what is happening
18.6万人思考着正在发生的事情
right in front of us the media is no
就在我们眼前，媒体却……
longer actually reaching the masses
更难真正触及大众
because they've lost complete trust with
因为他们已经完全失去了对……的信任。
them in fact 30-year-olds right now for
事实上，他们现在都是30岁左右的人。
the first time ever 30-year-olds have
这是有史以来第一次30岁的人
more trust in you social media
社交媒体更值得信赖
influencers than they do the mainstream
影响者比主流媒体更受关注
media it's not the same for all age
媒体对所有年龄段的人来说并不相同。
groups but that is what I am seeing
我看到的都是些群体。
right in front of us is we're like show
就在我们眼前，我们就像在表演一样。
me what's real because I do not trust
我不信任任何人，所以无法告诉我什么是真实的。
puppets who parrot things from
鹦鹉学舌的木偶
teleprompters they know that you and I
提词器知道你和我
are having a real conversation there's
他们正在进行一场真正的对话。
no teleprompter in site when you look at
当你看着屏幕时，看不到提词器。
your notes look at your notes it's real
看看你的笔记，看看你的笔记，它是真的。
and I think that is what I'm realizing
我想这就是我正在意识到的。
with our message we have to be honest
我们必须坦诚地传达信息。
because nobody trusts anybody right now
因为现在没人信任任何人。
so if someone's just clicked onto this
所以如果有人刚刚点击了这个链接
conversation for whatever reason maybe
出于某种原因的谈话
they don't know who you are maybe they
他们可能不知道你是谁
they you know they're just clicking
你知道，他们只是在点击
because they it's the routine that they
因为这是他们的日常习惯。
have by the end of this conversation
到本次谈话结束时，我将……
what do you hope they come away with
你希望他们能从中获得什么？
what do you hope they're going to be
你希望他们会是什么样的人？
able to um Implement into their lives
能够将其融入到他们的生活中
following this conversation how to make
根据这次对话，如何制作
more money and why it matters that you
更多金钱以及为什么这对你很重要
make more money that's really it because
赚钱才是关键，仅此而已。
I think money is just a tool it's a tool
我认为金钱只是一种工具，它只是一种工具。
in your toolbox for you to be able to
你的工具箱里应该有这些东西，以便你能够……
have more freedom to do more things and
拥有更多自由去做更多的事情
to say no more often to say actually I
要更频繁地说“不”，要更频繁地说“实际上我”。
don't want to do that at all and because
我根本不想那样做，因为
I don't want to do that I need money to
我不想那样做，我需要钱。
push back and so by the end of this
反击，所以到最后……
conversation I think you should have a
我认为你们应该进行一次对话。
few ideas to be a little bit richer and
一些让自己更富有的想法
a little bit more free and can everybody
更自由一些，每个人都可以。
do that do you genuinely believe that
你真的相信这一点吗？
every think about everybody you've ever
你对所有人的一切想法
you know and everybody you've ever met
你认识的以及你认识的所有人
does the advice that you offer yeah um
你提供的建议是……嗯……
fit all of them is it accessible and
适合所有人吗？方便吗？
actionable for all of them
对他们所有人来说都可采取行动
my gut says yes it's only not accessible
我的直觉告诉我，是的，只是无法访问而已。
to you if you're a lazy piece of [__]
如果你是个懒惰的混蛋，那就这么对你吧
that wants to do nothing you know if you
你知道，如果你什么都不想做，
really want only to be given things you
你真正想要的只是别人给予你的东西
want to ask permission all the time and
总是想征求许可，
you aren't willing to work a little bit
你连一点点工作都不愿意做。
earlier in the morning and work a little
早上早点去，稍微工作一会儿。
bit later in the evening then you should
晚上晚些时候你应该
turn this off just like I don't know
把它关掉，就像我不知道一样。
what they're probably not watching you
他们可能没在看你
anyway if that's this type of human
总之，如果这就是那种人的话。
that's not you guys but for that type of
那不是说你们，而是指那种类型的
human this isn't going to work because
人类，这样做行不通，因为
nothing that I offer is get rich quick
我提供的任何服务都不是快速致富的捷径。
or go go buy this stock that's not going
或者去买这支不会涨的股票
to work um but it is things that I think
工作嘛，嗯，但我觉得是这样的。
we knew early on somehow we got maybe
我们很早就知道，或许我们能得到一些东西。
lucky with a few mentors but none of
很幸运能遇到几位导师，但没有一位。
this is rocket science which should be
这是火箭科学，应该是
really freeing for people to listen to
听起来让人感觉很轻松自在
and who
还有谁
you existential
你存在主义
question um you know I'm a former
问题，嗯，你知道我以前是……
Finance investor for 15 plus years
拥有超过15年经验的金融投资者
Investment Banking Asset Management who
投资银行资产管理
finally because covid happened took a
最终，由于新冠疫情的发生，导致了
little breather realized that I didn't
短暂的喘息让我意识到我没有
want to be like the managing directors
想成为像总经理那样的人
that I saw all around me and started
我环顾四周，开始
writing stuff online because I wasn't
因为我没有在网上写东西，所以我就没写。
doing Road shows selling Investments and
举办路演推销投资产品
investing people's money for for a year
用人们的钱投资一年
or whatever that was and because of that
或者不管那是什么，正因为如此。
started writing about the things that I
开始写我做的事情
do and I kind of thought nobody liked
我确实这么做了，但我以为没人喜欢。
the idea of owning laundromats and car
拥有自助洗衣店和汽车的想法
washes and all of that and it turns out
洗涤等等，结果证明
a lot of people thought that was
很多人都这么认为。
interesting and I do think we kind of
很有意思，而且我觉得我们有点……
hit this zeitgeist
正契合时代精神
of you know you saw it during Co people
如果你知道的话，你在Co People期间就看到了。
left big cities right there they bought
他们把大城市都留在了那里。
houses in Cape Town or somewhere out in
开普敦的房子或者其他地方的房子
rural areas right they got away from the
农村地区，他们逃离了……
corporate job in office in suits and
在办公室穿西装从事公司工作
realized God I don't want a 75 minute
我意识到上帝，我不想看75分钟的节目。
commute I uh maybe want a little bit of
通勤 我呃，也许想要一点点
fresh air um into chicken coops a lot of
新鲜空气进入鸡舍，很多
chicken coops these days and um and so
如今的鸡舍，嗯，等等。
because of that they got interested in
正因如此，他们对……产生了兴趣。
these small businesses these Community
这些小型企业，这些社区
businesses and so I think I got a little
所以我觉得我稍微有点儿……
bit Lucky in the fact that that was
有点幸运的是，那是
interesting to me I've done it for years
我对此很感兴趣，我已经做了好几年了。
I've invested in those things forever I
我一直都在投资这些东西。
started writing about on the internet
开始在互联网上写作
and then we got a lot of views and now
然后我们获得了大量的浏览量，现在
all of a sudden there are millions of
突然间，出现了数百万个
people that talk about buying these
谈论购买这些的人
small businesses or what we call boring
小型企业，或者我们称之为无聊的企业
businesses I want to get into that but I
我想涉足的行业，但是
um I want to start with something that I
嗯，我想先说说我……
saw the other day on your Instagram you
前几天在你的Instagram上看到了你
wrote a post about your 20s and your
写了一篇关于你20多岁以及你的文章
earlier life you said you think that
你早年曾说过你认为
your 20s suck and that no one tells you
你的二十几岁糟透了，但没人会告诉你这一点。
that when you hit 30 you become happier
当你到了30岁，你会变得更快乐。
and you offered sort of 32 pieces of
你提供了大约32件……
advice for people that are um in that
给那些身处其中的人一些建议
phase of Life focusing on in on your 20s
人生中专注于20多岁的阶段
with the benefit of hindsight now when
现在回过头来看，当……
you think about how you played your 20s
你会回想自己20多岁时的人生。
and how you'd suggest that maybe a child
以及您会如何建议也许一个孩子
you have someday or a friend that is 20
你总有一天会遇到这种情况，或者你有个20岁的朋友。
years old should play their 20s what is
20多岁的人应该打球，他们的20多岁是什么？
the best advice for a 20-year-old the
给20岁年轻人的最佳建议
best advice for a 20-year-old is to
给20岁年轻人的最佳建议是
realize that your 20s do suck that you
你要明白，你的二十几岁其实很糟糕。
are probably drinking too much you're
你可能喝得太多了
hanging out with people that aren't the
和那些不是……的人一起玩
best versions of themselves neither are
他们都不是自己最好的版本。
you you've got crazy hormones going on
你体内的荷尔蒙分泌失调了。
you're going to Bar and hanging out with
你要去酒吧和……一起玩
people having a few to or many drinks
人们喝了几杯或很多杯酒
and then going to a job you kind of hate
然后去做一份你有点讨厌的工作。
because you're brand new into the
因为你是这方面的新手
workforce and so of course you're doing
劳动力，所以你当然要这样做。
the worst thing humanly possible and
人类所能想到的最糟糕的事情
that's going to continue for like 5 to
这种情况还会持续大约5到
10 years like you are going to do a
就像你打算做的那样，10 年
$65,000 a year job for two or three
年薪 65,000 美元的工作，适合两到三人。
years that sucks and you're going to
那些年糟透了，你即将……
have no time for anything except what
除了……之外，我没有时间做任何其他事情。
your boss asks of you and I wish people
你的老板要求你这样做，我希望人们
had told me that because if you see the
他曾告诉我，因为如果你看到
light of the end of the tunnel you're
你是隧道尽头的光芒
like oh okay like I can do this for 2 or
哦，好吧，我可以做这个，2 或
three years I can learn I can grow and I
三年时间我可以学习，我可以成长，而且
can suck it up for 2 to three years
可以忍耐两到三年
and then after that I get a little bit
然后之后我就有点……
better and a little bit better and a
越来越好，稍微好一点，然后……
little bit better um and so the advice
好多了，嗯，所以建议
would be when you have a foot in your
当你一只脚踏入你的……
nail which is what it's like when you
指甲，就像你……
start your first job being 20 don't you
你20岁就开始第一份工作了，对吧？
know try to ignore the fact that it's
要知道，尽量忽略它是……的事实
painful it's there like it's there it's
痛苦就在那里，就像它就在那里一样。
real it sucks and I wish somebody had
真是太糟糕了，我希望有人能……
told me that because these days
告诉我，因为这些日子
everybody's like no you can be a
大家都说不，你可以成为
20-year-old and drive a Bugatti and you
20岁，开布加迪，你
know I don't know play around with
我知道我不知道，玩玩而已
crypto not real not real and then once I
加密货币不是真的，不是真的，然后一旦我
learned like okay this sucks and I can
明白了，好吧，这太糟糕了，我可以
deal with it then the next thing would
处理完这件事之后，下一步该做什么呢？
be everybody focuses on how much money
所有人都只关注多少钱。
you make when you're in your 20s huge
你在20多岁的时候赚了很多钱
mistake the only thing you should focus
犯错，你唯一应该关注的事情。
on is learning how can I think about my
我正在学习如何思考我的
salary like putting pieces of cash into
薪水就像把现金存入
my brain how can I learn as much as
我的大脑，我怎么才能学到那么多东西？
possible how can I come and work an
我怎样才能来这里工作呢？
apprentice for somebody that I think I
我当过某个人的学徒，我觉得我
might want their life one day and I'll
他们或许有一天会想要回自己的生命，而我会
take the minimum amount of cash that I
我只拿最少的现金。
need in order to fill my brain so that
需要填满我的大脑，这样
my next step can be to make more money
我的下一步可以是赚更多钱。
but in the beginning too many people
但一开始人太多了。
obsess on money and I wish I hadn't
我曾经那么执着于金钱，现在想想真后悔。
thought that way i' would rather learn
那样想的话，我宁愿学习
than earn when I'm young do you think
你觉得我年轻的时候挣的钱比现在挣的钱多吗？
there's a different amount of work and
工作量有所不同，
work ethic required in different seasons
不同季节所需的工作态度
of life so in your 20s should you be
所以，在你20多岁的时候，你应该……
working harder than when you're say 30
比你30岁的时候更努力工作
40 50 100% you can't have the same Stam
40%、50%、100% 的体力值不可能相同
stamina I mean I you know I was
耐力，我的意思是，你知道，我曾经是
weightlifting the other day and I was
前几天举重的时候，我……
showing my less strong friend next to me
给我看我旁边那位体弱的朋友
like this is how you do a deadlift and
这就是硬拉的正确做法。
here's I put another plate on there and
我又放了一个盘子在上面，
then you know blew out my hip you know
然后你知道，我的髋关节就受伤了。
and I'm like now I'm I'm in like back
我现在感觉就像回到了原点。
pain and you know I'm 37 I can't I do
疼痛，你知道我37岁了，我做不到。
not have the same stamina I had when I
我没有以前那样充沛的精力了。
was 25 physically you decline mentally
25岁时身体机能开始衰退
you decline and I think your work ethic
你拒绝了，我认为你的工作态度有问题。
declines too and so you know you it's
也会下降，所以你知道它是
really hard to keep going for 20 years
坚持20年真的很难
at 12-h hour long days you can do it but
每天工作12小时，你也能做到，但是
it's much easier when you're 20 and so
当你20岁的时候，事情就容易得多。
if you know that then know let's
如果你知道这一点，那就让我们开始吧。
frontload the pain so that in my 30s we
把痛苦集中在前期，这样到了我30多岁的时候，我们
can have a lot of fun you know my
你知道，我可以玩得很开心
husband who you you met is former na and
你遇到的丈夫是前任，而且
we always talk about how I think the
我们总是谈论我的想法
only reason we're kind of successful is
我们之所以能取得某种程度的成功，唯一的原因是
we just said what are the worst jobs we
我们刚才说了哪些工作是最糟糕的。
can take when we're young where we can
年轻的时候，我们可以抓住一切机会。
learn the most we can hopefully I think
希望我们能尽可能多地学习，我想。
have something that's a Resume Builder
找个简历生成器之类的东西
and then once we're in our mid 20s to
然后到了二十五六岁的时候
late 20s we can start reaping the fruits
到了二十七八岁，我们就可以开始收获成果了。
of our labor but you know being an nav
我们辛勤劳动，但你知道，做一名导航员
seal sucks you do it when you're young
海豹吸吮，你年轻的时候就应该这么做
you do all the worst things when you're
当你……的时候，你会做所有最糟糕的事情。
young but then for the rest of your life
年轻的时候，但之后你的一生都将如此
you're a [__] former Navy SEAL you're
你他妈可是个前海豹突击队员啊
set because he front loaded the pain
因为他把痛苦集中到了前面，所以才这样安排的。
when you look back over your career do
当你回顾你的职业生涯时
you um can you identify any sort of
嗯，你能识别出任何类型的……
light bulb moments where you were
灵光乍现的时刻，你当时
exposed to information that caused a bit
接触到一些信息，导致了一些问题。
of a paradigm shift as as it relates to
范式转变与此相关
how you think about wealth because I I
你如何看待财富？因为我
had I've had a couple of moments and you
如果我曾有过那么一会儿，而你
know to varying degrees but some real
了解程度不一，但有些确实
standout moments where I saw someone
让我印象深刻的时刻，我看到了某人
operate I was exposed to how they made
操作过程中，我接触到了他们是如何制造的。
their money and how they built their
他们的财富以及他们如何积累财富
wealth and I thought [__] nobody told me
财富，我当时想，操，没人告诉我这些。
this and I had the game wrong yeah has
没错，我之前对游戏的理解错了。
there been those moments in your life
你的人生中总会有那么一些时刻。
for sure
一定
um I think the well there's there's
嗯，我觉得那里有……
actually uh studies showing something
实际上，一些研究表明了某些事情
called economic interconnectedness which
称为经济相互联系，
basically shows that say you have a poor
基本上表明，假设你很穷
neighborhood to the left and a poor
左边是贫民区，还有一个穷人。
neighborhood to the right same uh
右边的街区也一样。
socioeconomic status so they both make
社会经济地位，所以他们俩都……
them around the same amount of money if
如果它们金额大致相同的话
this neighborhood just has a few rich
这个社区只有少数几个富人。
people in it even though on average the
里面的人虽然平均而言
neighborhoods are the same and people in
社区都一样，人们也一样。
the poor neighborhood interact with rich
贫困社区与富裕社区互动
people a little bit more on the left
稍微偏左一些的人
than they do on the right if you go 30
如果你走30步，就会发现右边的情况比右边好得多。
years down the line the kids that just
多年以后，那些孩子……
had a few more interactions with rich
与富人又有过几次互动。
people are going to be richer on average
人们的平均财富将会增加。
by 35% than the people in the same
比同一地区的人高出35%。
neighborhood to the right except with
除了右侧的街区外，
less economic interconnectedness and so
经济联系减少，因此
what that tells me is as often as
这告诉我，这种情况经常发生。
possible you want to be around people
或许你想和人待在一起。
who are richer than you sounds obvious
比你富有的人，这听起来显而易见。
kind of but I don't think it's that
有点像，但我觉得不是那样。
obvious you don't have to live next to
显然你不必住在隔壁
them you don't have to have their money
你不需要拿他们的钱。
you just want to be around them because
你只是想和他们待在一起，因为
it is contagious in some ways ideas are
在某些方面，思想是会传染的。
contagious and this ability to see into
具有传染性，而且这种洞察力
the future I think is contagious you
我认为未来是会传染的。
know if you think about it like you're
如果你这样想，你就会知道
driving in a car the faster the car is
开车时，车速越快
going the further the headlights have to
车头灯必须走得更远
be able to peer into the future
能够窥探未来
otherwise you're going to to blow off a
否则你就会错过机会。
cliff and so I think when people are
悬崖，所以我认为当人们
moving really fast they have a lot of
移动速度非常快，他们有很多
money and they have big risk to the
资金投入，但风险很大。
things they do their headlights are just
他们做的那些事，他们的车头灯只是
a little bit farther than the rest of us
比我们其他人走得更远一些
and so I got really lucky because I
所以我真的很幸运，因为我
chose Finance Finance is full of people
我选择了金融，金融行业人很多。
who are obsessed with money I think
我认为，那些痴迷于金钱的人。
there's a lot of you know ethical issu
你们知道，有很多伦理问题。
isues in that industry but all around me
那个行业的问题，以及我周围的一切问题。
were rich people so I remember one
他们是富有的人，所以我记得一个
instance uh really really well and that
例如，嗯，真的很好，而且
was um I was in I was in Chicago at the
嗯，我当时在芝加哥。
time I was working at Goldman Sachs and
我在高盛工作的那段时间
um the head of the Chicago office was a
嗯，芝加哥办事处的负责人是……
guy by the named Bruce and um Bruce was
一个名叫布鲁斯的人，嗯，布鲁斯是
a good guy he ran the fixed income
他是个好人，负责固定收益业务。
Division and after I left Goldman Sachs
部门，以及我离开高盛之后
I kind of stay in touch with a few
我跟一些人保持着联系。
people there including Bruce well one
那里的人，包括布鲁斯，都在那里。
day I find out Bruce becomes the
我发现布鲁斯成为的那天
ambassador to Canada I was like Canada I
作为驻加拿大大使，我当时就像加拿大一样。
don't even know if Bruce been to Canada
我甚至不知道布鲁斯是否去过加拿大。
like he's not a how did that happen and
就好像他不是那种会问“这是怎么发生的”的人一样。
so I started talking to a few other
于是我开始和其他几个人交谈。
people and I realized oh you buy
我和人们意识到，哦，你买
Ambassador ships in the US and so you
大使级舰艇在美国，所以你
could Google right now and see what the
现在就可以用谷歌搜索一下，看看结果如何。
average ambassadorship in the US costs
美国大使的平均费用
the answer it's about a million dollars
答案是大约一百万美元。
directly donated to a president plus a
直接捐赠给总统的款项加上
couple million dollars donated in a pack
一批捐赠了几百万美元
so Bruce bought the ambassadorship which
所以布鲁斯买下了大使职位。
I thought was fascinating and I was like
我觉得这太有趣了，我当时就想：
[__] I didn't realize that was for sale
妈的，我都没注意到那东西在卖。
like that's you just buy those things
就像你买那些东西一样。
that's so bizarre and that flipped my
这太奇怪了，彻底颠覆了我的认知。
perspective entirely to realize oh man
完全从这个角度来看待问题，哦，天哪
money really just is power and can you
金钱其实就是权力，你能做到吗？
imagine how wide open your ability must
想象一下你的能力必须有多强大。
be for abundance if you're like oh yeah
如果你觉得“哦耶”，那就去追求富足吧。
I'm going to buy a position of authority
我打算买下一个权力职位。
in the world never even would enter my
在这个世界上，我甚至从未想过我会进入我的视野。
equation when a lot of people think
很多人认为的等式
about money and they hear conversations
他们谈论的是钱，而且他们会偷听到相关的谈话。
about wealth I think some people kind of
关于财富，我认为有些人有点……
cringe because they think of money as
因为他们把金钱看作……，所以感到尴尬
being quite an ugly thing and and some
真是件丑陋的事，而且有些
people think it's quite an evil thing
人们认为这是一件非常邪恶的事情。
the the desire to accumulate more of it
想要积累更多这种东西的欲望
they see as being I don't know selfish
他们认为这是自私的，我不知道该怎么说。
or some maybe even manipulative or I
或者有些人甚至可能具有操控性，或者我
don't know you know so how how do you
不知道你懂，那你怎么知道？
square that for those
对于那些来说，这很方正。
people I I mean first of all I would
人们，我的意思是，首先我会
just say you're never going to attract
你就说你永远不会吸引人
it if you don't like it if you think
如果你不喜欢，那就别看了。
it's evil you're certainly not going to
这是邪恶的，你肯定不会……
make much of it and that sounds touchy
对此大做文章，听起来很敏感。
feeling I'm from Austin and I kind of
感觉自己像个奥斯汀人，而且我有点
like crystals so maybe that is a little
就像水晶一样，所以也许有点
touchy feely but it's the truth of the
虽然有点感性，但这却是事实。
matter it's just like women these days
没关系，就像现在的女人一样
who say all men are bad I can't find a
那些说所有男人都是坏人的人，我找不到……
man I don't like men anywhere do you
老兄，我哪儿都不喜欢男人，你呢？
think you're going to find one that way
你觉得那样能找到一个吗？
you know if you say things like that are
你知道，如果你说那样的话……
you going to be in Partnership of course
你当然会成为合伙人。
not you're going to repel them because
你不会把他们吓跑的，因为
you don't even like them it's the same
你甚至都不喜欢他们，结果还是一样。
thing with money it's very common sense
谈钱这件事，其实很简单，很有常识。
when you think about it and so I always
当你仔细想想，所以我总是
like to think about money as it's just
我喜欢把金钱看作是……
that it's that tool in your toolbox it's
它就是你工具箱里的那个工具。
like so do I want somebody else to have
我也希望别人拥有我这样的人。
the chainsaw or do I want it well i' I'd
电锯，或者我想要它吗？嗯，我会的。
rather have it because I think I'm a
我宁愿拥有它，因为我认为我是一个
good person and I think that I could
我是一个好人，而且我认为我可以
help more people with it and so people
帮助更多的人，这样人们
really need to lose the emotional
真的需要摆脱这种情绪
attachment to money especially if it's
对金钱的执着，尤其是当……
negative um I think there's a lot bigger
否定的，嗯，我认为还有更大的问题。
issue with too many people thinking is
太多人认为……的问题在于
bad than too many people thinking money
比太多人只想着钱更糟糕。
is good and that's weird if you think
这很好，如果你觉得这很奇怪的话。
about it because the opposite is usually
关于这一点，因为通常情况恰恰相反。
what we're told right and in that
我们被告知的是正确的，而且就这一点而言。
analogy of it being like a woman looking
打个比方，就像一个女人看着
for a man but saying that men are bad
对男人来说，但说男人不好
Etc does the woman in that analogy but
等等，那个比喻中的女性也是如此，但是
also in the analogy of money also need
同样，用金钱作比喻，也需要
to feel like she's deserving of a good
觉得自己值得拥有美好的未来
man I do you need to feel like you're
兄弟，我确实需要那种感觉。
deserving of money in order to attract
值得获得金钱以吸引
it I mean this may be Strays into things
我的意思是，这可能是流浪汉闯入的。
like manifestation and whatever else but
就像显化之类的，但
you know do you have to feel like you
你知道你必须感觉自己像你吗？
deserve to be rich do you think in order
你认为他们应该富有吗？
to attract more money into your life
如何吸引更多金钱进入你的生活
does it change how you make your
它会改变你制作……的方式吗？
decisions how you show up negotiate
你如何展现自己并进行谈判的决定
certainly I mean I think um I think the
当然，我的意思是，我认为，嗯，我认为
truth of the matter is that if you want
事实是，如果你想
to attract things the best way to get
吸引事物的最佳方法
them is to be great yourself so if you
他们的宗旨是让自己变得伟大，所以如果你
want a great partner be a great partner
想成为优秀的伴侣，就成为优秀的伴侣
you know if you want to be rich you need
你知道，如果你想变得富有，你需要
to start doing things where you're
从你所在的地方开始做事情
acting rich and I don't mean by spending
装作有钱人，我指的不是花钱。
but like what would a rich person do if
但是，一个有钱人会怎么做呢？
they wanted to achieve X Y and Z well
他们希望很好地实现 X、Y 和 Z 目标。
they probably work harder they surround
他们可能工作更努力，他们包围着
themselves with different types of
他们自己具有不同类型的
people and uh but then I realized
人们，呃，但后来我意识到
there's so many people that do not
有太多人不这么做。
believe in themselves and do have
他们相信自己，并且确实拥有
negative stories they have to break
他们必须打破负面新闻的魔咒
before they can take one tactic and do
在他们采取一种策略并……之前
anything yeah so I think you're right
什么都行，所以我觉得你说得对。
first you got to believe it it is it
首先你得相信它就是它。
does feel like it's really the Crux of
确实感觉这才是问题的关键所在。
all of this stuff because um the
所有这些事情都是因为……
evidence you have or don't have I guess
我想，不管你有没有证据。
forms what we call self-belief and some
形成我们所说的自信和一些
people who you know with all the will in
那些你认识的、意志坚定的人
the world they just can't believe in
他们无法相信的世界
themselves because they deeper systemic
他们自己，因为他们有更深层次的系统性问题。
sort of self-esteem issues and I guess
有点自尊方面的问题，我想
this ties into the conversation around
这与围绕这个话题的讨论有关。
like feeling like an imposter um and the
感觉自己像个冒名顶替者，嗯，还有
reason I I referenced this is because I
我之所以提到这一点，是因为我
I remember many years ago as you were
我记得很多年前，你
talking a friend of mine saying that
我跟一个朋友聊天时，他说……
when he finally got some money he just
当他终于攒够钱的时候，他
had a huge sense of guilt because his
他感到非常内疚，因为他
father had worked really really really
父亲真的真的真的非常努力工作
really hard and been paid a fraction of
非常努力，却只得到了很少的报酬
what he had the money he had made so he
他拥有的钱，就是他挣的钱，所以他
always had the sense of sort of guilt
一直有一种愧疚感。
with his money like he didn't deserve it
他挥霍无度，好像自己不配拥有这些钱似的。
um like he was an imposter potentially
嗯，他可能是一个冒名顶替者。
and a lot of people struggle with that
很多人都为此苦恼。
you know yeah they think it's for other
你知道，他们觉得那是给别人用的。
people yeah I mean I do think like where
是的，我的意思是，我确实觉得就像……
your body goes your belief follows and
你的身体会改变，你的信念也会随之改变。
so I was at this event for women and uh
我当时参加了一个女性活动，呃……
it was like pretty high up people in
就像是高层人士在……
finance and only females in the crowd
金融行业，而且人群中只有女性。
and it was the first time that I
那是我第一次
realized that a lot of people have a
意识到很多人都有
negative relationship with women because
与女性的负面关系，因为
the the facilitator asked everybody to
主持人要求大家……
close their eyes with money with money
他们用钱闭上眼睛
okay so the facilitator said I want you
好的，主持人说我想要你
to picture
到图片
money put your eyes closed picture money
闭上眼睛，想象金钱。
and then have a visual representation
然后进行可视化呈现。
with your body of how you feel when you
感受你的身体，感受你当时的感觉
hear the word money right so in my mind
听到“钱”这个词，我的脑海里就浮现出这个念头。
I hear the word money I go money like
我一听到“钱”这个词，我就想钱就像……
yeah give me more of that like it big V
对，再给我来点儿，就像大V一样。
right and yet when I looked into that
没错，但是当我深入研究之后……
she said freeze open your eyes and so
她说，别动，睁开眼睛，就这样。
then we open our eyes and we looked
然后我们睁开眼睛，望向远方。
around could you imagine what most of
你能想象周围大部分是什么吗？
these high-powered women looked like it
这些强势女性看起来就像……
was like fetal position or like like
就像胎儿的姿势，或者像……
money we're like money we're like money
金钱，我们就像金钱，我们就像金钱
just very small
非常小
and that's when I realized oh of course
那时我才意识到，哦，当然
they're not going to get a ton of it
他们不会得到很多。
because that's their feeling with money
因为这就是他们对金钱的感受。
and so what she recommended that I have
所以她建议我这样做。
since done with a lot of the women that
自从和很多女性做过之后，就……
I've engaged with is say when when you
我参与讨论的内容是，当你……的时候
think about money all I want you to do
我只想让你满脑子想钱。
just make a big expressive movement with
只需做一个大幅度的、富有表现力的动作
your body like am i g to get that salary
你的身体就像我渴望获得那份薪水一样
yes I am you know do I want more of it
是的，你知道吗？我想要更多吗？
give it to me and I do think your body
把它给我，我确实认为你的身体
ends up really determining how your
最终真正决定了你的
brain functions and Tony's talked about
大脑功能，托尼谈到了这一点
this and a lot of other people that have
这一点以及其他许多人都有过类似的经历。
so maybe if you don't think you deserve
所以，也许如果你觉得自己不配拥有这一切
money I don't know how to fix your brain
钱，我不知道怎么修好你的大脑
right away but I do do know how to fix
虽然马上就想解决，但我确实知道该怎么做。
your body which is just make a big
你的身体，这只会造成很大的
movement that tells your body that money
这种运动会告诉你的身体，金钱
is good for you don't make a protective
对你有好处，不要采取保护措施
small movement that makes you in fear
微小的动作都让你感到恐惧
make a big movement that gives you into
采取重大行动，让你进入
abundance and so I that stuck with me
富足感，所以这个概念一直萦绕在我心头。
for a long time I find it interesting as
我一直觉得这很有趣，因为
well thinking about who talks about
仔细想想谁在谈论
money because men talk about money a lot
因为男人经常谈论金钱。
and I don't know I don't know if women
我不知道，我不知道女人是否……
talk about money in private but I know
私下里可以谈论钱，但我知道
my my male friends are all talking about
我的男性朋友们都在谈论……
their money they're investing their
他们投资的钱
investment Etc and I wondered if there's
投资等等，我想知道是否有……
any sort of gender difference you've
你所经历的任何性别差异
observed because you speak to so many
因为你跟很多人交谈过，所以才会被注意到。
people about gender differences as
人们谈论性别差异时
relates to money well perfect example is
和金钱有关，一个完美的例子是
our audience across socialist is about
我们在社会主义领域的受众大约
60 to 65% men and I'm a woman and yet
60%到65%是男性，而我是一名女性，然而
it's actually quite hard to get women
其实找女人挺难的。
interested and engaged on these issues
对这些问题感兴趣并积极参与。
interesting and so um you know I think a
有趣，所以，嗯，你知道，我认为
lot of women first of all they think
很多女性首先认为
it's a little a little cringe um you
有点尴尬，嗯……你
know there's not normally Iz ation of it
我知道通常情况下没有 Iz ation 来解决这个问题
so you know there's never a group where
所以你知道，从来没有哪个群体是
women are getting together on the 19th
女性们将于19日聚会
hole at a golf course and talking about
高尔夫球场上的一个洞，然后谈论
the deals that they did that week that's
他们那周达成的交易就是……
very normal for men right where would
对男人来说非常正常，对吧？
women all get together to talk about
女人们聚在一起谈论……
their business aspects like I don't
他们的商业方面，我并不了解。
think there exists a a container for
认为存在一个容器
that and so um I'm big on this belief
所以，我非常相信这一点。
that everybody should learn how to get
每个人都应该学习如何获得
money especially if you're a woman you
金钱，尤其是如果你是女性的话。
don't have to go be a girl boss and if
不必非得成为女强人，而且如果
you want to stay home and take care of
你想待在家里照顾……
the the kids and be a Trad wife that's
照顾孩子，做一个传统的妻子。
amazing but understand where your money
很棒，但要明白你的钱都花在哪儿了。
is located understand how it's made in
位于了解其制造方式
your family understand how much things
你的家人明白事情的严重性。
cost what you spend um and it is there's
花费多少，嗯，就是这样。
nothing more fun than making your first
没有什么比制作你的第一部电影更有趣的了。
dollar on your own it's very liberating
靠自己的钱生活，感觉非常自由。
do you think money's seen as a masculine
你认为金钱被视为一种男性特质吗？
thing investing wealth creation do you
投资财富创造对你来说意味着什么？
think those are all seen as
认为这些都被视为
masculine I mean Investment Banking is
男性化的，我的意思是投资银行是
87.6% uh male oh really yeah um the
87.6% 呃 男性 哦真的吗 是的 嗯
finance industry in general is 65% plus
金融行业总体占比超过65%。
male so that would tell me yes feels
男性，所以这会告诉我“是的，有感觉”。
like a real inequality in society that
就像社会中存在真正的不平等一样
the people that are working in finance
在金融行业工作的人
are heavily male but also finance and
男性居多，但金融业也存在类似情况。
money is power right well I mean time in
金钱就是力量，对吧？我的意思是，时间就是力量。
career right I mean they just have had
职业生涯方面，我的意思是他们一直都有
longer to have access to that industry
需要更长时间才能进入该行业
and so I don't think there's some big
所以我觉得没什么大问题。
conspiracy theory happening I think what
我觉得这是阴谋论。
happened is women haven't had the right
事情的起因是女性一直没有权利
to to work for as long long um Finance
尽可能长时间地工作，嗯，财务
is the highest paid industry of all
是所有行业中收入最高的。
industries that you could go into it's
你可以进入的行业是……
also one of the most competitive it also
它也是最具竞争力的之一。
has one of the highest barriers to entry
准入门槛极高。
a number of Licensing graduate degrees
多项执照管理研究生学位
Etc it's also one of the most
等等，它也是最……之一
competitive to get into those positions
竞争激烈，才能获得这些职位。
and so of course it's going to be
所以，当然会是这样。
dominated by those who have you know an
被那些你认识的人所主导
unfair Advantage from more time
不公平的优势来自更多的时间
attempting to do this I think if you
我认为，尝试这样做的话……
history shows us anything recently
历史告诉我们，最近发生的事情
there's going to be more women in it
里面会有更多的女性角色。
going forward so if I took you back then
展望未来，如果我带你回到过去……
if I took you back to your first dollar
如果我带你回到你的第一块钱
and I took away everything that you have
我夺走了你的一切。
but also I take away all of your
但我也夺走了你所有的
contacts yeah you can keep your brain
联系方式，是的，你可以保持你的大脑
but you can't keep your contacts and I
但你不能保留你的联系人，而且我
set you the challenge in
给你设定挑战
2024 of building your wealth from
2024年财富积累之路
scratch what's what are the first things
先别管什么是什么，首先是什么
that come to mind to get you going so
我能想到的这些就能让你开始行动了。
you're in a studio apartment you are
你住在一间单身公寓里。
broke you have all the information you
你已经掌握了所有信息
have you have no contacts what do you do
如果你没有任何人脉，你会怎么办？
am I allowed to be 20 again or do I have
我可以重返20岁吗？还是我必须……
to be you can be 20 okay if I'm if I'm
做你自己，20岁也可以，如果我是，如果我是
young why did you ask that well I think
年轻人，你为什么问这个问题？嗯，我想
um it's easier when you're young If
嗯，年轻的时候更容易些。
we're honest when you're young people
年轻的时候我们都很诚实
who have money they see themselves in
有钱人把自己看作是
you at an earlier date if you got that
如果你之前收到过，就会早点收到。
hunger I mean one of our rules in hiring
饥饿，我的意思是，这是我们招聘规则之一。
is hire people so hungry you're scared
雇佣那些如此饥饿以至于让你感到害怕的人
they might bite
它们可能会咬人
you and uh and so when you're young you
你，还有，还有，所以当你年轻的时候，你
know you you've had this happen you meet
我知道你也经历过这种情况，你遇到了
a young man who's just got that fire
一个充满激情的年轻人
right he doesn't know anything but you
没错，他除了你什么都不知道。
can just see in him that he will do
我能看出他会这么做。
whatever it takes he's here before you
无论付出什么代价，他都会先你一步到达这里。
he's here after you he's coming up with
他来这里是为了你，他正在想办法
ideas he's doing jobs to the point where
他的想法是，他正在做各种工作，以至于……
you're like chill bro like that's not
你就像在说“冷静点兄弟”，好像那不是真的。
even your job right couple of them in
甚至你的工作也包括其中几个。
here right and what do you do with those
对，那你拿这些怎么办？
guys you're like I'm GNA help you why
伙计们，你们就像我是GNA，帮帮你们，为什么？
because actually you see yourself in
因为实际上你会看到自己
them it's like a weird selfish father
对他们来说，就像一个古怪自私的父亲。
mother thing we have we're like I see
母亲的事情我们就像我看到的那样
you I remember being you I'm going to
我记得你，我就是你要去
help you and so if you're young what I
帮帮你，所以如果你还年轻，我
think you do is you get with the biggest
你以为你做的就是和最大的人在一起吗？
baddest guy you can find or gal you can
你能找到的最坏的男人或女人
find and who's already successful who
找到并找出那些已经成功的人
you think has the life that you want and
你认为自己拥有了想要的生活，
you do everything possible to provide
你尽一切可能提供
value to them and that's probably a
对他们来说很有价值，这可能是
bunch of Sweat Equity stuff that's
一堆靠汗水换来的回报之类的东西
probably a bunch of [__] in the
很可能全是胡说八道
beginning but it's so rare like intense
刚开始，但非常罕见，就像强度很大一样。
competence is so rare and when you're
能力如此稀缺，当你……
young I think you throw it away with
年轻的时候，我觉得你会把它扔掉。
these ideas of like quiet quitting and
这些想法，比如悄悄辞职和
not engaging like that is your moment to
不那样做，正是你的机会。
show that fire and then what happens is
先展示火势，然后会发生什么呢？
you're only going to need to do that for
你只需要这样做一次
like a year or two with a few players
比如和几个球员一起待一两年。
and you're going to move quickly because
你要迅速行动，因为
if you are with people who have a ton of
如果你和一群拥有大量……的人在一起
resources what is your biggest
资源方面，你最大的优势是什么？
constraint in your business right now is
您目前在业务方面遇到的制约因素是
it money do you not have enough money
你没钱吗？
could you raise more if you needed it of
如果需要的话，你能筹集更多资金吗？
course do you need more attention no you
当然，你需要更多关注吗？不，是你。
get hundreds of millions of views do you
获得数亿次观看量，你呢？
need more ideas probably not you got a
还需要更多想法吗？可能没有，你已经有了。
lot of them what do you need people you
他们很多人，你需要什么人？
need people you need hungry little ankle
需要人，你需要饥饿的小脚踝
biters that are willing to do whatever
那些愿意做任何事的咬人者
it takes and so people don't like this
这需要时间，所以人们不喜欢这样。
answer but it's not like I would do real
回答，但我不会真的这么做。
estate I would do po podcasting it's go
我会做播客，没问题。
find a person who is so rich but willing
找到一个既富有又愿意
to give you a
给你一个
shot for as long as you can okay so
尽可能长时间地拍摄，好吗？
let's zoom in on that then because
那我们就放大看看吧，因为
someone's going to hear that now they're
现在有人要听到这件事了。
gonna go cool got it Cody and they're
冷静点，明白了，科迪，他们
going to go on LinkedIn they're just
他们会去领英上找我。
going to start peppering Bill Gates and
准备开始向比尔·盖茨投掷胡椒喷雾
Elon Musk Etc you know what I mean so
埃隆·马斯克等等，你知道我的意思。
let's make this a little bit they're
让我们稍微……
like this didn't work Cody El want
就像这样行不通一样，科迪·埃尔想要
didn't text me back yeah so so when I'm
没回我短信，是啊，所以当我……
thinking about reaching out to these
考虑联系这些人
individuals that are powerful and I
那些有权势的人，而我
guess we could frame it in the context
我想我们可以把它放在这个语境中来理解。
of you you're a very powerful woman
你是一位非常强大的女性。
you've got lots of opportunities and
你有很多机会，
probably less time
可能时间更短
um than opportunities so how would I get
嗯，比机会多得多，那我该如何获得呢？
to Cody yeah how could I manipulate you
对科迪来说，我怎么可能操纵你呢？
or motivate you into giving me a shot
或者激励你给我一次机会
yeah let's talk about two things one if
好，我们来谈谈两件事：一是……
you want to get in front of a rich
你想接触一位富人
powerful person start with concentric
强大的人从同心圆开始
circles so start with what's closest to
画圆，所以从最接近的开始
you so for instance who's the richest
例如，谁最富有？
guy on your block who's the richest guy
你街区里最有钱的那个人
in your community who's the richest guy
你们社区里谁最有钱？
that you can get to or G you can get to
你可以到达或G你可以到达
start there there's no one there there's
从那里开始，那里没有人，那里有
no way first of all you're like seven
不可能，首先你才七岁。
degrees of Kevin Bacon right so what I
凯文·贝肯的学位，对吧，所以呢？
would say is it's just a number GI game
可以说，这只是一场数字游戏。
there's somebody maybe they're only
或许有人只是
making a couple hundred k a year but
年收入几十万，但
that's like way more than you could ever
那远远超过你所能想象的。
imagine start there MH so that would be
想象一下从那里开始，MH，那会是
my first point and I think about that
我的第一点，我一直在思考这个问题。
like you know for instance you go to
比如你知道，你去
school so everybody goes to school in
所以每个人都去上学。
some way shape or form who do you know
以某种方式，你认识谁？
who also goes to your school who is the
还有谁跟你上同一所学校？
richest kid at your school can you get
你学校里最有钱的孩子，你能得到什么？
to their dad or their mom right so try
对他们的爸爸或妈妈来说，就是这样，所以试试看
to get to who's closest you that you can
尽可能接近你身边最亲近的人
physically touch and you can actually
可以进行实际的身体接触。
engage with that human I would start
与那个人互动，我会开始
there because it's lower Stakes so one
因为风险较低，所以……
if the richest guy on your block or in
如果你街区里最有钱的人，或者在
your college uh that's a friend of your
你的大学……呃，那是你的一个朋友
you know that's a dad of one of your
你知道那是你其中一个孩子的爸爸吗？
friends owns a big sprinkler company
朋友拥有一家大型洒水公司
that makes a couple million dollars a
那能赚几百万美元
year start working with that and while
今年开始着手处理这件事，同时
you're there give yourself a deadline
既然你已经到了那个阶段，那就给自己设定一个截止日期吧。
six months or a year learning at this
六个月或一年的学习
level and then level up who's now the
等级，然后升级，现在谁是
richest person times 2x you can get to I
最富有的人乘以 2，你就能达到 I
think the biggest problem is people
我认为最大的问题是人
confuse Fame with with being rich they
他们把名气和富有混为一谈。
go after you and I we're not the richest
来追你吧，我们又不是最富有的。
people I mean we do pretty good but like
我的意思是，我们做得还不错，但是……
we're not the richest and by the way who
我们不是最富有的，顺便问一下，谁
has more
拥有更多
competition everybody's in your and my
竞争无处不在，你我皆是如此。
email inboxes just because we have a lot
邮箱数量太多，是因为我们有很多邮件。
of of followers I would never go to an
在我的粉丝群里，我永远不会去
influencer and try to play this game I
我是一名网红，想试试玩这个游戏。
would go to the guy who runs a sprinkler
会去找那个负责洒水器的人
company that nobody is talking to at all
一家根本没人理睬的公司
but he makes a ton of money and then you
但他赚了很多钱，然后你
you cozy up to this guy and you go this
你和这个人亲近起来，然后你就这么做了
is incredible what are you do you did
太不可思议了，你做了什么？
this with sprinklers how much does your
用洒水器的话，你的费用是多少？
company make wo I want to be like you
公司制造 wo 我想成为像你一样的人
one day can I intern for you or
有一天我能来你这里实习吗？
Apprentice for you I'll do whatever you
我愿做你的学徒，你说什么我都愿意做。
want do you know what that is going to
你知道那会是什么吗？
feel like to a guy like that as opposed
对那样的人来说，感觉就像……
to me or you or we're going to be like I
对我或你来说，或者我们会像这样：
don't have time I have too many interns
我没时间，我手头实习生太多了。
so go where the water is the shallowest
所以要去水最浅的地方。
is what I would start with it's so true
这正是我要说的，说得太对了。
because I I'm sure both of us get just
因为我确信我们俩都会明白的
hundreds and thousands of um messages a
成百上千条嗯嗯嗯消息
year of people lit and literally will
一年中，人们点亮并真正地……
stop me outside my office and say
在我的办公室外面拦住我，然后说
remember this kid the other day about a
还记得前几天那个孩子吗？
week ago stopped me outside of our new
一周前，我停在我们新家门外。
office and said um he was stood outside
办公室，然后他说，嗯，他当时站在外面。
there and he had his like CV and a
在那里，他带着他的简历和……
little binder and he was like I will
他拿着小活页夹，就像在说“我会”。
come in and I will just clean the floor
进来吧，我这就把地板打扫干净。
and I'm that's not a great pitch because
我觉得这并不是一个好的推销方案，因为
I obviously I can't do that I can't have
我显然做不到，我不能拥有
someone come into my company unpaid
有人未经许可擅自进入我的公司。
which is going to cause a whole PR
这将引发一场全面的公关危机。
disaster when that leaks out into the
当这种情况泄露出去时，就会酿成灾难。
Press Etc but I wouldn't anyway um and
Press Etc，但我反正也不会这么做。
you I don't know what it was about that
我不知道那件事到底是怎么回事。
but that doesn't necessarily make me
但这并不一定意味着我
think that you are tremendously valuable
我觉得你非常有价值。
if you're coming in and offering to the
如果你进来并向……提供……
tea and clean the
茶和清洁
floor so I'm so compelled by what it is
地板，所以我被它所吸引。
in that initial message that sometimes
在那条初始信息中，有时
in your case will just get you to pause
对你来说，这只会让你暂停。
a second and maybe reply to the person
再给对方一点时间，或许可以回复一下。
in a sea of DMS and messages is there
在浩如烟海的私信和消息中，它就在那里。
something in particular that spikes you
有些东西会让你情绪飙升。
the only thing that spikes is some sort
唯一出现峰值的是某种东西
of expertise you and I are only
在专业知识方面，你我都只是
interested really in one thing we are
我们真正感兴趣的只有一件事。
interested in somebody who has a
对拥有……的人感兴趣
understanding of the world that we don't
我们对世界的理解，我们并不理解。
that can take us one step further right
这可以让我们向右迈进一步。
you don't need another floor cleaner you
你不需要另一台地板清洁剂了。
don't need another driver but if a young
不需要另一个司机，但如果是一个年轻人
kid reached out to you and they said hey
有个孩子联系你，说了声“嗨”。
I've analyzed 542 YouTube videos of
我分析了 542 个 YouTube 视频
yours here are the thumbnails that
这里是缩略图。
actually work the best uh here's a bunch
实际上效果最好的是……嗯，这里有一堆
that you have lately that I don't
你最近拥有而我没有的东西
actually think work here's the data
实际上，我认为这些数据有效。
driven behind this I actually put
受此驱动，我实际上投入了
together a few mockups of it for you and
我为你准备了一些模型图。
um and I reached out to these three
嗯，我联系了这三位。
people that I think would be great to
我认为这些人会很棒
have on your podcast here's why and
在你的播客节目中提到这一点，原因如下：
they've already agreed to it if this is
如果这是真的，他们已经同意了。
interesting I just wanted to forward
有意思，我只是想转发一下。
along this packet to you you might be
您可能随这包包裹一起收到
like hm that's interesting okay what
嗯，这很有意思，好吧，什么？
about that last line you used there I
关于你刚才用的那句话，
just wanted to forward this onto you why
只是想把这个转发给你，为什么？
is oh yeah you never want to expect
哦，是的，你永远不想期待
something for a gift given I call it the
我称之为礼物的东西
10x rule so I try to never ask for
十倍法则，所以我尽量不开口要
something unless I have given 10s 10x to
除非我给了10个10次，否则不会有其他东西。
a person and we have that across our
一个人，我们在整个过程中都有这种现象
business too I think you should do that
我觉得你也应该在生意上这么做。
with with young people so when I was
与年轻人在一起的时候，当我
younger I have a lot of people that I
年轻的时候，我有很多朋友。
thought of as
被认为是
mentors they would never know that they
他们永远不会知道，他们是他们的导师。
were a mentor of mine and all I would do
他们是我的导师，而我所做的一切都是为了他们。
is I would ask them one question so I
我只会问他们一个问题，所以我
wouldn't go to famous people but I might
我不会去见名人，但我可能会去。
go to a normal you know kind of
去一个普通的地方，你知道的，那种。
high-powered exec in finance or
金融界的高管或
something and say like hey I was
做点什么，然后说类似“嘿，我……”之类的话。
wondering I saw you did this deal over
我很好奇，我看到你完成了这笔交易。
here um I was wondering why you chose to
嗯，我想知道你为什么选择……
invest in that company versus this
投资那家公司而不是这家
company you know if you had time for a
你知道，如果你有时间的话，可以去这家公司看看。
one- sentence reply that'd be amazing
一句话回复就太好了
and they might reply me one sentence
他们或许只会回复我一句话。
maybe one out of 10 people would and
或许十个人中会有一个人会这样做。
then I would say thank you no need to
那我就会说谢谢，不用了。
respond further this is really helpful
请继续回复，这真的很有帮助。
I'm going to go implement this in some
我打算去实现这个功能。
way and then I would reach out to them
然后我会通过某种方式联系他们。
in a couple weeks and I'd be like hey
几周后，我就会说：嘿
that piece of information you gave me I
你给我的那条信息
just did X Y and Z with it really
真的就用它做了 X、Y 和 Z 而已。
helpful thank you no need to reply just
很有帮助，谢谢。不用回复了。
letting you know that you made an impact
让你知道你产生了影响。
and that no need to reply and me
无需回复，我
following up is so rare I wish people
后续跟进如此罕见，我希望人们
realize that today that if you want
今天就意识到，如果你想
something follow through is worth its
坚持到底是有价值的。
weight in gold I mean one of the other
以黄金重量计算，我指的是其他重量。
things that we do is when people reach
我们所做的事情是当人们达到
out to us and say stuff like we'd like
出来跟我们说些我们想听的话
to do XYZ for you I say read this book
为了帮你做XYZ，我建议你读这本书。
and I'll give them a random book and I
我会随机给他们一本书，然后我
say Come Back to Me with a few XYZ
说“带着几个XYZ回到我身边”。
questions or things how many people do
问题或事情有多少人做
you think actually come back I I think
你觉得真的会回来吗？我觉得
I've had five maybe and so follow
我大概有五次了，所以继续
through is so rare and what would happen
这种情况非常罕见，会发生什么呢？
with these people and I still do it to
和这些人在一起，我仍然会这样做
this day I had one guy who was um what
那天我遇到一个家伙，他……嗯……
was his role H he was quite high up at a
他的角色是H，他在公司职位相当高。
company called State Street and I can't
公司叫道富银行，但我不能
remember what his role was but he said
记住他的角色，但他说道
to me one day I was in New York I had
有一天，我在纽约，我……
played that game with him for probably
可能跟他一起玩过那个游戏
years like hey tiny little thing one
就像嘿，小东西一号
sentence of advice great thank you
一句很好的建议，非常感谢。
here's how I implemented it again and
以下是我再次实现它的方法：
again and again maybe 20 times over the
一遍又一遍，可能重复了20次。
course of two years and finally I was in
经过两年的学习，我终于……
New York and he was in New York and I
纽约，他当时也在纽约，而我
pinged him and said I'd love to take you
我给他发了条消息，说我很乐意带你去。
to dinner I want to talk to you about a
晚餐我想和你谈谈……
few things and it was so funny because
事情不多，但却非常搞笑，因为
as we sat down he goes this is the
我们坐下后，他说，这就是
weirdest thing and I thought oh no what
最奇怪的事，我当时想，哦不，怎么回事？
and he said uh I don't really know you
他说，呃，我其实不太认识你。
but I feel invested in your success I
但我真心希望你成功。
was like I know you do because I'm
就好像我知道你会这么做，因为我
dripping on you for two years showing
两年来，你身上一直滴着东西
you that a tiny little action which felt
你觉得一个微小的举动就能让你感到……
like nothing to you actually made a
就像什么都没发生一样，你实际上做了一件
material impact on my life m and most
对我的生活产生了实质性的影响，而且大多数
people don't get to feel that way so I'm
人们没有机会有这种感觉，所以我
a I'm a young person I'm I'm Cody
我是一个年轻人，我是科迪。
Sanchez without anything you've managed
桑切斯什么都没做到，你已经做到了。
to get yourself nice and cozy with
让自己感到舒适惬意
someone rich and Powerful you're now in
你现在身处一个富有而有权势的人之中
there in a circle you're learning from
你正身处一个你正在学习的圈子中
them where did you go from there yeah um
然后你去了哪里？嗯……
well the first thing that I would do is
首先，我要做的就是……
you if you look back at my resume I
如果你回顾一下我的简历，你会发现
think I stayed at most jobs for like a
我觉得我大多数工作都只待了大概一个星期。
year and a half two years Max until I
一年半到两年，最多到我
was at one called First Trust where I
我当时在一家叫First Trust的公司工作，在那里我
was there for five years because I had
我在那里待了五年，因为我有
ownership uh in the business and uh I
拥有公司股份，而且我
felt like I had skin in the game I had
感觉自己像是在这场游戏中投入了真金白银。
control of my outcome but before that
掌控结果，但在此之前
and I really only stayed in jobs about a
我基本上只在一份工作上待了大约一个季度。
year and a half the second that they
一年半后，他们
told me I couldn't progress anymore or I
他们告诉我我不能再进步了，或者我
couldn't have an option to make more
没有更多选择的余地。
money I left and so in my opinion the
我留下的钱，所以在我看来
Young Generation does have it right that
年轻一代的说法确实有道理。
you should not stay at a job for 20
你不应该在一份工作上待20年。
years unless that job continues to allow
除非那份工作继续允许，否则这种情况可能会持续数年。
you to earn more and to learn more so
这样你就能赚更多钱，学到更多东西。
the second I wasn't earning more and the
第二个原因是，我没能赚到更多钱，而且
second I didn't feel like I could learn
其次，我觉得自己学不会。
more exponentially I left so that's what
我离开得更远，就是这样。
I think they should do and you basically
我认为他们应该这样做，你基本上
are you're kind of monkey barring
你是不是有点像猴子一样横着走？
both how much you earn and what you can
你的收入和你的能力都取决于你。
learn to your next position and I think
学习胜任下一个职位，我认为
that people too many people start doing
太多人开始这样做
entrepreneurship too
创业精神也
early uh in my opinion because you can
在我看来，早点这么做是因为你可以
learn on somebody else's dime as opposed
用别人的钱去学习，而不是
to going out and doing the brutal awful
出去做那些残酷可怕的事情
thing that could put you 10 years behind
这可能会让你落后十年
because you lose all your money and you
因为你赔光了所有的钱，而且你
don't actually have enough knowledge to
实际上没有足够的知识来
do the job right go and work for a bunch
把工作做好，然后去为一群人工作。
of entrepreneurs for five or seven years
创业者五到七年
and then once you've been sure that you
然后一旦你确定你
really want to be in the game and be an
真的很想参与其中，成为一名……
entrepreneur then go do it but that's
那就去当企业家吧，但那只是个开始。
what I would do I would Leap Frog to
我会做的，我会跳跃到
positions of higher power and then
更高的权力职位，然后
eventually I might become an
最终我可能会成为一个
entrepreneur and in finance they have a
企业家和金融人士
really cool thing that I think more
我觉得这真是太酷了
companies should do and that if you
公司应该这样做，如果你
leave your company you should try and we
你应该尝试离开你的公司，我们
should play it with you so when I left
我应该和你一起玩，所以当我离开的时候
First Trust the first person who wanted
首先信任第一个愿意向他/她提出要求的人
to give me a check was my CEO so I was
给我开支票的是我的CEO，所以我当时
like I'm going to go do something else
就像我要去做别的事一样
I'm going to build something else and he
我打算再建点别的东西，而他
he wanted me out of the firm he was like
他想让我离开公司，他就像……
I don't want you running the business
我不想让你经营这家公司。
how you're running it now you need do it
你现在的运行方式需要改进。
my way not your way but we left ambly
我的路不是你的路，但我们离开了安布利
and he said I want to be your first
他说，我想成为你的第一个
investment like when you go looking for
就像你寻找投资一样
investors I want to be it and I think
我想成为投资者，而且我认为
that is what employees should strive for
这正是员工应该努力追求的目标。
try to get your boss to give you your
试着让你的老板给你你的
first capital and if you're a great
第一笔资金，如果你很棒
employee they're going to be happy
员工们会很高兴的。
too in order to Leap Frog you're gonna
为了实现跳跃式发展，你还需要……
have to do a lot of interviews so I just
我需要参加很多面试，所以我就……
wanted to pause there and and ask you
我想在那里停下来问问你。
know when you're interviewing people
要懂得何时面试别人
what are the red flags um and if I was
有哪些危险信号？嗯，如果我是
interviewing to join Cody Sanchez's
面试加入科迪·桑切斯的团队
business this
这家公司
Empire what's the best things that I
帝国时代，我最好的东西是什么？
could say and do and what's the best
能说什么、能做什么，以及什么才是最好的
behavior that I could exhibit in that
我可以表现出的行为
moment yeah um people will give you
嗯，有人会给你
things when they think you know them
当他们以为你了解某些事情的时候
more than they know you and so what do I
他们比你更了解你，那我该怎么办？
mean by that I mean nobody I mean our
我的意思是，我的意思是没有人，我的意思是我们的
favorite word is our our name right for
最喜欢的词是我们的，我们的名字是对的
every single one of us and we all like
我们每个人都喜欢
to talk about ourselves more than we
我们谈论自己的时间比谈论我们自己的时间要多得多
like to ask questions it's just kind of
喜欢问问题，这感觉就像……
true for most humans so if we know that
对大多数人来说都是如此，所以如果我们知道这一点的话
to be true what do you want to do in an
说实话，你到底想做什么？
interview you want to go in and say
你想在面试中进去说
Here's all the things I think I know
以下是我认为自己知道的所有事情
about your company I'm not sure because
关于贵公司，我不太了解，因为
I'm I'm not you I'm on the outside but
我不是你，我身处局外，但
this is what I think I know about it
这就是我所了解的。
really impressed by this I think this is
我真的被这个深深打动了，我觉得这是
great over here I'm curious about this
这边也很好，我对这个很感兴趣。
can you tell me why you guys made this
你们能告诉我你们为什么制作这个吗？
decision the interview should be showing
面试应该展现的决定
the
这
interviewer that you know almost
你几乎认识的面试官
everything that there is to know about
关于……的一切
their company and it should be done with
他们的公司，而且应该这样做。
a lot of humility like I think that even
我觉得他非常谦逊，即使
if you're certain that I think is
如果你确定我认为是
important and the second that happens
重要，其次就是这种情况。
are ego gets to us and I go H this this
我们的自负蒙蔽了我们的双眼，然后我就……这……
guy's pretty smart you're right that was
这家伙挺聪明的，你说得对。
a good move that we did over there and
我们在那边采取的那个举措很明智。
so that's what I think a lot of people
所以我觉得很多人都这么想。
don't do too many people do shotgun
不要太多人用霰弹枪
rounds which is really wide going after
回合数真的很多
a ton of different jobs as opposed to
有很多不同的工作，而不是
sniper shots go after the three
狙击手向三人开枪。
positions you want aggressively knowing
你想积极了解的职位
everything about that company and that
关于那家公司的一切，以及
boss you're much more likely to get it
老板，你更有可能得到它
than just to imply on indeed is there
不仅仅是暗示确实存在
anything else that is an immediate
其他任何立即发生的事情
turnoff you in an interview like an
在面试中让你反感的事情就像……
immediate red flag if someone says
如果有人说
something or does something oh yeah
做某事或做某事，哦耶
there's so many immediate not going to
有很多事情不能立即去做
hire you if you talk badly about your
如果你诋毁你的公司，就雇用你。
last boss because the way you treated
最终boss是因为你对待他的方式
your last person is probably going to be
你最后一个人很可能是
the way you treat me immediately not
你对待我的方式立刻就不是
going to hire you second immediate not
马上就要雇用你了，不是吗？
going to hire you is if you talk about
如果你谈论……，我就会雇用你。
all the reasons why something didn't
所有导致某事未能发生的原因
work and it's not your fault so if
工作，这不是你的错，所以如果
you're victim mentality at all well this
你完全是受害者心态。
didn't work because of this this didn't
因为这个原因，它没能奏效。
work because of this third in the
因为这第三个原因而开展的工作
interview is if
面试是……
you at all start talking about um
你完全开始谈论嗯
this one's a little inappropriate but if
这个有点不合适，但是
you come into my companies and you say
你来到我的公司，然后说
uh talk to me about work life balance
呃，跟我聊聊工作与生活平衡吧。
I'm not the place for you our companies
这里不适合你，我们公司
are hardcore there's not a lot of work
他们是硬核玩家，工作量不大。
life balance we work hard so I'm not
生活平衡，我们努力工作，所以我并不
going to hire you if you talk about how
如果你谈谈如何做，我就会雇用你。
much time off are you you know texting
你有很多空闲时间吗？你知道，你会发短信吗？
on the weekends the answer is yes the
周末的答案是肯定的。
second uh point to that is I always make
第二点是，我总是……
the job seem worse than it is and so and
这份工作看起来比实际情况更糟糕，等等。
a lot of people who hire try to sell the
很多招聘人员都试图推销……
person this is why it's so great you
这就是你如此棒的原因
should come here my interview usually go
我应该来这里，我的面试通常会去
goes like this hey I want to ask you a
事情是这样的：嘿，我想问你一个问题
bunch of questions about your background
一系列关于你背景的问题
then I going to tell you all the things
然后我会把所有的事情都告诉你们。
that are really tough about this job so
他们对这份工作真的非常严格
you get the honest truth about it one
你会得到关于这件事的真相。
way or the other and then I'll wrap up
不管怎样，然后我就结束今天的分享。
with you with you asking any questions
和你一起，你有什么问题吗？
you want does that sound good they go
你想要什么？听起来不错吗？他们走了
yep I kind of pepper them with questions
是的，我会问他们很多问题。
about them they go here's all the things
关于它们，它们都在这里。
that suck about this job here's all the
这份工作最糟糕的地方就在这里：
things that are hard here's all the
这里所有难点都在这里
reasons why it hasn't worked to date any
至今为止它为何没有奏效的原因
questions on that and the reason why is
关于这一点以及原因的问题是什么？
because I don't want anybody coming into
因为我不想任何人进来
my company and going God I thought it
我的公司和上帝，我想到这一点
was going to be better than this I want
本来会比现在好得多的，我想要
them coming in and going oh okay this
他们进来又走，哦，好吧，这个
actually is a
实际上是一个
miserable and at some point from you
痛苦不堪，而且在某种程度上，你
know you leap frog from one place to
知道你从一个地方跳跃到另一个地方
another and eventually you have enough I
另一个，最终你会得到足够的。
guess intelligence to to start thinking
猜测智力开始思考
about becoming an owner at some point
关于在某个时候成为所有者的问题
how do I make that transition from being
我该如何从……过渡到……
a team member or an employee to becoming
从团队成员或员工到成为
an owner if I only have a couple of
如果我只有几个，那我就是个老板了
thousand dollars let's say I mean can I
假设我有一千美元，我的意思是，我可以吗？
at that point or do I need to become
那时我需要成为
rich to become an owner that's a good
成为富有的老板，这很好。
question first I think becoming an
首先，我想问的是，成为一个
inside of a business is totally possible
在企业内部这样做是完全可能的。
and so you should ask your boss this
所以你应该问问你的老板这个问题。
question which is in this business if I
问题是，如果我从事这个行业，我会面临什么？
am one of your top performers
我是你们公司业绩最好的员工之一
consistently and make myself materially
持续不断地让自己在物质上有所成就
important to the business can I get some
对企业来说很重要，我能得到一些吗？
ownership in either this business or
这家企业的所有权或
anything else that we do and I am
我们做的其他任何事情，而我……
willing to earn it or invest in it to do
愿意挣钱或投资去做
that and so for instance at my companies
例如，在我所在的公司也是如此。
if you're one of the top performers you
如果你是顶尖员工之一，你
can invest alongside me in some of our
可以和我一起投资我们的一些项目。
other companies that's a finance model
其他公司也采用这种金融模式
that I stole so in private Equity the
我在私募股权领域窃取了这么多东西
reason why people in private Equity are
私募股权从业人员的动机
so rich is because all the the managers
之所以如此富有，是因为所有的经理人
of the company have an opportunity to
公司有机会
invest in the best deals so they can put
投资最划算的交易，这样他们就可以……
some money in and there's allowances for
投入了一些资金，还有一些零用钱
people who aren't accredited investors
非合格投资者
but are employees to actually invest
但员工真的会投资吗？
even though they're not accredited in
即使他们没有获得认证
the US which is a really unfair
美国这样做真的很不公平。
advantage and so I would ask your your
优势，所以我想问问你的……
employer that question then the second
雇主问了这个问题，然后是第二个问题。
thing that I would do is I would would
我会做的就是……
try to see if you can earn still so you
试试看你是否还能赚钱，这样你
can W to earn you can make as much money
通过W赚钱，你可以赚到很多钱。
as humanly possible from your salary and
尽你所能，从你的薪水中……
then take the money from your salary and
然后从你的工资里扣除这笔钱
invest in other side deals and I would
投资其他副业，我也会
do that before I ever jumped into my own
在我跳进自己的领域之前，就先这么做了。
business overall the problem I think
我认为，整体而言，商业问题在于……
that came straight to mind when I think
想到这一点，我脑海中立刻浮现的就是这个。
about that is how when you start
大概就是这样，当你开始的时候
investing in side deals you're you're
投资副业，你是……
going to make a lot of mistakes and
会犯很多错误，而且
you're going to lose a lot of money
你会损失很多钱。
because seed investing is tough anyway
因为种子投资本来就很难。
but especially if you have poor deal
但尤其是在你运气不好的情况下。
flow are you're not getting a lot of
流量是不是太少了？
deals it's just your mate Kevin who has
交易，只有你的朋友凯文有
this idea for an app Kevin and he asked
凯文提出了这个应用程序的想法，他问了这个问题。
for 25k yeah so you know I say this
25k，是的，所以你知道我这么说
because I had a a fairly famous actor
因为我有一个相当有名的演员
come up to me the other day who's very
前几天有个很……的人走过来跟我说话。
young in his career made a lot of money
年轻时就赚了很多钱
and he said Steve I don't know what to
他说：“史蒂夫，我不知道该怎么办……”
do with my money Etc I don't know where
我不知道该怎么处置我的钱等等。
to invest it and he goes my mate has
他想投资，然后他就说我的朋友有
this app idea and I oh God you know but
这个应用创意，哦，天哪，你知道的，但是
he that's that's the only deal he has on
那是他唯一的交易。
his plate so he's giving his friend 25
他把盘子里的饭菜给了朋友，所以他给了朋友25块。
or 50k for an app idea so um is that
或者给一个应用创意5万美元，所以，嗯，是这样吗？
smart to do or yeah that's a great
这样做很明智，或者说，这真是个好主意。
question no I think until you're rich
不，我认为只有当你富有之后才会被问到这个问题。
and let's define rich as until you're a
让我们把富有定义为直到你成为……
millionaire I would do zero startup
百万富翁我会选择零启动
investing I mean zero because it's a 90%
投资，我的意思是零，因为它是90%
failure rate you only invest in startups
你只投资初创公司，失败率很高。
when you want to get pretty rich because
当你想要变得非常富有的时候，因为
you can burn some capital in order to
你可以烧掉一些资金来……
have a few home runs so instead I might
我本来可以打出几个本垒打，所以也许我会改打其他项目。
go to something like we're an investor
去看看类似“我们是投资者”之类的东西
in this company so full disclosure but
在这家公司，所以要完全披露信息，但是
there's a company called percent where
有一家名为“百分比”的公司，
they allow you to invest in bond deals
它们允许你投资债券交易
that cash flow for small businesses you
小型企业的现金流
could also do Equity deals in businesses
也可以进行企业的股权交易。
that cash cash flow um so I would stay
现金流嘛，所以我会留下来。
away from anything that isn't already
远离任何尚未存在的东西
profitable that doesn't already make
盈利能力强但尚未盈利
money and I think once you have your
钱，而且我认为一旦你有了你的
first million you can play that game but
第一个百万你就可以玩那个游戏了，但是
until then you only want to do deals
在此之前，你只想做交易。
where you're cash flowing and so that's
你的现金流在哪里，就是这样。
where I would start you could start with
你可以从这里开始。
something like percent you could also
比如百分比之类的，你也可以
start by talking to you know your
首先和你知道的人谈谈。
employer like I was talking about and
就像我刚才说的那种雇主
say hey in this business that we have
在这个行业里，我们打个招呼吧。
now how could I earn some equity and the
那么我该如何获得一些股权呢？
answer might be you can't like I don't
答案可能是你不能，就像我不能一样。
give equity and contrarian thinking my
给予公平和逆向思维
media company because I want to own my
因为我想拥有自己的媒体公司
name forever I don't ever think I'm
永远的名字，我从不认为我是
going to sell this thing but if we have
打算把这东西卖掉，但如果我们有
cash flowing and laundromats and car
现金流、洗衣店和汽车
washes yeah you guys can invest in that
洗车用品，你们可以投资那个。
if you're seen as a marquee member of
如果你被视为一位杰出的成员
the team so maybe find companies where
所以团队或许可以找到一些公司
that's allowed too just on that point
就这一点而言，也是允许的。
just curious this is kind of a bit of a
只是好奇而已，这有点像……
tangent but if I'm a team member of
跑题了，但如果我是团队成员……
yours and because you said if you're a
你的，因为你说过如果你是
marquee member of the team so so what if
团队的明星成员，那又怎样？
I come to you and I say Cody can I get a
我来找你，我说科迪，我能要一个
piece of that laundry mat yeah you turn
那家洗衣店的一部分，是的，你转身
to me and go no you're not a marquee
对我而言，然后说不，你不是招牌。
member of this team mhm oh yeah for sure
团队成员？嗯，当然。
what what you'd say to me yeah I I would
你会对我说什么？嗯，我会
yeah I would say at this point people
是的，我想说，在这一点上，人们
who are allowed to have equity in the
获准拥有股权的人
company are people that I think we are
公司是由我认为我们是的人组成的。
going to travel through time together
我们将一起穿越时空。
that means years or DEC you didn't think
那意味着你没想过的几年或十二月。
I'm going to travel in time with you I'm
我要和你一起穿越时空。
not sure yet I don't know you well
还不确定，我对你也不太了解。
enough yet you've been here for a year
够了，但你已经在这里待了一年了。
you know you run our social media
你知道你负责我们的社交媒体。
accounts you've hit goals but you
您已达成目标的账户，但是您
haven't absolutely blown them out of the
还没有完全击败他们
park yet you know do you think that if
公园，但你知道你认为如果
you left the company right now we would
你现在离开了公司，我们会
be unable to function without you and
没有你，我根本无法运转。
the answer is usually like no probably
答案通常是“可能否”。
not okay so at this point Point you're
不太好，所以目前你的情况是
not a partner in the business yet you're
你还不是公司的合伙人
still at employee status but if you keep
仍然保持员工身份，但如果你继续
taking on more responsibility and you
承担更多责任，你
keep beating goals overall and you show
不断超越目标，你就能展现出
me that the business is better and would
让我觉得这家公司更好了，而且会
lose steam without you then absolutely
没有你，他们就会失去动力，绝对的
you can invest but I learned this from
你可以投资，但我从中学到这一点
Jim Bowen at First Trust he did this
吉姆·鲍文在第一信托公司做了这件事
beautifully you had to pay into the
你必须为此付费。
partnership to become a partner you and
建立合作伙伴关系，成为合作伙伴，你和
that kind of sucked because you also
那感觉真糟糕，因为你也
have to pay taxes on partnership and um
必须为合伙企业缴纳税款，而且
so not only do you not get money right
所以你不仅没能正确获得资金。
away but you have to spend money every
远行，但你每时每刻都得花钱。
year because your partnership value goes
因为你的合伙价值会逐年下降
up and you have to pay taxes on it but
上涨之后，你还得为此缴税，但是
Jim made this big this big feeling at
吉姆让这种强烈的感觉……
the company about the chance when he
公司谈到他有机会的时候
offers somebody partnership it was like
向某人提供合作关系就像
a
一个
celebration and that is I think what we
庆祝，我认为这就是我们所要做的。
want to do in our companies same thing
我们也想在公司里​​做同样的事情。
Warren Buffett does you know he allows
沃伦·巴菲特，你知道他允许吗？
his employees to have equity in his
他的员工应享有公司股权。
companies but only those that he thinks
公司，但仅限于他认为的那些。
he's going to travel through time with
他将和……一起穿越时空
and Warren Buffett has had the same 7
沃伦·巴菲特也拥有同样的7个
employees I think for like 20 years it's
我认为员工们已经这样工作了大约20年了。
you can go look at their Christmas cards
你可以去看看他们的圣诞贺卡。
and nobody changes year after year after
多年来，没有人改变。
year can I get rich if I just have a
如果我只有……，我能在一年内致富吗？
salary do you think yeah you can you
你觉得薪水怎么样？是的，你可以。
can't get on the Forbes 100 list if you
如果你
just have a salary but if you want to
只要有份工资就行，但如果你想……
make a couple million dollars 100% I
赚几百万美元，100% 我
mean Bruce Brucey Bruce back at Goldman
布鲁斯·布鲁西·布鲁斯回到高盛
Sachs bought an ambassadorship and he
萨克斯花钱买了一个大使职位，而他
was only ever a salaried employee got
仅仅是一名领固定薪水的员工
bonus too of course climbed the
当然，还有额外的奖励，那就是攀登
corporate ladder and is probably worth
企业阶梯，而且可能很有价值
100 million plus now so why do I need to
现在已经超过1亿了，那我为什么还需要……
buy a boring business you don't you
买一家无聊的公司，你不会的。
don't need to the problem is what if
不需要，问题是如果
Bruce gets fired what if your job
布鲁斯被解雇了，如果你的工作也这样怎么办？
doesn't exist what if you're an attorney
如果不存在，那如果你是一名律师呢？
now and you make great wages or hours
现在你就能获得丰厚的工资或工作时间。
but AI does take your jobs what's your
但人工智能确实会抢走你的工作，你的怎么办？
backup plan so my backup plan might just
备用计划，所以我的备用计划可能只是
be I don't know I own some airbnbs and I
我不知道，我有一些Airbnb房源，而且
rent them out or something could do that
可以把它们租出去，或者用其他方式实现这一点。
too Airbnb is pretty volatile market
Airbnb市场波动性也相当大。
we've seen that now and I think I like I
我们现在已经看到了，而且我觉得我喜欢我
don't like Risk and so I think if you
我不喜欢风险，所以我觉得如果你
want to get rich how do you get rich you
想致富吗？怎样才能致富？
try to not lose money over time and you
尽量避免长期亏损，你
try to have enough bets where you can
尽量在你能下注的地方下注。
have an outsized return at some point so
在某个时候获得超额回报
you could just own airbnbs you could
你可以自己拥有Airbnb房源。
just do real estate I don't really care
就做房地产吧，我不太在意。
how people do it I don't think everybody
我不认为每个人都会这样做。
should own a laundromat or a car wash
应该拥有一家自助洗衣店或洗车店
but I do think you should have a backup
但我认为你应该准备一个备用方案。
plan so one day when you want to retire
做好计划，以便将来你想退休时可以安心退休。
too you got some extra income coming in
你还有一些额外的收入。
so if I've got tens of thousands of
所以如果我有成千上万个
dollars or pounds yeah um do you think
美元还是英镑？嗯，你觉得呢？
what what do you think what would you do
你觉得你会怎么做？
with it I was playing this game
我当时正在玩这个游戏
yesterday there's three business I
昨天有三家企业
really like right now I really like uh
我现在真的很喜欢……
Senior Care Centers Senior Care Centers
老年护理中心 老年护理中心
okay which is interesting because you'd
好的，这很有意思，因为你会
go Cody I said tens of thousands not
去吧，科迪，我说的是成千上万，不是。
hundreds of thousands but senior care
数十万，但老年护理
centers are interesting because there's
中心之所以有趣，是因为……
all these government grants and
所有这些政府拨款和
allowances for the fact that we do not
考虑到我们没有
have enough of them in the US and you
美国已经有很多这种人了，而且你
can turn a house with the right
只要方法得当，就能把房子变成……
licensing and Zoning into a senior care
获得老年护理机构的许可和分区
center and so I won't get too technical
居中，所以我就不深入技术细节了。
on it but demographics show we have a
但人口统计数据显示我们有一个
huge aging population we need more areas
人口老龄化严重，我们需要更多地区
to take care of them and you can start
照顾好它们，你就可以开始了
small
小的
by having an independent living house
通过拥有独立生活住宅
that has a rotating nurse you make 3 to
那里有轮班护士，你挣3到
5x the rent on that as you do a regular
租金是普通租金的5倍
midterm or long-term rental so I like
我喜欢中期或长期租赁。
the demographics of that one plus it's
那个群体的人口统计数据加上它是
not super Capital intensive because you
并非超级资本密集型，因为你
could rent the house out from somebody
可以从某人那里租房子
else and then just layer this Assisted
否则，只需叠加这个辅助层即可。
Living Center on top of it um we had we
生活中心就在上面，嗯，我们曾经有
had to put my grandparents in in one of
不得不把我祖父母安置在其中一个
these uh at one point because they
这些呃，在某个时候是因为它们
needed 247 care did you buy no but I
需要24小时护理，你买了吗？没有，但是我
should have should have um I think my my
应该应该应该嗯，我想我的我的
f their families are already like crazy
他们的家人已经疯了
I could only imagine if I said the thing
我简直不敢想象如果我说了那句话会是什么感觉。
is I'd like to cash flow on this be like
我希望这能带来现金流，就像这样
Cody get out of here I also really like
科迪，快离开这里！我也很喜欢他。
um I like businesses today that are
嗯，我喜欢现在那些……的企业。
service-based uh but don't require a ton
服务型工作，但不需要太多东西。
of upfront Capital so for instance
例如，前期资本。
window cleaning businesses I just bought
我刚买的窗户清洁公司
one of these it's called pinks with this
其中之一叫做粉色，就是这个
company called resi Brands but I love it
公司名叫Resi Brands，但我很喜欢它。
because I did it we have a YouTube video
因为我做了这件事，所以我们有了YouTube视频。
that's going to come out and I was like
那件事肯定会曝光，我当时就想：
am I full of [__] let's try this see if
我是不是在胡说八道？我们来试试看。
I could actually do it so you need to
我其实可以做到，所以你需要……
make
制作
$384 a day in order to have a business
每天需要384美元才能经营一家企业
that does $100,000 a year if you only
如果你只做一件事，那它每年能赚10万美元。
work five days a week so I was like can
一周五天工作，所以我就想，可以吗？
we make
我们制造
$384 pre-selling window cleaning
预售窗户清洁服务，价格 384 美元
services to somebody uh in order to
为某人提供服务，以便
start this business and we tried it and
我们创办了这家公司，并且尝试了一下。
we did it and so um so I might start
我们做到了，所以，嗯，我可能要开始了
like a window cleaning business a
就像一家窗户清洁公司
pressure washing business uh a painting
高压清洗业务，呃，一幅画
business uh you could also buy one of
商业方面，你也可以买一个
those
那些
those are Trade Services businesses and
这些是贸易服务企业，
then the third type of business that I
然后是我从事的第三种类型的业务。
always talk about are what I call
我总是谈论的就是我所说的
gateway drug businesses or semi um
入门毒品业务或半官方
semi-autonomous businesses like
半自治企业
laundromats or car washes the problem
洗衣店或洗车店的问题
with those are they're slightly more
这些就稍微多一些。
expensive I just want to take a PO here
太贵了，我只想在这里拿个邮局。
and just sort of get perspective on what
只是想从另一个角度来看待这个问题。
you're talking about for someone that
你是在谈论某人
has no understanding of business so my
他对商业一窍不通，所以我的
name is Nigel and I am 37 I've never ran
我叫奈杰尔，今年37岁，我从未跑过步。
a business before I don't know anything
在创业之前，我什么都不懂。
about businesses or investing or
关于企业或投资或
anything like that what are what is it
类似的东西是什么？它是什么？
you're telling me to
你是让我……
do and so and Nigel wants to make more
照做，就这样，奈杰尔想做更多。
money Nigel wants to make more money he
尼格尔想赚更多钱
wants to be an owner he wants to be a
他想成为老板，他想成为……
millionaire in in 10 years time and
10年内成为百万富翁
Nigel's willing to work hard he's
奈杰尔愿意努力工作，他
willing to work the hardest he just
他愿意付出最大的努力
doesn't really know what to do because
他真的不知道该怎么办，因为
there's so many options and so many
有很多选择，也有很多
conflicting things he gets he's hearing
他听到了一些相互矛盾的事情。
all these words resi Brands he's hearing
他听到的所有这些关于 resi Brands 的词语
like window cleaning power he's like
他就像擦窗户的力气一样大
what what's she doing with a power
她用权力做什么？
washer so if I was Nigel here's the
洗衣机，所以如果我是奈杰尔，这就是……
question I would be asking myself I
我会问自己的问题是：
would be saying one do I want to keep my
这就好比说，我是否想保留我的
job that I have currently or do I want
我目前的工作，或者我想要的工作
to not keep my job that's really
丢掉工作真是太可惜了。
important because it's like am I going
这很重要，因为这就像在问：我是否要去
to go work on something 24/7 or not I'm
不管是不是24小时不间断地工作，我都是
not making enough money to completely
赚的钱不够多，无法完全
walk away from my job yet okay perfect
离开我的工作，好吧，完美
so that me little bit of savings yeah
所以，我攒下了一点钱，是的。
you want a little side hustle that you
你想做点副业吗？
think could be your full-time hustle
想想这或许能成为你的全职事业
right so in that case what I would start
对，那么在这种情况下，我会从哪里开始呢？
doing is asking myself we have something
我所做的就是问自己，我们拥有什么。
called your unfair Advantage Vin diagram
你称之为不公平的优势图表
and what your unfair Advantage vent
以及你那不公平的优势发泄
diagram is is your skill set so what is
图表展示的是你的技能组合，那么是什么呢？
an Angel Good at and that that's as
一位天使擅长此道，而且就是这样
simple as like maybe Nigel's in
就像奈杰尔可能在的那样简单
marketing so he's actually pretty good
所以他在市场营销方面其实相当不错。
at Mar marketing maybe Nigel drives a a
在三月份的市场营销中，Nigel 或许会开车。
you know an Uber or a car service so
你知道，像优步或者其他汽车服务之类的。
he's really good at working super long
他真的很擅长长时间工作。
hours he's just got the Workhorse in him
他简直就是个工作狂。
then uh I add my network who does Nigel
然后，呃，我把我的关系网里的人加进来，他们叫奈杰尔。
know that could help him so that might
知道这可能会对他有帮助，所以也许
be like Nigel's brother is actually a
就像奈杰尔的兄弟实际上是一个
plumber he works inside of a plumbing
他是一名水管工，在管道系统内工作。
business so if Nigel figured out how to
所以，如果奈杰尔想办法……
buy a business he could partner with his
买一家他可以和他合作的企业
plumber brother-in-law or whatever and
水管工姐夫之类的
they could do it together and then
他们可以一起做，然后
finally it's like what gets you excited
最后，这就像是什么让你兴奋一样。
and by what gets you excited I don't
至于什么能让你兴奋，我并不清楚。
mean an industry I mean Nigel loves
我的意思是，奈杰尔很喜欢的那个行业。
sales Nigel loves it he wants to sell
销售员奈杰尔很喜欢这份工作，他想卖掉它。
people stuff okay and the reason I talk
人际交往方面的事情还好，这也是我说话的原因。
about this vend diagram like this is
关于这个销售图表，就像这样
it's a little bit more complex than
它比这稍微复杂一些。
saying you should go buy a franchise you
你说你应该去买个加盟店
should go buy a window cleaning business
应该去买一家擦窗公司
or start those is because I think the
或者开始做这些是因为我认为
biggest reason why people struggle with
人们难以应对的最大原因
what to do next is they don't actually
接下来他们该怎么做呢？实际上他们并没有。
know themselves and so if I was Nigel I
他们了解自己，所以如果我是奈杰尔，我会
would say to you find what your vend
我会告诉你，找到你销售的产品。
diagram is of the things that you think
图表是你思考的事物。
you're good at your network is good at
你擅长你的人脉关系，你擅长
that you could actually go either start
实际上，你可以选择从任何一方开始。
or buy a business on because the fastest
或者收购一家企业，因为最快的方式是……
path to wealth is having some type of
通往财富的途径是拥有某种类型的……
ownership so I would start there before
所有权，所以我会先从那里入手。
I knew what I know now about business if
如果我早知道我现在对商业的了解，
ID heard you say when I was 18 years old
我18岁的时候听你说过
just go buy a business I'd go Cody
你就去买个生意吧，我会去的，科迪。
listen I've got $700 left for my call
听着，我还有700美元可以用来打电话。
center job a month yeah like how can I
中心工作一个月，是啊，我该怎么做？
buy a business that's making millions or
收购一家年收入数百万美元的企业
hundreds of thousands I'm going to have
我将拥有数十万
to wait till I'm rich Yeah well yeah you
等我发财了 是啊，是啊，你
can't buy it with your 700 extra bucks
你多出来的700块钱也买不到。
but you could buy it with your sweat and
但你可以用汗水买到它。
your time so there's three ways to buy a
花费您的时间，所以有三种方式可以购买
business you can either use cash you can
做生意，你可以用现金。
use expertise or you can use time or
利用专业知识，或者你可以利用时间。
what I call Sweat Equity so think about
我称之为“汗水换来的股权”，所以请思考一下。
it right now I buy a bunch of businesses
我现在正在收购一批企业。
I have a ton of cash you know what I
你知道吗，我有很多现金。
don't have a lot of operators I don't
我没有很多操作员
have a lot of people who can go actually
实际上有很多可以去的人
run the business that I want them to run
让他们按照我的意愿经营业务。
but if had a young guy who was super
但如果有个超级棒的年轻人呢？
hungry and I could give him $100,000 to
他饿了，我可以给他10万美元。
go operate the business that I was going
回去继续经营我原本要去的生意。
to go run I would probably do that and
如果要去跑步，我大概会这么做。
people do that every day in our
人们每天都在这样做
community and so for this young gun
社区，以及这位年轻枪手
you're not going to go buy the business
你不会去收购这家公司。
outright yourself with your own Capital
完全用你自己的资本投资自己
you're going to say I'm working 12 hours
你会说我工作了12个小时
in a call center right now I am
我现在在呼叫中心。
Relentless if you pair me with somebody
如果你把我跟某人配对，我会毫不留情。
that knows how to run a plumbing company
懂得如何经营一家管道公司
and I just have to learn and do a bunch
我只需要学习和完成很多事情。
of the [__] to start the company and
创办公司时那些胡扯和
grow the company or continue the company
发展公司还是继续经营公司
would you partner with me and they're
你愿意和我合作吗？他们是
not going to be able to partner with a
无法与一家公司合作
Steven or a Cody probably at FR at first
史蒂文或者科迪一开始可能在FR
but they might be able to partner with
但他们或许能够与……合作
you know somebody uh somebody's dad that
你认识某人，呃，某人的爸爸？
they know and so like for instance we
他们知道，比如我们
had a young guy in our group I'll change
我们组里有个年轻人，我会换人。
his names to Adam since I don't know if
他的名字叫亚当，因为我不知道他是否
if I'm allowed to talk about it or not
我可以谈论这件事吗？
but let's say so Adam was 19 years old
假设亚当当时19岁
Adam worked inside of a marketing
亚当在一家市场营销公司工作。
company and he had never run a business
他之前从未经营过这家公司。
before didn't have a lot of cash Adam
以前亚当没多少钱。
went to the senior partner of his
去找了他的高级合伙人。
marketing company that he worked for and
他曾就职的营销公司
said like we have this vendor over here
就像我们这里有个供应商一样。
that we do some stuff with they do all
我们用他们做一些事情，他们也做所有事情。
of our graphic design work uh they're
我们的平面设计作品，嗯，它们是
really good the guy's kind of done with
真的很好，那家伙差不多已经结束了。
running this business like I don't think
经营这家公司，我觉得我根本不会这么想。
he wants to keep doing it I was talking
他想继续做下去，我刚才在说。
to him about the other day what if we
前几天我跟他说起如果我们
bought this business and I ran it like
买下这家公司后，我像……一样经营它。
all integrate it for us all bring it
我们都把它整合起来，把它带来
into this company and I think we can buy
投资这家公司，我认为我们可以收购
it with just a percentage of future
它仅占未来收益的一小部分。
profits we bring in which is called
我们带来的利润，也就是所谓的
seller financing and the marketing head
卖方融资和市场营销主管
was like if you think you can get that
就好像你认为你能得到那个一样
deal done yeah yeah sure and the guy was
交易完成了，是的，当然，那家伙是
like okay Adam says well if I do that
亚当说，好吧，如果我那样做的话
can I have part of the company for
我可以拥有公司的一部分股份吗？
bringing it over and he said well yeah
他拿着东西过来，然后说，嗯，是的。
yeah I mean I you I don't have to put in
是的，我的意思是，我不需要投入。
capital to the deal I have to put in a
我需要为这笔交易投入资金。
very small amount of capital you're
你拥有的资金非常少
going to run it and we basically have
准备运行它，我们基本上已经……
like a risk-free trade because we just
就像无风险交易一样，因为我们只是
have to pay them a percentage of future
必须支付他们未来收益的一定比例。
revenue or future profit sure and so now
收入或未来利润肯定没问题，所以现在
Adam owns a business that he's about to
亚当拥有一家公司，他即将……
sell because he basically partnered with
出售是因为他基本上是与……合作
his his owner and so I mean you could
他是他的主人，所以我的意思是你可以
even think about that with your business
甚至可以考虑一下你的业务。
today if you're if you're a young person
今天，如果你是一个年轻人
working with step and you're like Hey
使用 Step 工具时，你会想：嘿
Stephen we're in this studio right now I
斯蒂芬，我们现在就在这个录音棚里。
saw like a sign out front that says that
看到前面有个牌子，上面写着：
they're actually they want to sell this
他们其实是想卖掉这个
studio space I bet we could rent out
我敢打赌我们可以租到工作室空间
this whole thing and uh we could
整件事，呃，我们可以
probably cash flow and make this a
可能是现金流，并使之成为
profit Center instead of a loss center
利润中心而非亏损中心
for us if I could like a negotiate a
对我来说，如果我能像谈判一样……
deal that was basically a seller
这笔交易基本上是卖方交易。
financed real estate deal for us would
对我们来说，融资房地产交易将是
we would you want to do something like
你想做类似的事情吗？
that I could help us run the the you
我可以帮助我们运营你
know rental of it now you might say no
现在知道了租金信息，你可能会说不
to that first deal but you're probably
完成第一笔交易，但你可能
going to look different at that employee
对那位员工的看法会有所不同
100% And also I just want to explain
百分之百。另外，我还想解释一下。
what seller financing is for someone
卖方融资对某些人来说意味着什么？
that doesn't know seller financing is
不知道卖方融资的人
how 60% of all businesses get sold when
60% 的企业是如何被出售的
they're small businesses so it's very
他们是小企业，所以非常
normal seller financing just means this
正常的卖方融资就是指这个。
that the seller uses a a percentage of
卖家使用一定比例的
future profits to let somebody else buy
让其他人购买未来的利润
the business and um instead of you
这家公司，还有，嗯，而不是你。
having a loan or a mortgage for a house
拥有房屋贷款或抵押贷款
they're basically saying hey my business
他们基本上是在说：嘿，这是我的生意。
right now makes $100,000 a year profit I
目前每年盈利10万美元。
want to sell it to you for
想把它卖给你
$300,000 um you go sounds good I don't
30万美元？嗯，你觉得不错，我不这么认为。
have
有
$300,000 and they go okay well why don't
30万美元，他们就说好吧，为什么不呢？
I sell it to you for $300,000 over five
我以 30 万美元的价格，分五年卖给你。
years and you pay me each year from that
年复一年，你每年都从中付我钱。
$100,000 profit that we have could we do
我们有10万美元的利润，我们能做到吗？
a deal that way you might be like yeah
这样一来，你可能会觉得“是啊”。
we could do that they've just got to
我们可以做到，他们只需要……
believe that you're going to be able to
相信你能够
grow the business yeah or not royally
拓展业务，是还是不是？
[__] it up yeah 100% which is you know
搞砸了，百分之百，你知道的。
selling anything is a trust trade right
出售任何东西都是一种信任交易。
so these days we have to do less trust
所以如今我们必须减少信任。
when we sell something because we have
当我们出售某件东西是因为我们有
immediate trust in like a credit card or
像信用卡那样立即获得信任
money this is almost going back to
这笔钱几乎又要回到……
bartering days where it's like I'm going
以物易物的日子，感觉就像我要去……
to sell you this with the idea that
向你推销这个产品时，会考虑到这一点：
you're going to give me that it's a
你会给我这个的
harder trade but it's totally doable
交易难度更大，但完全可行。
it's funny because at the heart of all
这很有趣，因为所有这一切的核心都在于此。
of your messages Cody is this sort of
科迪，你的信息就是这样的。
deep op optimism and belief that one can
深切的乐观主义和信念，即一个人可以
just kind of bend the world and I say
就这么改变一下世界，然后我说
this because you know whenever we're
这是因为你知道，每当我们
talking about this hypothetical young
谈论这位假设的年轻
person everything is kind of just yeah
人的一切感觉都差不多，嗯。
just go ask this person to do this and
直接去问这个人要不要做这件事。
but and I was just as you saying that I
但是，我就像你说的那样，我
was thinking I resonate with that
我当时就在想，我对此深有同感。
because I was that 18 year-old kid that
因为我就是那个18岁的孩子
was just sending off the emails and
当时我只是在发送邮件而已。
asking people to help me and whatever
请求别人帮助我等等
else but I don't think the vast majority
除此之外，我认为绝大多数人不会这样。
of people have a deep internal belief
人们内心深处都有一种信念
that they can kind of just mold the
他们可以大致塑造
world yeah it's so true you know what I
世界啊，确实如此，你知道吗？
mean just like bend it in this direction
意思是像把它往这个方向弯一下一样
they think it is how it is and you you a
他们认为事情就是这样，而你，你
role within it not that you can just
在其中扮演的角色并非你只能如此
like yeah just go to a guy and knock on
对，就直接去敲敲门就行了。
his door and offer him this and you're
敲开他的门，把这个给他，你就会……
actually so right what I mean yeah it's
确实如此，我的意思就是这样，没错。
true it's a it's a bias that I think you
没错，这是一种偏见，我认为你
and me have because we've been exposed
我也有，因为我们已经接触过。
to the fact that you can't actually just
事实上，你不能只是
bend the world around yeah you just got
扭转乾坤，没错，你刚刚就得到了
to watch one person do it and then you
看着一个人做，然后你
go oh I'm a wizard too you know we're
哦，我也是个巫师，你知道我们
all wizards um is this your banister
所有巫师……嗯，这是你的栏杆吗？
effect idea that I heard you talk about
我听你说过那个效果创意
oh yeah that's right so well there's two
哦，对，没错，所以有两个
things I want to talk about one is
我想谈的事情之一是……
you've heard of of Steve Jobs um reality
你听说过史蒂夫·乔布斯吗？嗯，现实
Distortion field
畸变场
leely yeah so Steve Jobs was known for
leely 是的，所以史蒂夫·乔布斯以……而闻名
having this energy that basically made
拥有这种能量基本上使
other people around him believe that um
他周围的其他人也这么认为。
they could change the world that they
他们可以改变他们所处的世界
were Unstoppable and so he would talk
他势不可挡，所以他会说
people would talk afterwards after he
他去世后，人们会谈论他。
died about how he'd come into their
他去世时还在想着他是如何进入他们的。
office and he'd be like we're going to
办公室里，他会说我们要去……
ship this Pro product in 24 hours I know
我知道这款专业版产品会在24小时内发货。
we were going to do it in 3 weeks but
我们原本打算三周内完成，但是
we're going to do it in 24 hours he
我们将在24小时内完成这件事。
would get them all riled up and then
会把他们都激起情绪，然后
they would ship it in 24 hours and after
他们会在24小时内发货，之后
the 24 hours were done they would kind
24小时过去了，他们会很友善的。
of be like you know coming out from a
就像你知道的那样，从一个
blackout like what just happened how did
突然停电了，就像刚才发生的那样，是怎么回事？
he talk me into that that's his reality
他成功说服了我，那就是他的现实。
Distortion field which I think is
我认为这是畸变场。
fascinating because we all actually have
令人着迷的是，我们实际上都拥有
that ability his was really strong but
他的那种能力确实很强，但是
for nerds Star Wars nerds like I am out
对于像我这样的星战迷来说，这简直太糟糕了。
there it's it's like the force you know
就在那里，就像你知道的那种力量。
it's if you actually believe that you
如果你真的相信你
are capable of something it's weird what
能够做到一些奇怪的事情
you can accomplish amen I think so amen
你可以做到，阿门，我想也是，阿门。
yeah you know um so I like to you know
是啊，你知道，嗯，所以我喜欢你知道
if if you want to get a reality
如果你想实现这个目标
Distortion field reading the biographies
扭曲场解读传记
of billionaires is really powerful I'd
亿万富翁的力量真的很强大，我会
rather read 10 uh billionaires
不如读读《十大亿万富翁》
biographies than 200 self-help books
传记数量超过200本自助书籍
because they've actually done it and so
因为他们实际上已经做到了，所以
uh I think it's who's the guy that wrote
呃，我想应该是写这篇文章的那个人。
Steve Jobs book is it abramof Walter
史蒂夫·乔布斯的书是沃尔特·阿布拉姆的吗？
Ison Walter Isaacson yeah Incredible
艾森·沃尔特·艾萨克森，是的，不可思议
Book to even listen to to see that
甚至要听听这本书才能明白这一点。
reality Distortion field Elon Musk is
现实扭曲场埃隆·马斯克是
the same I mean I I spoke to Walter and
我的意思是，我和沃尔特谈过了。
he he told me that Elon has this just in
他告诉我埃隆刚刚有了这个
obsessive AB
强迫症 AB
to just assume that everything he's
就这么想当然地认为他的一切
being told is basically not true I.E if
被告知的内容基本上不是真的，例如如果
someone says something takes eight 8
有人说某事需要八个小时。
months or something he he seems to just
几个月或者更久，他似乎就只是
reject that idea on site and he
当场否决了这个想法，他
immediately asks about the core
立即询问核心部分
components of the challenge so he'll
挑战的组成部分，所以他会
immediately go right down to the roots
立即直达根部
of the problem Y and from there he'll
问题 Y，然后他会从那里开始
figure out that in fact it can get done
弄清楚这件事实际上是可以实现的。
in eight days and I and I just don't
还有八天，我，我就是不想
think people understand the advantage of
认为人们理解以下方面的优势
saving that amount of time on on big on
节省大量时间
any challenge you have in your life on
生活中你遇到的任何挑战
figuring out a way to make it happen
想办法实现它
faster because one of the great
速度更快，因为其中一位伟大的
currencies of all of our Lives is just
我们生活中的货币就是
the time that we have and some people
我们拥有的时间和一些人
are like some people will take three to
就像有些人会花三个小时
four years to start a business that with
四年时间创办一家企业
your information and that your
你的信息以及你的
understanding and your bias would
理解和你的偏见会
probably take you 90 days yeah that's a
大概需要90天，是的。
three like a three year emth saving on
就像三年的EMTH储蓄
life just because you have this sort of
仅仅因为你拥有这种生活，就无法拥有这种生活。
urgent bias you have this bias towards
你对紧急偏好有这种偏好
believing that all these deadlines are
认为所有这些截止日期都是
actually just um I don't know a [__]
其实就是……我不知道，胡说八道。
yeah I mean one of my favorite mentors
是的，我是说我最喜欢的导师之一。
told me a line that changed my life
一句话改变了我的人生
which was um it was Bill Perkins I asked
那个人是……嗯……我问的是比尔·帕金斯。
him why he's so successful in so many
他想知道为什么他在这么多领域都如此成功。
aspects of his life damn near a
他生活中的某些方面几乎
billionaire and uh and he said the only
亿万富翁，呃，他说只有
reason that I am successful is I'm
我成功的原因是我
faster than everybody else by the time
到那时，速度比其他人都快
they have thought about an idea taken it
他们考虑过一个方案并采纳了它。
to a meeting and started to move I have
去开会，然后开始走动，我有
already made three mistakes and found a
已经犯了三个错误，并且发现了一个
faster way and so his bias on speed is
更快的方式，所以他对速度的偏好是
fascinating if you ever hang out with
如果你有机会和他们一起玩，你会发现这很有趣。
guy it's wild you know I'll be like can
伙计，这太疯狂了，你知道吗？我会说“可以”。
we schedule a meeting he's like I'm
我们安排了一次会议，他就像……
calling you right now um and so he just
我现在正在给你打电话，嗯，所以他就……
moves quicker so in our companies we
行动更快，因此在我们的公司里，我们
implemented something called the 24-hour
实施了一项名为“24小时”的措施
rule which was this idea that if we want
这条规则的核心思想是，如果我们想要
to win we have to have a bias towards
要想赢，我们必须对……抱有偏见
action we have to decrease our time
我们必须采取行动来减少时间
between thinking about a thing and doing
在思考某事和实际行动之间
the thing and so most people say well
这件事，所以大多数人都会这么说。
I'll get back to you on that next week
我下周会回复你。
right get back to you on that next week
好的，下周我会再回复你。
hate that line that is where dreams and
讨厌那条线，那是梦想的起点。
money goes to die instead I say can you
钱都白白浪费了，我说你能吗？
get it to me tomorrow if all we do
如果我们只做一件事，那就明天把它给我。
different than our competitors is they
与我们的竞争对手不同的是，他们
take a week to do things and we get it
做事花一周时间，我们明白。
done in a day I don't have to be richer
一天就能搞定，我不需要变得更富有。
smarter or better I'm just faster and it
更聪明或者更优秀？我只是速度更快而已。
drives my team crazy many times but I'm
我经常让我的团队抓狂，但我
not smarter I'm really not I'm just very
不是更聪明，我真的不是，我只是非常
fast at a few things and I ignore a [__]
我擅长几件事，但我忽略了一件蠢事。
ton of stuff that I don't think is going
很多东西我觉得都不会发生
to move us
感动我们
forward you're you're the same I've seen
向前走，你还是我见过的那个你。
it with your team you know we've gone
和你的团队一起，你知道我们已经走了
back and forth with your team and then
与你的团队来回沟通，然后
you'll be like let's just do this one
你会想，那就做这一个吧。
thing right now instead I'm like oh yeah
现在我反而觉得，哦，是的
okay I sense MH I think speed is the
好的，我感觉到了MH，我认为速度是……
consistency it's Chris and I were just
始终如一，克里斯和我只是
talking about this I got annoyed the
谈到这件事，我感到很恼火。
other day because I was
前几天因为我
um you know what happens is people
嗯，你知道接下来会发生什么吗？人们
overthink things and in this day and age
过度思考，在这个时代
it happens more and more they they think
他们认为这种情况发生的频率越来越高。
about the thing and they confuse
关于这件事，他们感到困惑
thinking with work and more often than
思考工作，而且比
not thinking is not working and this is
不去思考是行不通的，而这正是
where people will yell at me on the
人们会在那里对我大喊大叫
internet and go well if I just don't
如果我不用网络，一切都会很顺利。
think about anything and I move really
想想任何事情，我都会真的动起来。
fast I could move fast in the wrong
我可以在错误的地方快速移动。
direction yeah you could but just
方向是的，你可以，但是只是
iterate move fast and iterate MH and
快速迭代移动并迭代MH和
that's what most people don't do and so
大多数人都不会那样做，所以
I'll tell my team all the time you're
我会一直告诉我的团队，你是
thinking about this way too much make a
想太多会……
decision in 30 seconds what's the
30秒内做出决定，这是什么？
decision I'll tell you if I like it yes
我会告诉你我是否喜欢它的决定。是的。
or no I like the decision move forward
或者，我喜欢这个决定，继续前进。
and so ask yourself that in life it's
所以问问自己，在生活中，这究竟意味着什么？
like Mel Robins 1 2 3 4 5 get out of bed
就像梅尔·罗宾斯一样，1 2 3 4 5 起床
yeah mine is 30 seconds to
是的，我的用时30秒。
decision I was it reminds me of a I
我做出的决定让我想起了我
think it was an sas former SAS soldier
我认为他是一名前SAS士兵。
that I was speaking to and he said his
我当时正在和他说话，他说他的
friend was going through a lot of
朋友当时正经历很多事
problems in his life going through a
他生活中遇到了很多问题。
divorce etc etc and he asked he called
离婚等等，他还问他打电话
him and asked him for advice he said
我向他请教，他说
you're an sas you know Soldier what
你知道，你是个特种部队士兵。
should I do and he said when you're in
我应该怎么做？他说当你在的时候
the middle of the woods and you're
你身处树林深处
feeling lost start walking yeah and it's
感觉迷路了，开始走，是的，就是这样。
a nice metaphor for life which is you
人生的一个绝妙比喻，那就是你。
you could you you'll die of starvation
你可能会饿死
just stood there overthinking about your
就站在那里，胡思乱想你的事
problems lost in the middle of the woods
迷失在森林深处的问题
but if you start walking you'll gain
但如果你开始走路，你就会有所收获。
some information you'll gain you'll gain
你会获得一些信息
your bearings and I think especially in
你的方位，我认为尤其是在
my earlier career I was certainly a
在我早期的职业生涯中，我当然是一名
victim of like procrastinating myself
我成了拖延症的受害者
into a hole with with a with a big
进入一个洞，用一个大的东西
business problem but even this morning I
业务问题，但即使是今天早上我
had something this morning my team in
今天早上我的团队遇到了一些事情。
the UK was speaking to me about a quite
英国方面正在和我谈论一件相当……
quite a critical business decision that
这是一个相当关键的商业决策。
I had to make and it's now in my old age
我不得不这样做，现在我已经年老了。
that I
我
realized
已实现
uh I realized I almost said like a flash
呃，我意识到我差点就说“像闪电一样”了
I like an older version of me was would
我喜欢年长的自己。
would spend three months trying to get
会花三个月时间试图获得
this decision right but a more mature
这个决定是正确的，但更成熟一些。
version of me knows that there is no
另一个版本的我知道没有
perfect outcome there's pain on all
完美的结果，但所有人都会感到痛苦。
sides of this
这边
decision so I have to write this long
所以我决定写下这么长一段话。
ass like essay memo this morning and
今天早上写这篇像作文备忘录一样的文章，真是让人头疼。
sent it into a person in my one of my
我把它发给了我认识的一个人。
offices in in in Europe and it's so
在欧洲设有办事处，而且非常……
crazy that they responded this person
他们居然回应了这个人，真是太疯狂了
responded within because I was so like I
内心回应是因为我太像我了
was so concerned about what they might
他非常担心他们可能会做什么。
say and how it might and they responded
他们会说什么，以及可能会如何回应
within 4 and a half minutes and they're
不到四分半钟，他们就……
like yeah cool got it I actually agree
嗯，明白了，我同意。
and no need to call me because I I
不用打电话给我，因为我
completely understand and I thought
完全理解，而且我认为
[__] hell that could have taken 3
妈的，本来可能要花3个小时。
months of us all in a boardroom
几个月来，我们所有人都在会议室里。
deliberating how to break this news 100%
正在斟酌如何发布这条消息 100%
it's interesting it's funny because the
这很有趣，也很搞笑，因为
people that are most experienced in
最有经验的人
business seem to be the most intense and
商业似乎最为紧张，
I think this kind of gives the clue as
我认为这算是给出了一些线索。
to why yeah you know one thing I've also
因为，你知道，还有一件事我也……
realized if you want to if you want to
如果你愿意的话，就实现吧
get higher level
提升等级
positions one of the other things you
定位你其他的事情之一
can do to get their faster I think is
我认为可以采取什么措施来更快地到达那里？
your speed of communication it's not
你的沟通速度并不快
even your speed of action so if you're
甚至你的行动速度，所以如果你是
in an interview don't Bumble [__] your
面试时别在 Bumble 上胡说八道
way through the interview think about
面试过程中要时刻思考
exactly what you want to say with as few
用尽可能少的文字，准确地表达你想说的话。
words as possible and be as direct as
尽量用最简洁的语言，并尽可能直接。
possible in it and I've realized there's
其中有可能，而且我已经意识到这一点。
a huge correlation in our Executives we
我们的高管之间存在巨大的相关性
hire between those who are good they
从那些优秀的人中选拔人才
speak fast they are clear and they don't
语速很快，他们表达清晰，而且他们不
waste other people's times you know
你知道，别浪费别人的时间。
there are a couple Executives I still
还有几位高管我仍然
have at some of my companies and there
我的某些公司也有这种情况，而且
are two that I know I have to move on
我知道我必须放下这两件事。
because they're not fast enough and
因为他们的速度不够快，而且
they're not fast enough in their
他们的速度不够快
communication I should have seen that
沟通方面，我应该早就注意到这一点。
UPF front and I think the way that you
UPF 前部，我认为你的方式
communicate is often the way you work
沟通通常是你工作的方式。
and it doesn't mean that you have for
但这并不意味着你已经拥有了
instance I don't respond to all text
例如，我不会回复所有短信。
messages you know I don't think that
你知道，我不这么认为。
every single thing that comes in front
前面出现的每一件事
of me needs to be handled I probably let
我的问题需要处理，我可能放任不管了。
40% of things go
40%的事情会
unanswered and 20% of things I am on top
未解答的问题以及我处于领先地位的 20% 的事情
of it like sauron's eye and Lord of the
它就像索伦之眼和魔王一样。
Rings I'm just watching if if I was to
戒指 我只是在看着，如果我要……
look at your business do you think that
看看你的生意，你觉得呢？
your highest performers is there sort of
你公司业绩最好的员工就在那里。
a correlation between how much how much
多少之间的相关性
they talk and how much they don't there
他们谈论，以及他们不谈论的程度。
is a correlation between having no
是否存在相关性，即没有
patience for wasted time interesting
对浪费时间的耐心很有趣
tell me so for instance one of my guys
例如，告诉我，我的一个手下
here Tanner he's like oh man I can't
坦纳说，哦，天哪，我不能
engage with this human because they're
与这个人互动，因为他们
always talking to me and I don't really
总是跟我说话，但我不太喜欢。
have time to do that and that is what I
我有时间做这件事，而这正是我要做的。
have found with high performers they do
我们发现，对于高绩效者来说，他们确实如此
not like when you waste their time and
不像你浪费他们的时间那样
so you know if you think about the
所以你知道，如果你仔细想想……
typical office life why do we not like
典型的办公室生活，我们为什么不喜欢？
typical office life because people come
典型的办公室生活，因为人们会来
in it's like water cooler [__] talk
就像茶水间闲聊一样
nobody really says anything you ask
你问什么，没人会回答。
about the kids you don't know the kids'
关于孩子们，你不认识孩子们。
names what happened this weekend you
请说出这个周末发生的事情。
don't really care High performers are
不太在意 高绩效者是
not interested in that why because you
我对那个不感兴趣，因为你
want to perform you want to talk about
你想表演，你想谈论
interesting things that move you forward
能推动你前进的有趣事物
and then you want to go live your life
然后你想继续过你的生活
you want out of the office I found
你想离开办公室，我发现
low-level performers they actually want
他们真正想要的其实是低水平的绩效人员。
to waste time during the day because
白天浪费时间，因为
they're not trying to execute they're
他们不是在试图执行任务，他们是
trying to just show that they are there
他们只是想表明他们的存在。
and there's a big difference between the
两者之间存在很大的区别
two and every time I hire a low
二，而且每次我雇佣低
performer it's because I ignore that
表演者，是因为我忽略了这一点。
point you
指出你
know which point the urgency the lack of
知道哪个点体现了紧迫性，哪个点体现了缺乏紧迫性
urgency in time yes yes I forget about
时间紧迫，是的，是的，我忘了。
it in the interview you know and it's
你知道，在面试中就会提到这一点。
really important to pay attention to
务必注意
those types of people in your life who
你生活中那些类型的人
are the people that just are okay
那些人，就只是还不错而已。
wasting your time because what does that
浪费你的时间，因为这有什么用呢？
mean if they're okay wasting your time
意思是他们是否愿意浪费你的时间
they're definitely wasting their time
他们肯定是在浪费时间
there was a phrase that I read in your
我在你那里读到过一句话。
work where you use the phrase obsessed
工作中你会用到“痴迷”这个词。
not interested oh yeah and I really love
没兴趣哦，对了，我真的很喜欢
that I actually screenshotted it on the
我当时还截屏保存了呢。
way over here today and I sent it to
今天我特地跑到这里，然后把它寄了过去。
some some of my team members that I talk
我跟我的一些团队成员聊过。
about this a lot too about this idea of
关于这一点，也关于这个想法，有很多话要说。
obsession and specifically the team
对团队的痴迷
members that are on the Forefront of
处于前沿的成员
really hiring people because there is a
确实需要招聘人手，因为确实存在这种情况。
big correlation between the outcome of
结果之间存在很大的相关性
someone who is obsessed versus someone
痴迷的人与
who isn't yeah and the obsessed people
谁不是呢？还有那些痴迷的人。
are just always the best they win you
他们总是最棒的，他们赢了你
know I was with Carl Rove again who's
我知道我又和卡尔·罗夫在一起了，他是谁？
like not a popular figure but he was
他虽然不是一个受欢迎的人物，但他
chief of the chief of staff Deputy Chief
参谋长 副参谋长
of Staff to George W bush and is like
乔治·W·布什的幕僚，就像
one of they call him the architect
其中一人称他为建筑师
because he Architects most of the
因为他设计了大部分……
Republican races in this country and so
这个国家的共和党竞选，以及……
whether you like it or not I'm I don't
不管你喜不喜欢，我都不喜欢
really care I don't need to like
我真的不在乎，我不需要喜欢
somebody to learn from them doesn't
没有人愿意向他们学习
matter to me and so I I had him on the
这对我来说很重要，所以我让他参与进来了。
podcast to hear like what does it mean
听播客，比如它是什么意思
to like architect the centers of power
就像建筑师设计权力中心一样。
that's fascinating and um when I was
那太有趣了，嗯，当我……
talking to him what stood out to me I'd
和他交谈后，我印象最深刻的是……
been in meetings with him multiple times
我曾多次与他会面。
and at his house a few times for for
而且有好几次都在他家。
fundraising events and I would watch him
他会参加筹款活动，我会观看他的活动。
and somebody would ask a question that
然后有人会问这样一个问题：
was like hey why did Bob Sanders and
我当时就想，嘿，为什么鲍勃·桑德斯和
Pennsylvania lose this Senatorial race
宾夕法尼亚州在这场参议员选举中失利
and his response would be like well we
他的回应大概是这样的：我们
lost it by you know 1,200 votes on the
你知道，我以1200票之差输掉了比赛。
third Friday on like December 4th 2012
2012年12月4日，第三个星期五
and the reason is because we didn't have
原因是我们没有
this segment of the population come out
这部分人口出来了
and then he would do that for like five
然后他会这样做，大概持续五分钟。
locations across the country and I
全国各地的地点以及我
remember I asked him I was like do you
记得我问过他，我说，你愿意吗？
have a photographic memory and he's like
他拥有过目不忘的本领，而且他就像……
absolutely not I only have one about the
绝对不是，我只有一个关于
things I'm obsessed with and I think we
我痴迷的事物，我认为我们
all actually have that like you've met
实际上，他们都像你遇到的那样。
friends where like they know every scho
朋友们好像认识学校里的每一个人。
score of a football game for Manchester
曼彻斯特队在一场足球比赛中的比分
United ever do they have a photographic
曼联到底有没有照片？
memory no they're obsessed and so if you
记忆力不行，他们很痴迷，所以如果你
can find people who are obsessed with
可以找到痴迷于此的人
the thing that you're doing it just
你正在做的这件事只是
means they don't work hard they're just
这意味着他们不努力工作，他们只是……
like they they think of it as hardly
就像他们认为这几乎是不可能的
working because they're so intense on it
因为他们对这项工作非常投入，所以才能成功。
and they can't help themselves well I
他们也控制不住自己，好吧。
was thinking of that as well as career
我当时也在考虑这一点，还有职业生涯。
advice as you're saying it because if
正如你所说，建议很重要，因为如果
I'm trying to figure out where to place
我正在想办法把它放在哪里。
myself to end up in the best place in 10
让自己最终在10岁之前到达最好的地方
years from now I should be placing
多年以后，我应该会……
myself against my my my true obsessions
我自己对抗我自己，我真正的执念
and you can't have fake obsessions yeah
你不能有虚假的痴迷，是的。
true you can't have a fake Obsession you
没错，你不可能有虚假的痴迷。
can't be obsessed about something you're
你不能对某件事过于执着。
not because it's like what are you doing
不是因为你会问“你在做什么”之类的问题。
at what video are you watching on
你在看哪个视频？
YouTube at 3:00 a.m. that's keeping you
凌晨三点还在看YouTube，这就是让你沉迷的原因。
from sleeping is my like sense check of
从睡梦中醒来就像是我的感官检查。
what I'm actually obsessed about that's
我真正痴迷的是……
a great point and presumably that's
这一点很重要，想必就是这样。
what's going to take me the furthest in
什么能让我走得最远？
my career or is that would you I think
我的职业生涯，或者说，你会这么想吗？
that's right and how do you teach
没错，那你是如何教的呢？
yourself to become obsessed with the
让自己沉迷于此
aspects of your business or whatever
你业务的方方面面或其他任何方面
that you need to like for instance I
你需要喜欢的东西，例如我
think a lot of people think of obsession
很多人认为痴迷就是痴迷。
like passion and hob
就像激情和爱好
you know I'm obsessed with Manchester
你知道我有多迷曼彻斯特
United and you know that's my that's
联合航空，你知道那是我的，那是
where my obsession goes well are you
我的痴迷之处在哪里？嗯，你呢？
obsessed with it you know or could you
你知道，或者你能理解我为什么对它着迷吗？
figure out that you're obsessed
意识到你已经着迷了
with you're obsessed with the way that
你痴迷于这种方式
you feel when you're in an environment
你在某种环境中的感受
that is kinetic like you know you love
那是一种你懂的动感，你爱它
that feeling of the crazy songs you guys
你们那些疯狂的歌曲给我带来的那种感觉
sing at the match so like where else
在比赛现场唱歌，就像在其他任何地方一样。
could you be where there's a kinetic
你是否身处一个有动力的地方？
energy like that all the time well maybe
一直保持那种能量，或许吧。
actually you like Live Events maybe you
其实你喜欢现场活动，也许你
like live events in conferences you know
比如你知道的，会议中的现场活动。
maybe you actually just want to have a
或许你其实只是想要一个
crazy team almost cult-like environment
疯狂的团队，近乎邪教般的氛围
can you become obsessed with that and
你会对它着迷吗？
then I do think that you can you can
那么我认为你可以，你可以。
catch being obsessed with winning you
别再执着于赢你了
can catch that because if you get a few
可能会感染，因为如果你感染几个
little tastes of winning in something
尝到一点胜利的滋味
it's really easy to go o I want I want a
真的很容易，我想要，我想要一个
little bit more of that and that's
再多加一点就差不多了。
definitely my addiction speaking of
当然，说到我的瘾，那肯定算一个。
addictions gateway drug businesses oh
成瘾是毒品交易的入门途径，哦
yeah you mentioned the term earlier what
是的，你之前提到过这个词。
what does that mean gateway drug
“入门毒品”是什么意思？
business is a business that is so simple
商业就是如此简单。
that you can explain it to your
你可以向你的
grandmother mhm and also you can
奶奶嗯，你也可以
probably run it even if you've never run
即使你从未运行过，也可能需要运行它。
a business before and those are things
之前做过生意，这些都是事情
like
喜欢
laundromats car washes I talk about
我谈论的自助洗衣店和洗车店
those two in particular because if you
尤其是那两个人，因为如果你
can't understand cleaning clothes and if
不明白如何清洗衣服，如果
you can't understand cleaning cars
你根本不懂洗车。
probably don't do any business there
可能不会在那里做任何生意。
there's the 1% that just like you know
还有那1%的人，就像你一样。
go work for somebody else don't worry
去给别人工作吧，别担心。
about it but most people can understand
虽然有点复杂，但大多数人都能理解。
how those businesses work and why I like
我喜欢这些企业的运作方式以及我为什么喜欢它们。
simple businesses like that not a lot of
像这样的简单企业不多。
employees not a lot of moving Parts not
员工不多，活动部件也不多
a lot of change is because then you can
很多变化都是因为这样你就可以……
get a little taste of winning you can
尝尝胜利的滋味吧
get addicted to the game of business and
沉迷于商业游戏
then your next business can be something
那么你的下一个事业可能就是……
better than a laundr map better than a
比洗衣店地图好，比……好
car wash but you can learn on a smaller
洗车，但你可以在较小的洗车场学习。
playing field but you're presumably not
竞争环境，但你大概不在。
going to make much money if everybody
如果每个人都能赚很多钱，那将会赚很多钱。
can do it no you're not going to make
可以做到，不，你做不到。
much money but I don't think your first
钱很多，但我觉得这不是你的第一笔钱。
deal is never going to be your last deal
这笔交易永远不会是你的最后一笔交易。
which is I think important for people to
我认为这对人们来说很重要
realize in buying businesses in life
在生活中购买企业时意识到这一点
just like your first job isn't either
就像你的第一份工作也不是一样
but but man if you are working on a in a
但是，伙计，如果你正在做一件……
W2 right now let's say and on the side
假设现在是W2，并且在旁边
you go buy an Airbnb business or you buy
你可以去买一家Airbnb民宿，或者买
a laundromat or a car wash that are not
一家自助洗衣店或一家洗车店，并非
very intense on the number of people
非常注重人数
that you have to have run them not that
你必须运行它们，而不是……
expensive for you to do you're going to
对你来说，这样做成本很高。
learn how to run a p&amp;l you're going to
学习如何管理损益表，你即将……
learn how to Market you're going to
学习如何进行市场营销，你即将……
learn how to make money every single
学习如何每天赚钱
business has these same characteristics
商业也具有这些相同的特征。
and so you learn in this small one and
所以你在这个小地方就能学到东西。
then you sell the business because
然后你把公司卖掉，因为
that's the beautiful part about a
这就是它的美妙之处
business is you can sell it to somebody
生意就是你可以把它卖给别人。
else and then you're like oh I may
否则，你就会想，哦，我可能
you know I always think about it as in
你知道我总是这样想的
private Equity we say level one to 10
我们把私募股权分为一到十级。
games level one to 10 operators so 10
游戏等级 1 到 10，操作员人数为 10 人。
being the best game you could play 10
是你所能玩到的最好的游戏 10
being the best operator you could have
成为你所能拥有的最佳操作员
the best operator in the world Elon Musk
世界最佳运营者埃隆·马斯克
with you know probably some SAS
你知道，可能还有一些特种部队成员。
companies like he has a rocket ship
像他这样的公司拥有一艘火箭飞船
company a Marketplace he's playing he's
他正在玩的是一家市场公司
a level 10 operator playing a level 10
一名10级操作员玩10级
game but in the beginning you know he he
游戏，但一开始你知道他他
didn't do that he was like trying to
他没那么做，他好像在试图……
figure it out just like the rest of us
像我们其他人一样，自己想办法解决吧。
so you'll start with your one business
所以你将从你的第一家企业开始。
and then you'll scale up to better and
然后你就能扩大规模，做得更好。
better and better games is there a is
游戏越来越好玩了吗？
there any age group that I should be
我应该属于哪个年龄段？
thinking about buying these boring
考虑买这些无聊的东西
businesses off oh yeah baby boomers
企业倒闭了，哦，是的，婴儿潮一代
right now are retiring across this
现在他们正在陆续退休
country in levels that we have never
国家达到了我们从未达到过的水平
seen this is a generational wealth
这是一笔代际财富。
creation event really across the world
创作活动遍及全球
post uh Baby Boom generation which
婴儿潮一代之后的那一代
happened after World War II and um and
二战后发生的，嗯，
so one thing that's fascinating about
所以，有一点很吸引人，
the baby boomer generation is they own
婴儿潮一代是他们自己的
most of the businesses so more than 50%
大多数企业，超过50%
of uh small businesses are owned by baby
很多小型企业都是婴儿拥有的。
MERS they are reaching retirement or
MERS，他们即将退休或
already there and they 65% of them do
已经在那里了，其中65%的人确实如此。
not have a um transition plan so their
他们没有过渡计划，所以他们的
plan is I'm going to live forever no
我的计划是永生，不
you're not they need to do something
你不是他们需要做点什么。
with that business most of them will
有了那项业务，他们中的大多数人都会
just shut down the business there's
直接把那家店关掉就行了。
something like 11 million small
大约1100万个小
businesses right now for sale in the US
目前美国有企业出售
most of those small businesses something
大多数小企业
like 70% of them will never sell whether
比如其中70%永远都卖不出去
because they aren't good enough
因为他们不够好。
businesses quote unquote to
企业报价
traditionally sell or because they never
传统上出售，或者因为他们从未
find a buyer and this phenomenon is
找到买家，这种现象就是
going to happen all over the US here's
这种情况将在美国各地发生。
the problem if we don't buy these
如果我们不买这些东西，就会出现问题。
businesses they say that there are
他们说，有一些企业
trillions of dollars in the baby boomer
婴儿潮一代的数万亿美元
generation that are going to be
即将成为的这一代人
transferred to the Next Generation we've
我们已经转移到下一代
all heard those numbers the problem is
大家都听到了这些数字，问题是……
people are thinking bank accounts money
人们都在想银行账户里的钱。
being handed down all the money's in
所有的钱都传给了别人
business when you are a small business
当你是小企业时，你的生意会是什么样子？
owner 90% of your net worth is wrapped
拥有者，你90%的净资产都被包裹起来了。
up in your business that's the average
就你们公司而言，这就是平均水平。
so that means 90% of the trillions is in
所以这意味着万亿中的90%都在
small businesses and if we don't buy
小企业，如果我们不购买的话
those businesses and take them over that
收购那些企业。
wealth evaporates and what happens then
财富蒸发后会发生什么？
Black Rock and Blackstone go in they buy
黑石集团和黑石集团入场，他们买入
all those businesses they get richer
所有这些企业都变得更富有了
they own our communities and we don't so
他们拥有我们的社区，而我们却没有。
you should be targeting people who are
你应该瞄准那些……
65 plus looking for the next move
65岁以上人士正在寻找下一步发展机会
probably open to seller financing
可能接受卖方融资
probably have a business that's a little
可能经营着一家规模较小的公司
hairy might even be more like a job than
毛茸茸的或许更像是一份工作
a business but you have an opportunity
这是一项业务，但你有一个机会
to buy that business or be an apprentice
买下那家企业或者做学徒
in into the business and take it over
进入公司并接管它
and when I'm thinking about which
当我思考哪个时
business to buy do I have to reflect on
要收购一家企业，我需要考虑什么？
what I'm good at or where where my sort
我擅长什么，或者我的类型在哪里
of Leverage is in terms of being able to
杠杆作用体现在能够……
take that laundry mat and make it 5x in
把那家自助洗衣店扩大 5 倍
Revenue over the next couple of years is
未来几年的收入是
you know are there certain businesses
你知道，有些企业
that are right for certain people based
适合某些特定人群的
on their experience for sure I think um
就他们的经验而言，我认为肯定是的。
so one yes if you want to play a bigger
所以，如果你想玩更大的游戏，答案是肯定的。
game if you want to be a top performer
如果你想成为顶尖选手，就玩这个游戏吧
if you want to be one of those level 10
如果你想成为那10级玩家之一
operators you should find a business
运营商们，你们应该找到一家企业
that is uniquely suited for you the
最适合你的
problem is I think a lot of people don't
问题是，我认为很多人都不这么认为。
know how to do that we have something
知道该怎么做，我们有办法。
called a deal Clarity worksheet where we
我们称之为交易清晰度工作表，其中我们
basically take people through where do
基本上是带人们了解该去哪里
you want the business to be located what
您希望企业位于哪里？
are you good at uniquely you know what
你擅长什么？你知道吗？
uh how much money does the business need
呃，这家企业需要多少钱？
to make for you how much money can you
你能为你赚多少钱？
put into the business um what type of
投入到业务中，嗯，是哪种类型的
businesses do you absolutely not want to
企业绝对不想
do you know what seem interesting to you
你知道你对什么感兴趣吗？
but I think the bigger issue for people
但我认为对人们来说，更大的问题是……
is trying to take the first move as
试图抢占先机
opposed to obsess on what industry or
相反，不要过分关注哪个行业或领域。
sector and think about it in 3 to five
该领域，并思考 3 到 5 分钟。
year increments it's just like you would
以年为单位递增，就像你会……
a job you get a job you think I'm going
找到工作，你觉得我要去
to do this thing for two to three years
做这件事两到三年
think the same thing with the business
对企业也有同样的看法。
and the Only Rule in buying businesses
收购企业的唯一规则
in my opinion is that you never want to
我认为你永远都不想
do a bad first deal because then you
第一笔交易搞砸了，因为那样你
won't do another one so you want to do
不会再做第二个了，所以你想做
one where you can decrease your risk to
一个可以降低风险的地方
bankruptcy what you mean by that how do
破产是什么意思？
I stop myself doing a bad Fest deal yeah
我阻止了自己做出糟糕的音乐节交易，是的。
the lots of one you should spend more
你应该多花点钱。
time learning how to do a deal than
学习如何做交易的时间比
actually doing the deal this is where I
实际上，交易就是在这里进行的。
always get nervous talking about this
每次谈到这个话题我都会紧张。
publicly because people like sweet I'm
公开场合，因为人们喜欢甜美的我
going to go buy laundr matat and talk to
准备去买洗衣店，然后跟他们谈谈
Cody you know she seems like she tells
科迪，你知道她好像会说……
me that everybody should own laundromats
我认为每个人都应该拥有自助洗衣店
I'm like no take a minute you know we we
我心想，不，稍等片刻，你知道我们……
teach at contrarian thinking we teach
在逆向思维教学中，我们教授
basically a 90day period where for
基本上是一个为期90天的时期，在此期间……
somewhere between 20 and 40 minutes a
大约20到40分钟之间
day you're learning about how to buy
你今天学习如何购买
businesses it's like your little 90-day
企业就像你的90天小期计划
m&amp;a MBA right and I want you to learn
并购MBA没错，我希望你学习
how to do a deal first one because
如何先达成交易？因为
you'll be able to negotiate anything you
你将能够就任何事进行谈判
want for the rest of your life you'll
你余生都渴望的
speak the language of money which is
用金钱的语言说话
equity and ownership and two because if
股权和所有权，以及第二点，因为如果
you just go buy a business you're not
你直接去买一家你并不拥有的企业。
going to know how do I negotiate it
我想知道该如何谈判
correctly what is the valuation of the
正确来说，估值是多少？
business how do I determine this guy's
我该如何判断这个人的商业行为？
not lying to me those it's called due
别骗我，那叫应得
diligence and so um I like people to
勤奋，所以，嗯，我喜欢人们……
learn that part and then once you've
学会那部分内容，然后一旦你……
learned that part you can go out and you
学会了那部分，你就可以出去了，然后你
start to date just like you would on
开始约会，就像你在……一样
Tinder or anywhere else let me look at
Tinder或其他任何地方，让我看看
this business let me look at that
这家公司让我有机会了解一下。
business I call it the 100 to one so
我称之为“百比一”的商业模式
typically you want to kind of kind of
通常你想有点……
like you're on Zillow you're probably
就像你在Zillow上一样，你可能
going to look at 100 houses on Zillow
我打算在 Zillow 上看 100 套房子。
right kind of like I like this I don't
对，有点像我喜欢的那种，我不喜欢。
like this you figure out exactly what is
这样你就能准确地弄清楚什么是
important to you and then you filter it
对你来说很重要，然后你把它筛选掉
down
向下
to your your one the one that looks
给你的那个，看起来
right for you at this moment that you're
此刻最适合你的就是你
going to stay in for the next two to
接下来两天我打算待在家里。
three years and where did you find these
三年了，你是从哪里找到这些的？
businesses to buy is there a website
想收购的企业有网站吗？
yeah there's lots um we have we have one
是的，有很多，嗯，我们有一个。
that's coming out that'll be really cool
即将推出的那个东西肯定很酷
but I don't think it'll be out by the
但我认为它不会在……之前发布
time this podcast is there so basically
这个播客的时间就是这样，所以基本上
the problem right now in buying small
目前小额采购的问题在于
businesses is there's no good way to
企业没有好的解决办法
find them online there's no Zillow
在网上找，没有 Zillow。
there's no NLS there's something called
没有NLS，只有一种东西叫做
Biz by sell but it's shitty it's got all
靠卖东西赚钱，但是太烂了，什么都有。
this trash on it so we basically are
上面全是垃圾，所以我们基本上是
building something that's the opposite
建造与此相反的东西
of that because the biggest two biggest
之所以如此，是因为最大的两个
questions I get are what type of
我经常被问到的问题是，哪种类型的
business I should buy where is it where
我应该买的生意在哪里？
do I find it can you give me the
我找到了吗？你能给我吗？
business so we're building something to
所以我们正在打造一些业务，以……
that regard um but right now you could
在这方面，嗯，但现在你可以
go to bis byell you could go to bis
去比斯，你也可以去比斯
scout.com that's the one that we own
scout.com，那是我们拥有的网站。
it'll be a waiting page you won't be
那将是一个等待页面，你不会是
able to see anything on it yet um you
还能看到上面的任何东西吗？嗯……
could go to um um e-commerce flippers
可以去电商投机者那里。
you could go to Flippa those are online
你可以去Flippa看看，那些网站都在网上。
business sites promoting all your
商业网站推广您的所有业务
competition I know well the truth of the
我深知竞争的真相
matter is
事情是
we're so good at this like there's
我们在这方面太擅长了，简直……
nowhere better to learn m&amp;a than us
没有比我们这里更好的并购学习场所了。
which is cool I'm really you know I want
这很酷，我真的，你知道我想要
to invest in this biscot thing oh
投资这个饼干生意哦
actually you should I I can't believe I
其实你应该……我简直不敢相信我
didn't ask you for that actually are you
我其实没问你这个吧？
you raising Investments we we rais a
你们筹集投资，我们筹集资金
couple million dollars for bis Scout and
几百万美元用于 bis Scout 和
in it is Shan rad so the founder of
其中有 Shan rad，所以是创始人
Tinder uh Bill Perkins um bology oh CTO
Tinder 呃 比尔·帕金斯 嗯 生物学 哦 首席技术官
coinbase me Andrew Wilkinson uh from
Coinbase 我 Andrew Wilkinson 呃 来自
Tiny capital and uh three guys called
小额资金，还有三个叫……的家伙
kmen Ventures their former Founders fund
kmen Ventures 是他们之前的创始基金
and um Uber PayPal guys and so we did a
还有 Uber 和 PayPal 的各位，所以我们做了
really small round because I think we
非常小的圆形，因为我认为我们
can run it profitably so I don't want
它可以盈利运营，所以我不想要它。
this to be like a uh you know we need to
这就像……你知道，我们需要……
raise $200 million I don't think we need
筹集2亿美元？我觉得我们不需要。
to do that I think with my audience
我认为要做到这一点，需要对我的观众来说。
because we'll already have Distribution
因为我们已经有了分销渠道。
on lock we basically can funnel all the
锁定后，我们基本上可以把所有东西都集中起来。
buyers and sellers to this site and then
买家和卖家来到这个网站，然后
create a better Mouse trp um so I hired
创建一个更好的 Mouse trp 嗯，所以我雇佣了
the former had a Marketplace at SeatGeek
前者在SeatGeek上有一个市场。
who took it from 5% uh market share to
谁将其市场份额从 5% 提升至
40% he's an animal and um and that's my
40% 他是畜生，嗯，这就是我的
Billion Dollar Bet what's the how do you
十亿美元的赌注，你怎么做？
monetize that I guess you do you take a
我想你肯定是通过这种方式赚钱的，你拿走
cut on the deal lots of different ways
削减交易成本的方式有很多种。
so we're gonna try to not get too tied
所以我们要尽量不要太纠结。
to one individual way to monetize but
以一种个人方式实现盈利，但
the idea is there's really like three
这个想法是，实际上有三个。
things that suck about finding a
寻找工作中令人沮丧的事情
business to buy one is if you're the
如果你是企业主，那么购买一台就是明智之举。
seller you get all these this like all
卖家，你会收到所有这些，就像所有这些一样。
these offes reaching out to you who
这些联系你的人
don't really want to buy your business
我其实并不想收购你的企业。
and they're super distracting like
它们非常分散注意力，比如
they're not capable they're not able so
他们没有能力，他们做不到。
we're going to create all these
我们将创造所有这些
mechanisms to screen who's reaching out
筛选联系者的机制
to you you're going to be able to see do
对你来说，你将能够看到……
they have funds cleared already what's
他们已经拿到资金了，那是什么？
their linked in you know do they have
你知道，他们在领英上有关系吗？他们有
credit history are the SBA pre-approved
信用记录是 SBA 预先批准的
like all the stuff that should be common
就像所有那些理应是常识的东西一样。
sense doesn't exist we're going to have
理智并不存在，我们将要拥有
that screening then we also have uh for
然后我们还有那个筛选，呃，为了
buyers we'll have businesses that are
买家方面，我们将拥有一些企业。
seller financing uh open so we'll have a
卖方融资方案开放，所以我们会有一个
whole screening of businesses where it's
对相关企业进行全面筛查
like hey you don't have financing well
比如，嘿，你没有资金。
these people are open to seller
这些人对卖家持开放态度。
financing we're also going to have uh
融资方面，我们也会……
we're using AI to basically curate the
我们正在使用人工智能来精心策划……
selection right now there's all these
现在可供选择的有所有这些
like fake franchises and stuff on these
比如这些虚假的特许经营权之类的东西
sites and it would be like if you went
网站，就好像你去了
to Zillow and they're like you like this
去Zillow看看，他们就像你一样。
house buy this house it doesn't exist
买这栋房子，它根本不存在
but you could build it you'd be very
但你可以建造它，你会非常
annoyed right and that's what it is in
确实很恼火，就是这样。
in business buying land right now so
目前正在进行土地买卖业务
we're going to charge for all series of
我们将对所有系列收费
that we'll probably charge Brokers for
我们可能会向经纪人收取费用
leads too but if I don't have that right
也会导致这种情况，但如果我没有那个权利的话
now yeah yeah then you got to go to bis
是啊是啊，那你得去比斯了。
by sell okay and what about just like
卖出去可以，那就像……
knocking on my local laundry M door and
敲响了我家附近洗衣店的门
and well the best way to find deals we
而寻找优惠的最佳方式就是我们
have something at bisc out that's called
饼干上有一种叫做
an off-market deal Searcher and so
场外交易搜索者等等
there's two ways to buy deals or buy
购买优惠或购买商品有两种方式。
businesses just like real estate right
就像房地产一样，企业也应该如此。
onm Market would be Zillow or bis Scout
onm Market 可能是 Zillow 或 bis Scout。
off-market would be door knocking right
非公开交易就是挨家挨户敲门。
you're going around door knocking people
你挨家挨户敲门拜访人们。
don't do that in real estate really
在房地产领域，千万别这么做。
anymore but in small business land I
不再是这样了，但在小企业领域，
have we teach 12 different strategies
我们教授了12种不同的策略
but one of the best strategies I think
但我认为这是最好的策略之一。
is called your personal p&amp;l review so if
这叫做你的个人损益回顾，所以如果
you're a business owner this is a
您是一位企业主，这是
no-brainer if you're a business owner
如果你是企业主，这根本不用考虑。
right now you should look at all the
现在你应该看看所有这些
places that you spend money or you can
你花钱的地方，或者你可以
actually get to the owner so not Amazon
实际上联系到了所有者，而不是亚马逊。
right and you're going to look at all
对，你要查看所有内容
your expenses on your credit card
你的信用卡支出
statement and figure out are any of my
声明并找出我的任何一项
vendors small enough and good enough
规模足够小且质量足够好的供应商
that I might be able to own part of that
我或许能够拥有其中的一部分。
business or the whole business and so
企业或整个企业，因此
you know you would just go down the list
你知道你会按顺序逐条查看清单。
and go ah we spend all this money with
然后我们就把这些钱都花在……
these people why don't I own part of
这些人，为什么我不能拥有一部分股份？
this business business and then if
这家企业，然后如果
you're an individual you can do the same
你也是一个独立的个体，你也可以做到这一点。
thing a fun one that we teach people
一件很有趣的事，我们教给人们
who've never bought businesses before
以前从未购买过企业的人
never run anything before I could never
我以前从未跑过任何赛道，我永远也跑不了。
buy a business I have no money we teach
买下一家企业，我没有钱，我们教
them the venmo challenge which is
他们接受了Venmo挑战，这是
basically you open up your venmo or
基本上，你打开你的 Venmo 账户或
PayPal because that means you're doing
PayPal，因为这意味着你在做
TR cash transactions so it's a small
TR现金交易，所以金额很小。
business and you look through them all
企业，你把它们都看一遍。
and you're like huh my landscaper my
然后你就想，嗯，我的园丁，我的
cleaning lady maybe my you know the the
清洁女工，也许你知道的
farmers market that I just bought some
我刚从农贸市场买了一些东西
cheese from I'm going to go to all of
我要去的奶酪
these people where I could get to the
这些人，我可以接触到他们
owner and say hey could I buy into part
老板说，嘿，我能买一部分股份吗？
of your business maybe and you know you
也许你的生意就是这样，你知道的
cleaned my house do you need more
我打扫过我的房子了，你还需要更多吗？
customers maybe I could help you get 20
或许我可以帮您拿到20个客户。
more customers and I could own part of
客户越多，我就能拥有股份。
your business if I help you grow it
如果我帮助你发展业务，你的业务就会增长
would you be open to that and so we do a
你是否愿意接受？所以我们就这么做了。
venmo challenge with people who've never
与从未用过 Venmo 的人一起挑战
owned a business because then you get a
拥有自己的企业，因为那样你就能获得……
partial shot at a business is there a
部分镜头拍摄的商业场所是否存在？
bit of a generational opportunity in the
这算得上是一个具有时代意义的机遇。
sense that the younger Generations are
感觉年轻一代是
native to social media so they have
社交媒体原生支持，所以他们拥有
their own leverage when they're
当他们……时，他们自身的筹码
brokering those conversations they can
他们可以促成这些对话。
go to their baby boomer and say listen
去找他们的婴儿潮一代，说听
you're running a great laundry map but
你的洗衣地图做得很好，但是
there's this thing called Tik Tok and I
有个东西叫抖音，而我
can make you bang on Tik Tok and so if
可以让你在TikTok上疯狂刷屏，所以如果
you give me I know 30% 50% 100% of your
你给我我知道你的30%、50%、100%
business we're going to with my unique
我们将用我独特的方式开展业务
leverage because I know how to make
利用我知道如何做事
content on Tik Tok I'm going to send
我将在TikTok上发送的内容
this thing to the Moon Grandpa yeah
这东西到月球去，爷爷，是的
exactly Grandad yeah that's exactly
没错，爷爷，就是这样。
right I mean I think all you have to do
对，我的意思是，我认为你只需要做
to understand this is understand how
要理解这一点，就必须理解如何
much a business makes so in order for
企业赚多少钱，为了
you to ask for Equity you got to figure
你想要求股权，就得自己想办法。
out what it's worth right and there's a
弄清楚它的价值，对吧？
very easy way to do that you go online
最简单的办法就是上网。
and you go what is the average
然后你去问，平均值是多少？
laundromat in
洗衣店
Charleston South Carolina make per year
南卡罗来纳州查尔斯顿每年收入
oh it's about $200,000 okay what's the
哦，大概是20万美元，好的，那是什么？
average profit margin of a
平均利润率
laundromat 15% okay so I know that this
洗衣店 15% 好的，所以我知道这一点
business is probably making something
企业可能正在生产某种东西。
like $30,000 a year because that's a
比如一年3万美元，因为那是
profit off of 200k uh in Charleston so
在查尔斯顿赚了20万美元，所以
what does that mean well if I could
那是什么意思呢？如果我能
double the profit of the business from
企业利润翻倍
30,000 to 60,000 could I ask for half of
3万到6万，我能要一半吗？
the business bu maybe or maybe you ask
生意或许是，或许是你问的
for 20% to double it and it's a
20% 就能翻倍，而且是
no-brainer offer for them you're already
对他们来说，这简直是轻而易举的提议，你已经……
making $30,000 a year I'm not going to
年收入3万美元，我不会……
touch that $ 30,000 but if I double it
动用那3万美元，但如果我把它翻倍……
can I have 15 20% of the business if I
如果我……我可以拥有公司15%到20%的股份吗？
don't double it I get nothing don't
别翻倍，我什么也得不到，别
worry about it great trade how do you
别担心，这笔交易很棒，你怎么做？
figure out if it's a good product cuz I
弄清楚这产品好不好，因为我
I've just finished rapping Dragon's Den
我刚唱完《龙穴》
which is like Shark Tank over here yeah
这就像这边的《创智赢家》节目一样，没错。
and the single most frequently expressed
以及最常表达的单一
reason why someone's business hasn't
某人的生意为何没有成功的原因
taken off yet when they're pitching to
当他们向……投球时，还没有起飞
me in Dragon's Den is we just need some
我在《龙穴》节目中说，我们只需要一些
marketing help it's so you know and I'm
营销帮助，这样你就知道了，我是
the the dragon that's most know
最知名的龙
associated with marketing so often
与营销相关的诸多方面
that's directed towards me they're
那是针对我的，他们是
thinking that I can come in and just
我以为我可以进来然后就
press the button that I have in my
按下我身上的按钮
backpack and things going to pop what do
背包和东西要爆炸了怎么办？
you think about that you never have a
你觉得你从来没有过
marketing or leads problem you have a
您在营销或线索开发方面遇到问题了吗？
shitty product problem and nobody wants
糟糕的产品问题，没人想要
to believe this truth but it's true
虽然难以置信，但这却是事实。
here's how you know here's how you know
这就是你知道的方法 这就是你知道的方法
if you have a shitty product or if you
如果你的产品很烂，或者如果你
have a marketing problem do you have 20
遇到营销难题？你有20个吗？
to 30% referrals or reviews to your
30% 的推荐或评论
product if you don't you have a bad
如果你没有这个产品，你就亏大了。
product and you have a leaky bucket and
产品，但你的桶漏水了。
you are trying to say Stephen please
你想说的是“斯蒂芬，请”。
bail me out from my leaky bucket ship
救我脱离这艘漏水的船
with your marketing help but what's
有了你们的营销帮助，但是……
what's the truth of the matter is and I
事情的真相是什么？
see this with our companies and small
在我们的公司和小企业中都看到了这一点
businesses all the time they're like I
企业总是这样，就像我
have a leads problem I have a leads
我遇到了销售线索问题，我有一些销售线索。
problem if I could just get more
如果我能得到更多，那就没问题了。
eyeballs my my company would grow no act
我的眼球，我的公司不会增长，不会有任何行动
like your first customer is going to be
就像你的第一个客户将会是
the only customer you will ever get get
你唯一能得到的客户就是
them to refer other people to you get
让他们把其他人介绍给你
them to write reviews where they say
让他们写评论，他们在评论中说
nice things about your business and
贵公司的一些优点
treat the current customers like they
像对待他们一样对待现有客户
are your marketing and sales and I think
你们的市场营销和销售部门是怎样的？我认为
that is the biggest issue with startups
这是初创企业面临的最大问题。
is that they think that they just need
他们认为他们只需要
more attention because they can't
因为他们不能，所以会受到更多关注
actually see that what's happening is
实际上，我们看到正在发生的事情是
when the attention comes in it's falling
当注意力集中起来的时候，它就开始下降了。
out of the Leaky bucket and it's falling
它从漏水的桶里掉了出来，正在往下掉。
out of the Leaky bucket so fix your
从漏水的桶里出来，然后修好你的
problem fix your product and you'll fix
解决问题，修复你的产品，你就能解决问题。
your sales um so that would be the first
你的销售额，嗯，那将是第一个。
thing I would ask them I would say
我会问他们什么？我会说
what's your referral rate what's your
你的推荐率是多少？
review rate and then they're going to go
审核率，然后他们就会走
like I don't know and you need to find
我不知道，你需要找到答案。
that answer and if they say well
那个答案，如果他们说好
actually for every person that we that
事实上，对于我们每个人来说，
buys
购买
one like what would be a perfect example
比如，一个完美的例子是什么？
remember that like squeegee face uh
记住，就像刮水器一样的脸
product Mr Clean is that what that's
Mr. Clean 这个产品就是它吗？
called Scrub Daddy Scrub Daddy there we
我们叫 Scrub Daddy Scrub Daddy
go okay that's like a Dragon's Den but
好吧，那就像《龙穴》节目一样，但是
Shark Tank product okay so Scrub Daddy
《创智赢家》产品，好吧，Scrub Daddy
Scrub Daddy was perfect why it's a
Scrub Daddy 完美地诠释了它为何如此受欢迎
scaring pad for anybody that doesn't
吓唬那些不了解的人
know like a little scaring pad to wash
知道它就像一块小小的疤痕垫，可以用来清洗。
dishes with yeah like a sponge yeah
菜肴就像海绵一样，是的。
anyway so it was kind of cute looking it
总之，它看起来还挺可爱的。
looked different and it really worked
看起来不一样，而且确实有效。
and so what would happen with Scrub
那么，Scrub会发生什么呢？
Daddy well Scrub Daddy they would you
爸爸，好吧，爸爸，他们会……
would buy it and then you would use it
你会买它，然后你会用它。
it would work great and so you would
它会非常有效，你也会如此。
tell your friends you're like there's
告诉你的朋友你就像……
this new thing it never gets dirty it
这个新东西永远不会变脏。
doesn't have any issues with like all
对一切都没有任何问题
that gross stuff that gets on a sponge
海绵上那些恶心的东西
you can squeeze it all the way out it
你可以把它完全挤出来。
doesn't scratch in your dishes you
不会刮伤你的餐具
should totally buy this thing and so you
绝对应该买这个东西，所以你
instantly know you have a good product
立即知道你拥有的是一款好产品
because other people are sharing it and
因为其他人也在分享它
those are are those are network Loops
这些是网络环路
it's very much like um you know chth
这很像，你知道的，chth
poopa right billionaire from one idea
一个想法就让亿万富翁变成了噗噗
one idea and every business has this
一个想法，每个企业都有。
idea and nobody looks for it and the
这个想法，但没人去找它。
idea at Facebook was called seven
Facebook 的一个想法被称为“七”。
friends in 10 days they could tell with
朋友们10天后就能分辨出来。
99% predictive certainty that if you
99% 的预测确定性，如果你
came to Facebook and you interacted with
你来到了 Facebook，并与他人互动
or brought seven friends in 10 days you
或者在10天内带了7个朋友来你
would stay at Facebook forever
会永远留在Facebook
so all they had to do was make sure that
所以他们所要做的就是确保
when they came to your city or School
当他们来到你的城市或学校时
you had density enough where you had
你的密度足够大，以至于你
seven friends in 10 days and if you got
10天内结识7位朋友，如果你能做到
those seven friends on your phone you're
你手机里那七个朋友
like woo I'm going to stay what is that
哇，我要留下来，那是什么？
in your
你的
business I have about 50 different
我经营着大约50家不同的企业。
companies in my portfolio at flight
我投资组合中的公司在航班上
group now some of which I've invested in
现在这个集团里，有些我已经投资了。
and some of which I've co-founded or
其中一些是我共同创立的，或者
founded myself one thing I've noticed is
我发现自己注意到的一件事是
that most companies don't put enough
大多数公司投入不足。
effort into their hiring process in my
我努力参与他们的招聘流程。
mind the first and most critical thing
注意第一件也是最关键的事情
in business is assembling your group of
在商业中，就是组建你的团队
people because the definition of the
人们因为定义
word company is group of people and
“公司”一词指的是一群人。
throughout all of my companies whenever
在我所有的公司里，每当
I'm looking to hire someone my first
我正在寻找我的第一个员工。
Port of Call is LinkedIn jobs who I'm
Port of Call 是 LinkedIn 上的招聘信息，我就是其中之一。
happy to say are also a sponsor of this
很高兴地告诉大家，我们也是这项活动的赞助商。
podcast they've helped us Source
播客他们帮了我们很大的忙。来源
professionals who we truly can't find
我们实在找不到的专业人士
anywhere else even those who aren't
在其他任何地方，即使是那些不……的人
actively searching for a new job but who
积极寻找新工作，但谁
might be open to a perfect role in fact
事实上，他或许乐于接受一个完美的角色。
over 70% of LinkedIn users don't visit
超过 70% 的 LinkedIn 用户不访问
other leading job sites so if you're not
其他领先的求职网站，所以如果你不是
looking on LinkedIn
在领英上寻找
you're probably looking in the wrong
你可能找错地方了。
place so today I'm giving the dire of
所以今天我要给出明确的答复
the CEO Community a free LinkedIn job
CEO社区提供免费的LinkedIn工作机会
post head to linkedin.com
帖子请发布到 linkedin.com
doac now and let me know how you get on
现在就去做，然后告诉我结果如何。
terms and conditions apply I am a big
适用条款和条件。我是一个大
Manchester United fan and I travel all
我是曼联球迷，经常旅行。
over the world one of the big lifes
放眼全球，人生大事之一
savers for me as someone that never
对我来说，储蓄者就像一个从不……的人
misses a game ever regardless of where I
无论我在哪里，我都会错过一场比赛。
am in the world is nordvpn because
我身处的世界就是NordVPN，因为
nordvpn allows me to watch the game in
NordVPN让我能够观看比赛。
territories and in countries where it's
在某些地区和国家，它是
often not available for a variety of
通常不适用于多种情况
different reasons but it's not just
原因各不相同，但这不仅仅是
about football it's websites movies that
关于足球的网站和电影
I can access and it helps me navigate
我可以访问它，它能帮助我浏览网页。
those geographical blockers and that's
那些地理障碍，就是这样。
why nordvpn are both a sponsor of this
为什么 NordVPN 既是这家公司的赞助商，又是其他公司？
podcast but a lifesaver for me and it
播客对我来说简直是救命稻草。
costs the same as a cup of coffee per
价格和一杯咖啡一样
month and not just that when I'm
一个月，而且不仅仅是当我……的时候
accessing Wi-Fi networks around the
访问周围的Wi-Fi网络
world it gives me a lot of security
这个世界给了我很多安全感。
which is something that I think we don't
而我认为我们并不具备这种能力。
think about enough if you want to check
想清楚再决定是否要检查
out nordvpn for a limited time only head
限时优惠，仅限头部
to
到
nordvpn.com
nordvpn.com
doac and you can access our exclusive
doac，您可以访问我们的独家内容。
deal which gives the DI of listeners a
这项交易赋予了听众的直接投资
huge discount plus four extra months
巨额折扣，外加四个月免费试用
when you sign up to a 2-year Plan and
当你注册两年计划时
there's no risk with nord's 30-day money
Nord 的 30 天资金计划没有任何风险。
back guarantee so give it a try that's
有退款保证，所以不妨一试。
nordvpn.com
nordvpn.com
doac or check out the episode
观看视频或收听本集
description link below what you're
描述链接在下方，你是什么
speaking to there is this idea of
与人交谈时，会产生这样一种想法
retention so a great product is
保持率，所以一款优秀的产品是
retentive and if it retains its customer
留住客户，以及如果它能留住客户。
then the customer is going to sit around
然后顾客就会闲坐着。
and evangelize and bring other people
并传福音，带领其他人。
with them like a like they're throwing
和他们在一起就像在扔东西一样
fishing rods into their Network and the
钓鱼竿进入他们的网络和
example you gave of choth who was one of
你举的例子是克托斯，他是其中之一。
the early Executives at Facebook is this
Facebook早期的几位高管是这样的。
the same thing if you bring seven people
如果你带七个人来，情况也一样。
with you you're going to stick around
有你在，你就会一直待在这里。
for the party stick around for the party
参加派对的话，请留下来参加派对。
long enough these Network effects build
足够长的时间，这些网络效应就会形成
now chth here so that you know and when
现在在这里，这样你就知道什么时候了。
these Network effects get bigger
这些网络效应会越来越大
retention increases and and this is why
留存率提高，这就是原因
it's so important to focus on the
专注于这一点非常重要
product right because we're talking
产品对，因为我们正在谈论它。
about this term LTV lifetime value we're
关于LTV（终身价值）这个术语，我们……
talking about if we make a really good
讨论一下如果我们能做出一个非常好的
thing people are going to tell their
人们会告诉他们的
friends they're going to continue to use
他们会继续使用的朋友
it and then they're going to Market it
然后他们就要把它推向市场。
for me but most people will focus on
对我来说，但大多数人会专注于
just trying to get a Tik Tok video to go
只是想让一个TikTok视频上传
viral versus making something truly
病毒式传播与真正创造事物之间的区别
great elon's an example isn't he of that
伟大的埃隆就是个例子，不是吗？
oh yeah it's much harder to um obsess on
哦，是的，要沉迷其中就难多了。
making a great product because it's
打造一款优秀的产品，因为它……
slower you know you're like well I have
慢点说，你知道，你会想，嗯，我有
one person and they're only going to you
只有一个人，而且他们只会来找你。
know re refer three of a person you know
知道并推荐你认识的某个人
I can't grow fast enough with that and
我长得不够快，
so what do we do we top a funnel top a
所以我们该怎么做？我们在漏斗顶部加一个漏斗顶部
funnel top a funnel let's talk about it
漏斗顶部，我们来聊聊它
let's talk about it let's talk about it
我们来谈谈吧，我们来谈谈吧。
but the problem is you can either spend
但问题在于，你可以选择花费
a bunch of time creating an incredible
花费大量时间创造了一个令人难以置信的
product once or you can spend the rest
一次购买，或者您可以花掉剩余的钱
of your life marketing and doing sales
你的生活营销和销售
so it's again it kind of goes back to
所以，一切又回到了原点。
this idea if you want to win and be
如果你想赢，并且成为……这个想法
successful in life upfront pain always
人生成功之道在于克服前期的痛苦
leads to long-term gain and people do
带来长期收益，人们也确实如此。
not want to hurt upfront so they hurt
他们不想一开始就伤害别人，所以他们就伤害了别人。
for the rest of their life I think
我认为，他们将终生如此。
that's the same thing with products they
他们的产品也是如此。
try and skip a step they skip a step and
他们试图跳过一个步骤，结果就跳过了一个步骤。
and and by the way I'm guilty of it too
顺便说一句，我也犯过同样的错误。
like we have one company right now where
比如我们现在就有一家公司，
our referral rate is based basically
我们的推荐率基本上是基于
zero and we slamming these ad dollars in
零，而我们却把这些广告费砸进了广告行业。
and all this marketing budget and I I
所有这些营销预算，还有我
looked at myself the other day and was
前几天我照​​镜子的时候……
like Cody you're an idiot you're you're
就像科迪一样，你是个白痴，你真是个白痴。
doing the thing that you tell other
做你告诉别人的那件事
people not to do which is we have to fix
人们不应该这样做，我们必须纠正这一点。
referrals and reviews why because they
为什么推荐和评价？因为它们
fix there's three Rs referrals reviews
修复了三个R推荐评论
and retention MH if your business
以及企业留存率 MH
doesn't have the three Rs you will spend
不具备你将花费的三项基本要素（3R）。
your life marketing and marketing is
你的生活营销和营销是
actually quite hard and
实际上相当难，
expensive and then you also have
价格昂贵，而且你还有
people that you don't even realize you
你甚至都没意识到的人
think that they're uh they're proponents
认为他们是……呃，他们是支持者
of your brand you know they pay you
你知道，你的品牌会付钱给你。
every single month for a service or a
每个月都要支付服务费或
product but they're actually detractors
产品，但他们实际上是批评者
they just haven't found a better a
他们只是还没找到更好的……
better product and so that's what often
更好的产品，所以通常情况下是这样。
happens to business you're like no no no
如果生意上发生这种事，你会说“不不不”。
these people love us no they don't have
这些人爱我们，不，他们没有。
they referred anybody to you have they
他们把任何人都介绍给了你，他们
left you a positive review that's the
我给你留了个好评，就是这样。
only way you know it's super interesting
只有这样你才能知道它超级有趣。
because there's a bit of a paradox in
因为这里存在一些悖论
what we're saying here cuz on one hand
我们在这里说的意思是，一方面……
we were talking about intensity and urg
我们当时在讨论强度和冲动
going fast and these kind of people that
速度很快，而且是这种人
just kind of you know shortened
就是那种你知道的，缩短版
deadlines and stuff like that but then
截止日期之类的，但是
on the other hand we're saying that you
另一方面，我们想说的是，你
need to go slow and build the thing
需要慢慢来，一步一步地把事情做好。
right because the slow way is the only
没错，因为慢的方法是唯一的方法
way in the long term um I was hugely
从长远来看，嗯，我非常
inspired by the story of Tesla and Elon
灵感源自特斯拉和埃隆的故事
Musk for this very reason because if you
正是出于这个原因，马斯克才会这么做，因为如果你
look at their stock price there's about
看看他们的股价，大约有
I don't know six seven eight maybe 10
我不知道，六七八，也许是十
years where they're completely flat um
那些年，它们完全平坦……
they elon's not you know made a
他们埃隆不是你知道的，他做了一个
significant amount of money from it and
从中可以获得大量资金
he's just going through absolute pain
他现在正承受着巨大的痛苦。
and then all of a sudden the company
然后突然之间，公司
just explodes and actually the most
突然爆炸，而且实际上是最
inspiring thing for me having been a
对我来说，这是一件鼓舞人心的事，因为我曾经是
person who built a business that scaled
打造了一家规模化企业的人
hundreds of millions of dollars in
数亿美元
Revenue but was really built on
收入，但实际上是建立在……之上的
unsustainable
不可持续
foundations I I know what Elon did in
我知道埃隆在基金会里做了什么
that 10 years when that stock price was
那十年间，该股票的价格是
completely flat he laid every
他完全平躺着
foundational brick of Tesla perfectly Y
特斯拉完美 Y 的基础砖
and he was doing it basically in silence
他基本上是默默地完成这一切的。
and it's so tempting in business I think
我觉得这在商业领域非常诱人。
to take shortcuts when you're laying
躺下时走捷径
those sort of initial like building a
那些最初的建设就像……
house like you're putting the
房子就像你正在放置的
foundations down but he said you know
地基倒塌了，但他却说你知道
we're going to completely make a new
我们将彻底创建一个新的
battery we're going to build the entire
我们将建造整个电池
supercharging network um so that all of
超级充电网络，嗯，这样所有的
our cars can go to 15,000 charging
我们的汽车可以充电至 15,000 公里。
locations around the country we're going
我们将前往全国各地。
to build a brand new Factory in fact
事实上，要建造一座全新的工厂。
we're going to build every single piece
我们将建造每一个部件
of this car and it's going to take 10
这辆车需要10个小时才能修好。
years but but the patience I think is is
多年来，但我认为耐心是
really the the thing that leads to the
真正导致这种情况的事情
perfection in the long term and it's a
从长远来看，这是完美，而且
big thesis that I've been playing with a
我一直在研究的一个大论点
lot recently because there's a part of
最近很多，因为其中一部分是
my heart that just wants everything to
我的心只想一切都
happen quick but as I've gotten older I
事情发生得很快，但随着我年龄的增长，我
start to think that um slowing down in
开始觉得，嗯，速度慢了下来
big thing in the big things like the the
大事中的大事，比如……
laying the bricks is actually the most
砌砖实际上是最
important thing this is I'm throwing
重要的是，我正在扔
this at you as just a point to see if
这只是一个观察点，看看是否
that it resonates in any way well I
它以某种方式引起了共鸣，我
think you're right the thing that I
我觉得你说得对，我
think is the problem is when you're
我认为问题在于当你……
young and
年轻而
starting we're usually you're not as
一开始我们通常你不会像
smart as Elon like you would if if you
像埃隆一样聪明，就像你一样，如果你
gave a 20s something 10 years to build
让一个二十多岁的人花了十年时间建造
what Elon has built in silence yeah they
埃隆默默打造的东西，是的，他们
wouldn't know what to build they
他们不知道该建造什么。
wouldn't know what a strong Foundation
不知道什么是坚实的基础
looks like so I always optimize for
看起来是这样，我总是会优化
urgency upfront because you have to have
一开始就应该有紧迫感，因为你必须要有
all these shots on goals to realize oh
所有这些射门都是为了实现目标，哦
whoops wrong goal wrong goal wrong goal
哎呀，进球失误，进球失误，进球失误
wrong goal and then I do think you get
目标错误，然后我认为你会得到
to a certain level where then you become
达到一定程度后，你就会变成
Warren Buffett Elon Musk where you know
沃伦·巴菲特和埃隆·马斯克，你知道的。
Warren Buffett says once in a lifetime
沃伦·巴菲特说，一生只有一次
opportunities come around about twice a
机会大约每两周出现两次。
year and so you basically do nothing
一年下来，你基本上什么也不做。
else except those two each year the
除了每年那两年之外，其他时间
problem is he can recognize that because
问题在于他能意识到这一点，因为
he had Decades of shot on goal shot on
他几十年来一直在射门得分。
goal shot
射门得分
so I think it's this it's this balance
所以我认为关键在于这种平衡。
of yes once you understand what good or
是的，一旦你理解了什么是好的或
great looks like it is your moral
看起来很棒，这很符合你的道德观
imperative to work as fast as possible
必须尽快完成
towards good or great but in the
朝着好或伟大的方向发展，但在
beginning since you don't know just do
从你不知道开始就去做吧
more faster it's interesting because the
速度越快，就越有趣，因为
thing I was thinking about when I passed
我经过时一直在想的事情
the floor to you there was I should have
你应该站在你面前的地板上
probably said what I'm actually
可能说出了我真正想说的话
referring to here much of it is actually
这里所指的大部分实际上是
hiring because you know when I'm
招聘是因为你知道我什么时候
starting a new company now I could
现在我可以创办一家新公司
because we you know we get tens of
因为你知道，我们能得到几十个
thousands of applications coming into
数千份申请涌入
the inbox I could resource that company
我可以在收件箱里找到那家公司的资源
with people in two weeks yeah but in
两周后和大家见面，是的，但是
fact one of the biggest pain points
事实上，这是最大的痛点之一。
across all of my businesses is we hire
我的所有业务都包括招聘
so agonizingly slow yeah same because we
慢得令人抓狂，是啊，一样，因为我们
know that that's when we talk about
要知道，那时我们就会谈论……
laying the fat foundational bricks of a
为一座建筑打下坚实的基础。
good of a good company it's all about
一家好公司的好处就在于此。
those initial hires yeah it's it's so
那些最初的招聘人员，是的，就是这样
true I mean every business is a people
没错，我的意思是，每个企业都是由人组成的。
business before it's a product business
在成为产品企业之前，它首先是一家企业。
before it's a profit business and and um
在它成为一家盈利企业之前，嗯……
the beautiful part about that is if you
这件事的美妙之处在于，如果你
don't have a business right now and
目前没有自己的生意，
you're listening to all this you should
你在听这些，你应该听。
feel very empowered like exceptional
感觉自己充满力量，像个杰出人物。
people are in such high demand and the
人口需求量非常大，
the sky is the limit on what you can
你能做到的事情，天空才是极限。
make both as your own owner or working
无论是作为自己的所有者还是员工，都可以制作。
for other people until you become your
为了别人，直到你成为你自己
own own owner if you're great and great
如果你很棒，就拥有自己的主人
is largely just I say I'm going to do a
基本上就是我说我要去做一件事
thing I do the thing
我做的事
repeat and if the bar is that low um man
重复一遍，如果标准杆那么低……嗯……
I think there's way more opportunity
我认为机会远不止这些。
than anybody realizes which maybe gets
比任何人意识到的都要多，这或许会得到
back to what you said before which is
回到你之前说的那件事……
this ability to bend the world that I
这种改变世界的能力，我
think both you and I see is really
我想你我都明白这一点
because we see how easy it is it's like
因为我们看到它有多么容易，就像
like have you ever seen
你见过这样的吗？
um have you seen like how um people will
嗯，你有没有看到人们会怎么做？
take one of those iron rods you know
拿一根你知道的铁棍。
really strong iron rod and you heat it
非常结实的铁棒，加热它
up and it just like [__] it just bends
向上，就像宾克一样，它就弯了。
immed
立即
but if you were going to try to brute
但如果你打算用蛮力解决问题
force it it never would but once you see
强行去做永远不会成功，但一旦你明白了
them heated up and then bend easy you go
加热后，轻轻弯曲即可。
oh well I'm never going to try to brute
哦，我永远不会尝试用蛮力。
force that again because look how easy
再强制执行一次，因为你看这有多容易
that is if you just heat it up M and I
也就是说，如果你只是加热它的话，M和我
think that's part of the hack of life is
我认为这就是生活技巧的一部分。
just figuring out heat and time and what
只是在弄清楚温度、时间和什么
those two ingredients are that's that's
这两种成分就是……
really I always think about the bloody
我真的总是想到那该死的
like um what do you call it that big
比如，嗯，这么大的东西该怎么称呼呢？
hole in the ground you have it the Grand
地上挖了个洞，你就有了它，大
Canyon
峡谷
yeah you always think about the big it's
是啊，你总是会想到大事。
just such a nice anal cuz I'm like how
真是太爽了，我当时就想：
did that get there well actually it was
那东西真的到了吗？实际上，它到了。
just water trickling through there for a
只有水从那里缓缓流过。
long period of time you didn't need to
很长一段时间你都不需要
brute force it it wasn't like a meteor
蛮力摧毁它，它不像流星那样。
or anoid hit the earth it was just
或者说，外星人撞击地球，那只是
consistency of a very gentle force over
持续施加非常轻柔的力
a long period of time and that's really
很长一段时间，这真的
how all rivers and how Earth is
所有河流是如何形成的，地球又是如何形成的
literally carved um it's interesting
简直是雕刻出来的，嗯，挺有意思的。
because I was also thinking as you were
因为我当时的想法和你一样。
speaking about this idea that at all
谈到这个想法，
times throughout your 20s and your 30s
在你20多岁和30多岁的那些日子里
you are actually without knowing it
你其实是在不知不觉中这么做的。
interviewing and being interviewed by
面试和被面试
your former your future potential
你过去的能力，你未来的潜力
business partners oh yeah you I mean
商业伙伴？哦，对，就是你。
because I was 18 years old and I went to
因为我当时18岁，我去了
San FR no I was 19 19 years old when I
San FR 不，我当时19岁。
went to San Francisco yeah and funnily
去了旧金山，是啊，真有意思。
enough I just sent a cold email to a
够了，我刚刚给一个……发了一封陌生邮件
billionaire I said I just saw you bought
我说，亿万富翁，我刚才看到你买了
a company it was a funny email that said
一家公司发来一封很有趣的邮件，内容是：
here are five reasons why girls call me
以下是女生给我打电话的五个原因
back in bars and here's five reasons why
重返酒吧，原因有五：
they don't it was basically my CV better
他们不，这基本上就是我的简历更好。
in that format I love it and he called
我喜欢这种形式，他打电话来了
me within 24 hours when I was in the UK
我当时在英国，24小时内就联系了我。
I was like hey love this um I'm going to
我当时就想，嘿，我喜欢这个，嗯，我要……
set you a challenge how would you get us
给你出个难题，你会怎么赢得我们？
to 10 million users I thought fine made
我觉得对1000万用户来说已经很不错了。
a deck sent it to this is how I'd get
一副牌把它寄给了我，这就是我收到它的方式。
this new company you've bought to 10
你收购的这家新公司已经达到10
million users he goes cool I'm gonna
百万用户，他很酷，我要
give you $10,000 a month I was in the UK
我当时在英国，每月给你1万美元。
just sat in my parents house I'm gonna
我就坐在父母家，我要
give you $10,000 a month I'm gonna fly
给我每月一万美元，我就飞走。
you out to San Francisco and you're
你去了旧金山，然后你
going to help us build this company and
他会帮助我们建立这家公司，并且
while I was there I was around some
我在那里的时候，周围有一些
really really smart people one of those
非常非常聪明的人，其中之一
very smart people 10 years later when I
十年后，当我还是个聪明人的时候，我发现我
had a new idea he was the first person I
他有了个新想法，他是第一个……
hit up through his Instagram DM through
通过他的Instagram私信联系了他
his Twitter DMS hadn't spoke to him for
他的推特私信已经很久没跟他联系了。
10 years turns out he had bought a $50
十年后，他发现自己买了一个价值 50 美元的……
billion company that had ipoed and he
那家十亿美元的公司已经上市，而他
was the CTO and I said hey there's this
当时他是首席技术官，我说，嘿，这里有这个
new thing called the blockchain I'm
我指的是一种叫做区块链的新东西。
really interested in it do you want to
我对这个很感兴趣，你想……
build a company with me in it and he
他和我一起创办了一家公司，他
goes yeah cool and I and I just I just
是啊，酷，我，我只是，我只是
reflected on the fact
反思了这一事实
that throughout my
在我整个过程中
20s there are so many people that I met
二十多岁的时候，我遇到了很多人。
that in my 30s I then leveraged so what
30多岁的时候，我利用了……所以呢？
I was actually doing is I was being
我当时其实是在做我当时正在做的事情。
interviewed by them without knowing it
在不知情的情况下接受了他们的采访
you know what I mean because a thousand
你知道我的意思，因为一千
per actually I won't say his name but uh
其实我不会说出他的名字，但是……
we have a mutual friend that knew you
我们有一个共同的朋友认识你。
from back in the day then and what is
从过去到现在，这是什么？
fascinating to me is watching the two of
让我着迷的是观察他们两人
you cuz you're slightly younger than him
因为你比他小一点。
I believe and um and he's been
我相信，嗯，他一直
successful but your success is like way
成功，但你的成功就像这样
more and so when I was looking at the
而且，当我看着……的时候
two of you and thinking what was the
你们两个在想，那是什么？
difference between the two he's also
两者的区别在于他也是
smart also driven um in the same
智能也驱动着嗯，同样
ecosystem had the same network what was
生态系统拥有相同的网络，那是什么？
the difference between 20-year-old
20岁和20岁之间的区别
Steven and 20-year-old X and I think
史蒂文和20岁的X，还有我认为
part of the difference is grit and time
部分区别在于毅力和时间。
and consistency you chose a few things
以及你选择的那些东西的一致性。
you stuck with them for quite a while as
你和他们待了相当长一段时间。
you have with this podast I mean how
你和这个播客有什么关系？我的意思是，如何
many podcast episodes have you done now
你现在已经做了很多期播客节目了。
I have to look at Che
我得看看切·格瓦拉。
400 3 yeah the average podcast is like
400 3 是的，平均播客就像
what 11 episodes or something like that
大概11集左右吧？
and then they then they cancel yeah and
然后他们就取消了，是的。
then you also chose bigger games like
然后你也选择了像这样的大型游戏
bigger and bigger and bigger as you
随着你越来越大，越来越大，越来越大。
scaled and this other guy that I know
缩放，还有我认识的另一个人
that I think really highly of too just
我也非常欣赏这一点。
like didn't want to work that hard for
好像不想那么努力工作
that long on that big of things and so I
那段时间我一直在思考那些大事，所以我
think if you can just have time
想想你是否能抽出点时间
consistency grit and then try to solve
保持颗粒状，然后尝试解决
bigger problems because they pay better
更大的问题，因为他们的薪酬更高
you know you're probably worth 100x of
你知道你的价值可能高达100倍吗？
that guy net worth wise because of those
就净资产而言，那家伙是因为那些原因。
four things so interesting you know one
你知道，有四件非常有趣的事情
of the things I've I've thought a lot
我思考过很多事情
about over the last couple of years is
大约在过去几年里是
that I basically have one skill set like
我基本上只有一项技能，比如
I have a very narrow skill set and I
我的技能非常狭窄，而且
essentially applied it to different
基本上将其应用于不同的
markets in my life and I think we all
市场在我生活中扮演着重要的角色，我想我们所有人都是如此。
kind of need to start thinking through
需要开始认真思考一下了。
this lens let me make this make really
这支镜头让我能够真正做到这一点。
specific sense so my skill set at the
特定感官，所以我的技能组合
start of my career my main skill set was
我职业生涯初期我的主要技能是
in social media at the very start of my
在我的社交媒体生涯之初，我就开始涉足这个领域。
career now what can you do with that
现在你的职业生涯可以做什么？
skill set you can sell dresses for
具备可以卖裙子的技能
boohoo.com which I did and the impact of
boohoo.com，我试过了，以及它的影响
me doing that for boohoo.com their sales
我这样做是为了boohoo.com的销售。
increasing is X right not a huge amount
X 增加的幅度并不大。
but also there's a lot of people that
但也有很多人
have that skill set of social media so
具备社交媒体方面的技能
that drives down my potential to charge
这降低了我充电的潜力。
High numbers when I was 26 or 27 years
我26、27岁的时候数字很高
old I moved that same skill set to of
我把同样的技能转移到了……
social media same skill set I moved it
社交媒体拥有相同的技能，我把它转移了过来。
to a different Market
进入不同的市场
which was companies before their IPO now
这些公司在首次公开募股（IPO）之前就已经存在了。
if a com and this was during that sort
如果这是一个 com，并且这是在那段时间发生的
of Reddit um Wall Street bets moment
Reddit 和华尔街的赌注时刻
where like Reddit took down a a massive
就像Reddit关闭了一个大型网站一样。
hedge fund in America and they pumped
美国的对冲基金，他们大量注资。
GameStop I thought to myself I have this
GameStop 我心想，我也有这个
skill set um companies before their IPO
技能组合 um 公司在首次公开募股 (IPO) 之前
now really care about retail investors
现在真的非常关心散户投资者了
the average person liking their stock so
普通人喜欢他们的股票
if I go and use that same social media
如果我使用同样的社交媒体
Skillet that I used to sell fizzy drinks
我以前用来卖汽水的平底锅
and um dresses with companies that are
以及与这些公司合作的连衣裙
in the biotech industry they know
在生物技术行业，他们知道
nothing about social media they think
他们对社交媒体一无所知
it's witchcraft right before they IPO
这是他们在IPO前夕搞的巫术。
what would my returns look like and
我的收益会是多少？
honestly the same skill set just move to
说实话，同样的技能，只是换了工作而已。
a different industry where it's scarce
在另一个稀缺的行业
and the person paying me stands to make
付钱给我的人可能会获得收益
potentially one to two billion if their
如果他们……的话，可能达到10亿到20亿。
IPO is successful delivers a thousand
IPO成功带来一千
times the value of selling the dresses
裙子售价的倍数
for boohoo.com and I just think people
对于 boohoo.com 来说，我只是觉得人们
often they're thinking I need a
他们常常认为我需要一个
promotion I need whatever much of the
我需要尽可能多的晋升机会
time I'm like just move your skill set
当时我就想，不如你赶紧提升一下你的技能吧。
to a better Market where it's scarce the
到一个更好的市场，那里这种商品稀缺。
person that's paying you stands to make
付钱给你的人可能会赚到钱
more I don't you know I mean it's like a
我不知道，你知道，我的意思是，这就像……
different way to think about career yeah
换个角度思考职业生涯，是的。
and it's it's I think it's so brilliant
我觉得这真是太棒了
because it's a little bit asymmetric
因为它有点不对称
it's like hard to put your fingers
就像很难把手指放进去一样
around it what people like what people
围绕着它，人们喜欢什么，人们
like that will never make you rich is
那样做永远不会让你致富。
this here's steps one through four to
这是步骤一到四。
get into real estate and if you do this
进入房地产行业，如果你这样做……
now you too will be a millionaire L
现在你也将成为百万富翁了！
you're never going to get rich that way
你那样永远也发不了财。
the way that you get rich is actually
你致富的方式实际上是
putting together multiple ideas that
将多个想法结合起来
don't seem like go together and that
看起来似乎并不相干，而且
cross-pollination is what gives you
异花授粉就是你获得这些能力的原因。
outsized returns you're like social
超额回报，你就像社交达人
media biotech IPO what and so when you
媒体生物科技IPO是什么，所以当你
have that weird
有那种怪异
cross-pollination that's where massive
异花授粉，这就是大规模繁殖的根源。
growth happens and I think you know it
成长是必然的，我想你也明白这一点。
was the same with me I was like I
我当时也是一样，就像……
remember with my CEO at the time when I
记得当时我和我的CEO在一起的时候……
I wanted I I was making a lot of money
我想要我当时赚了很多钱
let's say I was making seven figures a
假设我年收入达到七位数
year working for somebody else I was
我为别人工作了一年。
actually happy I would have stayed there
其实我很庆幸自己当时留了下来。
for probably ever at this uh investment
可能永远都是这样，呃，投资
firm but I saw the future of social
但我看到了社交的未来
media and newsletters in particular I
媒体和新闻简报，尤其是我
was like why am I going why am I on the
我当时想，我为什么要来？我为什么要来？
road every single day doing steak
每天都在路上做牛排
dinners trying to sell pensions and
试图推销养老金的晚宴和
Sovereign wealth funds or investment
主权财富基金或投资
vehicles I could be doing this all with
我可以用这些车辆来完成这一切
the internet like we don't need to be
互联网就像我们不需要的那样
meeting in person anywhere to the degree
在任何地方进行面对面会谈的程度
that we are and so I went and told the
我们是这样的，所以我去告诉了他们
CEO of my company that and he was
我公司的首席执行官，他当时
basically like if you want to row left
基本上就像你想向左划船一样。
and I want to roll right you need a new
我想继续前进，你需要一个新的
boat and I was like okay fine so I
船，然后我就想，好吧，就这样吧
couldn't convince him and so he gave me
我没能说服他，所以他就给了我
his Blessing and said like go do it
他祝福了我，然后说，去做吧。
somewhere else cuz we're not doing it
去别的地方吧，因为我们不打算这么做。
here and I was really mad at the time I
当时我真的很生气。
had built up a billion dollar business
已经建立起一家价值十亿美元的企业
for this guy in Latin America where a
对于这位身处拉丁美洲的人来说……
business didn't exist like three years
三年前公司就不存在了。
before four years before and um and so I
四年前，嗯，所以……
was mad I'm like I am your best
我当时很生气，因为我是你最好的。
International you know sales force I was
国际销售团队，你知道，我曾经是。
total victim mindset about it I was like
我当时完全抱着受害者心态。
it's cuz I'm a woman you know all these
因为我是个女人，你知道的，所有这些
dudes they don't get it I was I was mad
伙计们，他们根本不明白，我当时很生气。
so I left and he did me a huge favor by
所以我离开了，他帮了我一个大忙。
pushing me out actually because then I
实际上，我被排挤是因为那样我
went and said you know what
然后他说，你知道吗？
newsletters plus private Equity plus
简讯 + 私募股权 +
social media plus laundromats and car
社交媒体加上自助洗衣店和汽车
washes I don't know but I think and
我不知道该怎么洗，但我认为……
together they now are responsible for us
他们现在共同对我们负有责任。
having a business that has 26 businesses
拥有一家旗下有26家企业的公司
in it businesses that do tens of
在从事数十项业务的IT企业中
millions of dollars in Revenue some of
数百万美元的收入
the Venture ones do hundreds of millions
风险投资公司赚了数亿美元。
of dollars in revenue and we don't even
数美元的收入，我们甚至都没有
have to have third party investors it's
必须有第三方投资者。
a lot of our own money because we've
我们投入了很多自己的钱，因为我们……
bought profitable businesses using using
利用收购盈利企业
totally unfair deals because of our
由于我们的种种原因，这些交易完全不公平。
social media presence and so you've
社交媒体影响力，所以你拥有
looked back in Connect dots there right
回头看了看连接点，对吧？
so someone that's you know at the start
所以，一开始你认识的那个人
yeah how do they get enough dots to
是啊，他们怎么才能获得足够的点数呢？
connect like what's the strategy to even
联系，比如，策略是什么？
be able to look back someday and connect
将来有一天能够回首往事并建立联系
these interesting to think about if I
这些都是值得思考的问题，如果我
wanted right now to figure out how could
我现在就想弄清楚该怎么做
I find my cross-pollination of ideas I'd
我发现我的想法相互碰撞，最终会碰撞出火花。
need three things I need a whiteboard I
我需要三样东西：一块白板。
need a whiteboard pen and I need a smart
我需要一支白板笔，还需要一个智能
buddy okay and all you got I can get you
哥们儿，好吧，你有什么我都能给你弄到的。
a whiteboard pen yeah exactly well all I
白板笔，对，没错，就是我
would do is I would put it up on the
我会把它上传到……
wall okay and I would try to find my
墙还好，我会试着找到我的
smartest
最聪明的
most brainstorm open-minded friend and I
我和我的一位思想开放的朋友进行了最深入的头脑风暴。
would write down everything I think I'm
我会把我所有的想法都写下来。
good at right to do it here yeah I mean
擅长在这里做这件事，是的，我的意思是
so so let's say it's for you right now
假设现在对你来说是这样。
let me screen record so that I can see
让我录屏，这样我就可以看到
what you've done and put it on the
你做了什么，并把它放在……
screen for everyone at home to watch
屏幕上，供家中所有人观看
what a fun idea and what was the
真是个有趣的主意，那是什么呢？
question again what are we talking so
再问一遍，我们到底在说什么？
the question is if right now you want to
问题是，你现在是否想要
find where is your unfair bet that can
找出你那笔不公平赌注的所在。
make you your Millions with your skill
凭借你的技能赚取百万财富
set that nobody else in the world can
设定世界上其他人都无法做到
replicate except you here's what I need
除了你以外，其他都一样，这是我需要的
would need a whiteboard I would need a
我需要一块白板，我需要一个
pen which I would do if I was you and I
如果我是你，我也会这么做。
would need a smart friend perfect like
需要一个聪明的、完美的朋友，比如
so I've got Stephen here and at the top
所以，我这里有斯蒂芬，他排在最前面。
of the right whiteboard I would write on
如果用的是合适的白板，我会在上面写字。
this side skills oh my God you're going
这副技能，我的天哪，你太棒了！
to see my handwriting like a doctor and
像医生一样看我的字迹
on this side I would write money and I
在这边我会写钱，而且我
would start writing down all the things
会开始把所有事情都写下来。
that we're brilliant at so let's pretend
我们很擅长这个，所以就假装吧
it's it's Stephen here and we'll pretend
我是斯蒂芬，我们假装一下
like you don't have all the things that
就像你没有所有那些东西一样
you have but your core skill set you
你拥有但你的核心技能组合是
could put your hand on the screen by the
你可以把手放在屏幕上
way it makes me nervous am I am I doing
这让我很紧张，我做错了吗？
this like a boomer I am the hand a
这就像一个婴儿潮一代，我是手 a
little bit it's giving doctor so oh yeah
有点儿，医生说的，哦，是的
look at that okay so embarrassing okay
看看这个，好吧，太尴尬了，好吧
so social media right you're incredible
所以社交媒体，你真是太棒了！
at social media what else are you
除了社交媒体，你还能做什么？
probably good at well you know a lot of
可能很擅长，你知道很多……
people you've got a network what else
各位，你们已经有了人脉，还有什么呢？
well it's not just social media though
不过，这不仅仅关乎社交媒体。
it's actually a few particular things
实际上，它包含几个具体方面。
it's like YouTube and I think you're one
它就像YouTube，我觉得你就是其中之一。
of the best in the world at short form
世界短板球界的佼佼者
video right you're also one of the best
视频里你也是最棒的之一。
in the world at like a
在世界上就像一个
datadriven social media strategy
数据驱动的社交媒体策略
so you can kind of say up front hey we
所以你可以一开始就说，嘿，我们
think this is going to go viral because
我觉得这个视频会火，因为
the data says this thing over here what
数据显示，这东西是什么？
else is Sten good at he's charismatic he
除此之外，斯滕还擅长什么？他很有魅力。
can probably get people to agree to
或许能让人们同意
things just by talking to them you know
跟他们聊聊就能了解很多事情，你知道的。
what what else uh British accent you
还有什么？呃，英国口音？
know so probably you want more in-person
我知道，所以你可能更想面对面交流。
interaction because uh we've got you
互动，因为我们有你
know uh a very charismatic person what
认识一个非常有魅力的人吗？
else is Stephen really good at well he
除此之外，斯蒂芬真的很擅长什么呢？嗯……
asks a lot of questions this is my hinge
问了很多问题，这是我的铰链
profile by the way I'm totally just
顺便说一下，我的个人资料里我完全是……
going to copy and paste
准备复制粘贴
yeah goodlook funny yeah exactly so so
是啊，祝你好运，真有趣，没错，就是这样。
we'll just say these there's a lot more
我们只能说，还有很多其他的。
deal flow but let's just pretend that
交易流程，但我们姑且假装如此吧。
all you're good at is social media
你唯一擅长的就是社交媒体
you're good at getting to people which
你很擅长与人接触，
is a network you don't even have to know
这是一个你甚至无需了解的网络。
rich people just can you get to them
有钱人你根本接触不到他们
you're charismatic you're data driven
你很有魅力，你又以数据为导向。
okay great we've got all these skills
好的，太棒了，我们掌握了所有这些技能。
now how could we apply these skills to
那么，我们如何将这些技能应用到……
get the most money humanly possible and
尽可能多地获取金钱
I would do exactly what you said so how
我会完全按照你说的做，那么该怎么做呢？
do you figure out most money humanly
你算出大多数人的钱是怎么来的吗？
possible it's two things it's the how
可能有两个方面，关键在于如何操作。
would I do this it's the size of the
我会这样做吗？它的大小是……
problem it is the value of the
问题在于它的价值
solution interesting okay and so if I'm
解决方案很有意思，好的，所以如果我是
thinking about this for you if I go and
如果我去的话，我会为你考虑这件事。
I give your social media skills yeah to
我认可你的社交媒体技能。
a trade or service
贸易或服务
business I'm not going to make that much
做生意我赚不了那么多钱。
money how do I know I'm not going to
钱，我怎么知道我不会……
make that much money because I'm going
我要去赚那么多钱
to go look up online what is the average
上网查一下平均水平是多少
revenue of this business and the average
这家企业的收入和平均收入
average profit margin yeah now you
平均利润率，是的，现在你
probably didn't even think this way when
当时可能根本没想过这个问题。
you were thinking about it but you guys
你一直在考虑这件事，但是你们
look online right now what's the average
现在就上网查一下平均水平是多少
profit margin of a biotech company in
生物技术公司的利润率
average revenue let me tell you what it
平均收入，让我来告诉你它是什么。
is it's going to be like 50 to
大概会是50到
80% and it's going to be hundreds of
80%，而且将会有数百个
millions that you could potentially get
你可能会获得数百万美元
Trade Services business a lot less yeah
贸易服务业务大幅减少，是的。
and so that's where I would start skills
所以，这就是我着手提升技能的地方。
plus money really equals to three things
金钱加上其他东西，实际上等于三件事。
which is like
这就像
sector size of the
行业规模
business and profitability of the
业务和盈利能力
business and I would play this game and
我和生意人会玩这个游戏，
what that might look like is you go okay
那可能看起来就像你答应了。
I know that I have some friends in let's
我知道我在“让我们”里有一些朋友
go to the places that we know have the
去我们知道有……的地方
most cash in Silicon Valley in on Wall
硅谷大部分现金都花在了墙上
Street if they could make a lot more
如果他们能赚更多钱，那就太好了。
money if they had a lot more attention
如果他们能获得更多关注，就能赚到更多钱。
because what I'm selling as attention I
因为我出售的其实是注意力
want to get to the people who can make
想找到那些能够做出这些贡献的人
the most money with the most attention
最多的钱，最多的关注
and that means that I'm not going to go
这意味着我不会去
to Walmart
去沃尔玛
only has 6% margins I'm going to go to
只有6%的利润率，我打算去
the highest person that I could get to
我能联系到的最高级别的人
and it'd be fun if anybody's listening
如果有人在听的话，那就太有趣了。
to this right now try it like tag
现在就试试这个标签
Stephen and I in your stories on
斯蒂芬和我出现在你的故事里
Instagram of your little charts and
在Instagram上分享你的小图表
let's see and I'll give feedback anybody
看看情况，我会给任何人反馈。
that tags me in it if you're like here's
如果你喜欢，就把我标记进去吧。
the here's what I think my skill is
我认为我的技能是这样的：
here's what I think the industry is I'll
这就是我对这个行业的看法。
tell you one way or another and it can
我会告诉你某种结果，而且可以
be fun you can see other people's
很有趣，你可以看到其他人的
examples live so people for people that
例如，人们为了彼此而活。
are only listening on audio and then
只听音频
that can't see what the um this uh
看不到这是什么……呃
chicken scratch chicken scratch you've
鸡爪字 鸡爪字 你已经
just drawn on the iPad um on one hand
刚才用iPad单手画的
you have you list your skills and then
你需要列出你的技能，然后
on the second side you're listing the
第二面你列出的是
ways you believe you could make the most
你认为你能最大限度发挥最大作用的方式
money from those skills based on the
利用这些技能赚取的收入
size of the problem you'd be solving
你要解决的问题的规模
with them and the value of the solution
与他们一起以及解决方案的价值
so for example let me let me try and
例如，让我试着……
play this game with you then so okay so
那我们一起玩这个游戏吧，好吗？
I am a writer so I'm going to do my
我是一名作家，所以我打算写点什么。
skills on the left hand I'm a writer and
左手边的技能是我是一名作家，
on write I'm going to write money yep
我打算写点什么，关于钱，没错。
I'm a writer I'm really good at writing
我是一名作家，我非常擅长写作。
stuff um that's it
东西，嗯，就这些了。
and I kind of get I kind of get the
我有点明白了，我有点明白了
internet so I kind of understand
上网我大概能理解
LinkedIn blogs and stuff like that but
LinkedIn博客之类的东西，但是
that's it I'm a writer let's go with
就是这样，我是个作家，我们开始吧
what would be the worst what would be
最糟糕的情况会是什么？
the worst thing you could do if you're a
如果你是……，你能做的最糟糕的事情就是
writer to make no money to make no money
作家赚不到钱
cuz sometimes it's easier to do the
因为有时候这样做更容易
negative okay working for a local
为当地工作没问题
newspaper local I was thinking like
我当时在想，就像当地报纸那样
fantasy books like you could write like
你可以写出像你这样的奇幻小说
fiction you know really hard to make
你知道，虚构作品真的很难创作。
money in you could write for a local
你可以靠写本地文章赚钱。
newspaper that's an even worse idea so I
报纸？那真是个更糟糕的主意，所以我
like that so now you've got your your
就这样，现在你就有了你的
bottom tier right which is like 14 bucks
最下面一层，大概14美元。
an hour or
一小时或
now if you look about you could Google
现在如果你四处看看，你可以谷歌一下。
this what is the highest paying jobs for
这是哪些收入最高的工作？
writers I bet the thing you'd find on
我敢打赌，作家们会发现……
top copywriter why I got a better one oh
顶级文案撰稿人，为什么我找到了更好的？
what's a the better one do you know why
哪个更好？你知道为什么吗？
I know this because when I was in
我知道这一点，因为当我在
working in biotech we couldn't hire one
在生物技术领域工作，我们招不到一个合适的人。
which is a medical writer oh so smart
那是一位非常聪明的医学作家。
hypers specialized honestly we so a
超级专业化，老实说，我们是如此
typical copywriter when I was working in
我以前在一家公司做文案撰写工作时，典型的文案撰写人
my social media company we might pay
我的社交媒体公司可能会付钱给我们
entry level £25,000 which is probably
入门级薪资为 25,000 英镑，这大概是
about
关于
$35,000 okay a medical writer someone
35,000 美元，好的，找个医学撰稿人
that can write about the cocin compound
可以写关于可可因化合物的文章
in my psychedelics business would get
在我的迷幻药生意中，我会得到
paid
有薪酬的
$150,000 or more we just couldn't find
我们找不到15万美元或更多。
some we found loads of people that could
我们发现很多人可以
write yeah but nobody that had within
写吧，但是没有人在里面
their skill stack even though it's quite
他们的技能叠加起来，即使这相当……
easy to teach the ability to write using
很容易教授写作能力
medical words slightly medical words it
医学词汇 略微医学词汇 它
doesn't mean you need a medical degree
这并不意味着你需要医学学位。
you could probably learn how to write
你或许可以学会如何写作
become a medical writer in a month if
一个月内成为一名医学撰稿人
you really committed yourself to it so
你真的全身心投入其中了
that's true and same with Finance we go
没错，金融领域也是如此。
to the things we know so you know biotex
就我们所知，所以你知道生物胶
you know there's a there I know finance
你知道那里有金融
and I know that again it's one of the
我知道这又是其中之一
highest paying Industries so a financial
高薪行业，所以金融
writer what would that look like it
作者，那会是什么样子？
would look like somebody who knows how
看起来像个懂得如何做事的人
to write probably an investor update yes
可能要写一份投资者更新报告，是的。
right yeah yeah yeah so hugely lucrative
对，对，对，所以利润非常丰厚。
and then the other thing you could do is
然后你还可以做另一件事：
I guess I didn't even think about this
我猜我根本没想过这个问题。
before it would be like size of the
以前它的大小就像
problem it would be value of the
问题在于它的价值
solution and then it would also be
解决方案，然后它也会是
structure of your job so like if you're
你的工作结构，比如如果你是
a copywriter I wouldn't take a job for
我不会接受一份文案撰写的工作
35k what would I do I would say hey pay
35k 我该怎么办？我会说，嘿，付钱。
me what is the salary you want to offer
我想问一下，你们愿意提供的薪资是多少？
35,000 I'll take 10,000 so I can eat
35,000，我要10,000，这样我才能吃饭。
because I'm hungry but can I have a
因为我饿了，但我可以要一个
percentage of The Upside that I drive
我所驾驶的“向上收益”百分比
above and beyond goal so if I'm going to
超出目标，所以如果我要……
write copy that converts into Revenue
撰写能转化为收入的文案
like I'm going to write a funnel for
比如我要写一个销售漏斗图
your biotech company or I'm going to
你的生物技术公司，或者我打算
write a funnel to get investors for you
为你编写一个吸引投资者的销售漏斗。
if right now per month you get $100,000
如果你现在每月能拿到 10 万美元
through that funnel how about you just
通过那个漏斗，你觉得怎么样？
pay me an extra 10 % of everything I
给我额外支付我所有收入的10%。
drive above your 100K so I think that's
你的车里程超过10万公里了，所以我认为是这样。
another way you can make more money is
另一种赚更多钱的方法是
getting smarter on Deal structuring MH
提升交易结构设计水平 MH
well that's actually when I moved into
其实，我就是在那时搬进去的。
biotch how I got paid and when I talked
婊子，我是怎么拿到报酬的，以及我什么时候说话的
about a th being paid a thousand times
大约有 th 被支付了一千次
more than I would have previously it's
比我以前预想的要多得多。
because the way I got paid was in
因为我的工资发放方式是……
options in the IPO brilliant yeah so I
IPO期权很棒，是的，所以我
got given in that particular company I
在那家公司我得到了这份工作
got given 400,000 shares effectively in
实际获得了40万股股票
the company at a certain price um and so
公司以某个价格出售，嗯，就这样。
when the company ipoed at 3.2 billion
该公司首次公开募股时，市值达32亿美元。
dollars on the NASDAQ in July 20 I don't
2020年7月纳斯达克美元指数，我没有
know 21 or something even though I'd
我知道自己大概21岁左右，尽管我
only worked in the company for about 6
只在该公司工作了大约6年
months just helping them build out the
几个月的时间都在帮助他们建设
marketing team I think my like net
营销团队，我觉得我喜欢网络
return was on the equity value at the
回报是基于股权价值计算的。
time was quite close to 10 million so 6
时间非常接近1000万，所以是6
months work 10 million return because I
几个月的工作，1000万的回报，因为我
you know and the re really really the
你知道，而且真的真的
reason I did it was because so
我这么做的原因是……
interested in psychedelics but it just
我对迷幻药感兴趣，但只是
opened my eyes to the fact that any kid
这让我意识到，任何孩子
with social media skills and that knew
具备社交媒体技能，并且知道
how to structure a deal with these
如何与这些公司达成交易
people could have walked in there and
人们可能走进了那里
said give me some stock in this IPO and
他说，给我一些这家IPO公司的股票吧。
I'll run on your social media for 6
我会在你的社交媒体上宣传6天。
months you're so right could have
几个月前你说的太对了，本来可以的。
changed your life yeah and it's it's
是的，它改变了你的人生。
something I'm struggling with trying to
我正在努力尝试解决一个问题。
get people to understand right now is
让人们现在就明白
that even if you never buy a business
即使你从未购买过企业
which is what people fixate on I haven't
这正是人们关注的焦点，但我并没有。
bought a business yet I haven't bought a
买下了一家企业，但我还没有买下……
business yet it's like God you're never
商业，但就像上帝一样，你永远不会
going to regret learning how to do
学会这样做我会后悔的
deals you're never GNA it's I think that
你永远不会遇到GNA的交易，我认为是这样。
is the most valuable skill set in the
是最有价值的技能组合
world I completely agree and it's so
我完全同意，这真是太棒了。
unfair that people don't know about it
不公平的是，人们对此一无所知。
it's so unfair but it's also your fault
这太不公平了，但也有你的错。
if you don't know about it because
如果你不知道这件事，因为
nobody's gatekeeping this information
没有人把关这些信息
anymore it used to be gay kept like when
以前是同性恋，现在却保持着这种状态
I first started off in private Equity I
我最初是从私募股权投资起步的。
wasn't allowed in the rooms where they
不允许进入他们所在的房间。
were actually doing the deals and the
实际上，他们正在进行交易。
terms and if I wanted to see what the
条款，以及如果我想看看什么
final terms were like I had to kind of
最后阶段就像我不得不做的那样
you know sweet talk my way into figuring
你知道，我用甜言蜜语哄骗他们……
out how they structured it but it's an
弄清楚他们是如何构建的，但这是一个
unknown unknown so before I knew I
未知，未知，所以在我意识到之前
didn't know that I didn't know yeah
我不知道，我真的不知道。
that's true yeah that's very true but
没错，确实如此，但是
now I think there's enough people out
现在我觉得外面的人已经够多了。
there talking about it where you're like
他们正在谈论这件事，就像你那样
I mean if you think about whether you
我的意思是，如果你想想你是否
like Donald Trump or not what is he
无论你是否喜欢唐纳德·特朗普，他究竟是什么样的人？
really good at deals the art of the deal
非常擅长交易，交易的艺术
like it it that's it and that is what I
我喜欢它，就是这样，这就是我想要的。
mean Elon Musk how does Tesla actually
埃隆·马斯克到底是怎么看待特斯拉的？
make money they make money through
他们通过以下方式赚钱
credits through credits for solar so he
他通过太阳能积分获得积分。
was able to survive for those 10 years
能够存活那10年
of building that company because he has
他之所以能建立那家公司，是因为他有
some of the best solar tax credits in
一些最好的太阳能税收抵免政策
the world that he negotiated with the
他与之谈判的世界
government so where does one go then
政府，那我们还能去哪儿呢？
where does a 25-year-old kid listening
一个25岁的孩子在哪里听歌
to this go to learn how to make deals
去这里学习如何达成交易
well I have a book coming out yeah
是的，我有一本书要出版了。
called Main Street millionaire yes
被称为“大街百万富翁”？是的。
exciting I know and we have we have
我知道这很令人兴奋，而且我们有……
stuff we can tell tell them about that
我们可以告诉他们一些事情。
later too okay well I'm going to link
稍后也行，好的，我要链接了。
Main Street millionaire below so
下面这位是街头百万富翁
everyone can pre-order it I've
所有人都可以预购，我已经预购了。
pre-ordered I think 10 or 20 copies of
预购数量我想有10到20份。
it maybe a couple more um but that's
可能还有几个，嗯，但也就这些了。
like 30 bucks and you learn almost
花30美元左右，你几乎就能学会所有东西。
everything you need to know about doing
关于做这件事，你需要知道的一切
a deal to start and that book is only
先达成协议，那本书只是
what you need to know I made it on
你需要知道的是，我成功了
purpose not really long not overly
目的不长，也不过度
intense it is exactly what you need to
强度很高，这正是你需要的。
know and then if you like learning deal
了解之后，如果你喜欢学习，那就去做吧。
making and you like that book then you
如果你喜欢那本书，那么你
go to contrarian thinking.com and we
请访问 contrarian thinking.com，我们
have courses and free newsletters and a
提供课程、免费简讯和……
community all about buying businesses um
社区内容涵盖收购企业等方方面面。
but that's where you should start I
但你应该从那里开始。
think I agree because the way that you
我想我同意，因为你的方式
break down information is so accessible
详细的分析信息非常容易获取。
and it really appreciates the naivity of
它真的很欣赏这种天真无邪。
the person on the other end you have a
电话另一端的人
remarkable way of communicating in a way
以一种非凡的方式进行沟通
that's really um yeah inviting versus
那真是……嗯，很有吸引力。
excluding and a lot of people when
排除在外，还有很多人
they're talking about these subjects
他们正在讨论这些话题。
they exclude you and they don't even
他们排斥你，甚至根本不理你。
know that they're doing it because
我知道他们这样做是因为
they're so smart and they're so Advanced
他们非常聪明，而且技术非常先进。
but um I've been lucky enough to take a
但是，嗯，我很幸运地接受了
look at the initial copy of your book
查看一下你书的初稿。
the sort of first draft of it and it was
这算是它的初稿吧。
exactly what I think 99% of people that
这正是我认为99%的人都会想到的。
are listening to this right now need to
现在正在听这个，需要
it's the Gap that they have in their
他们店里有Gap的商品
thinking um so I'd highly recommend
思考了一下，嗯……所以我强烈推荐
everyone go and pre-order I I'm going to
大家都去预购吧，我要去
link it below really really highly
强烈推荐下面的链接
recommend it and if if I'm wrong about
推荐，如果我错了……
that please do send me abuse in my DMs
请随意在我的私信里辱骂我。
yeah exactly well and I spent three
是的，没错，我花了三个月
years writing it and that that was
写了好几年，就是这样。
always the part I was nervous about is
我一直最紧张的部分是
like when I get it to all my smart
就像我把它发给我所有智能设备时一样
friends what are they going to think so
朋友们，他们会怎么想呢？
when I showed it to you and like Andrew
当我把它给你看的时候，就像安德鲁一样。
Wilkinson all these people who had done
威尔金森所有这些人都做过
deals I was like [__] you know are they
我当时就想，去他妈的，你知道他们是什么吗？
going to like it so there's that means a
你会喜欢它，所以这意味着……
lot basically is what I'm heavily
基本上，我非常重视的就是很多事情。
heavily anticipated a lot of people are
备受期待，很多人都在期待
talking about it so I'm very very
谈到这件事，我非常非常
excited um one of one thing I did want
很兴奋，嗯，其中一件我确实想要的东西。
to talk to you about before I just go to
在我去之前想先跟你谈谈。
the last question here is Prejudice
最后一个问题是偏见。
because I don't think people talk about
因为我觉得人们不谈论这个
it enough obviously you and I and really
显然，你和我，真的，这就足够了。
everybody experien Prejudice in business
每个人都会在商业中遇到偏见。
and in life in wealth and everything
在生活中，在财富和一切方面。
investing whatever it might
投资任何东西
be what is your perspective on that when
你对此有何看法？
I say Prejudice I mean you're a woman in
我说偏见，我的意思是，你是个女人
business I'm a I was a young black guy
我是一名商人，我曾经是一个年轻的黑人
at one point that had a big afro and was
他曾经留着蓬松的爆炸头，而且
very very poor trying to make it in life
生活非常非常糟糕，努力想在这个世界上生存下去
what relationship should we have with
我们应该与……建立怎样的关系
the Prejudice we face I had a woman ask
我们所面临的偏见，我曾被一位女士问到
me the other day um how do I show up as
前几天我问他，我该如何以……的身份出现
a woman in a male-dominated industry
一位在男性主导行业中工作的女性
because you've you've done that Cody and
因为你已经这么做了，科迪，而且
I and she said I had I've had struggles
我和她说我经历过一些困难
with it and my feeling and response on
以及我对它的感受和反应
it is this that what do you think the
这就是你认为的？
universe gives you when you tell the
当你告诉宇宙时，它会给你什么？
universe that I struggle because I am a
我挣扎于这个宇宙，因为我是一个
woman in business it's going to give you
女企业家会给你带来什么
struggle what do you think the un would
你认为联合国会如何应对？
give you if instead you said I have such
如果你说我有这样的东西，我就会给你。
incredible opportunity because I look
绝佳的机会，因为我看起来
different than everybody here and if I
与这里所有人都不一样，如果我
am good I am so much more memorable than
我很好，我比任何人都更令人难忘。
every Tom Dick and Larry in a blue suit
每个穿着蓝色西装的汤姆、迪克和拉里
that looks just like everybody else what
看起来和其他人没什么两样，是吗？
if the thing that you think is your
如果你认为的是你的东西
biggest weakness and the thing that
最大的弱点，也是最……
makes you feel excluded and less than is
让你感到被排斥和低人一等
actually your biggest strength and if
实际上，你最大的优势是……
you could flip your mindset on that how
你可以转变一下你对这件事的看法。
much more money and opportunity would
更多金钱和机会
you have and how much more interesting
你拥有的，还有多么有趣啊！
would you be for other people who are
你会为其他人做些什么呢？
wealthy and successful to be around do
和富有成功人士在一起会很愉快
you want to be around somebody who is
你想和这样的人在一起：
labelings as a victim and complaining
被贴上受害者标签并抱怨
all the time or do you want to be around
一直都想待在附近吗？还是你想待在附近？
somebody who thinks that the world is
认为世界是
full of
充满
opportunity and it's a hard lesson to
机会，也是一个惨痛的教训
learn because the truth of it is
学习是因为真相是
business is hard you will be [__] on
做生意很难，你会吃亏的。
people will keep you out people will
人们会把你挡在外面，人们会
judge you for your skin color and being
因为你的肤色而评判你，以及你的身份
a woman or a man or not for sure but
是女人还是男人，或者不确定，但是
don't let that into your psyche instead
不要让这种想法影响你的内心。
choose the opposite and Watch What
选择相反的选项，然后观看。
Happens so interesting it's so um it's
事情发生得太有趣了，简直……
so difficult to say that because you're
很难说出口，因为你
not denying the reality that prejudice
不否认偏见的现实
is real no you're giving people the most
真的吗？不，你给了人们最多的
optimal productive way to move forward
前进的最佳高效方式
in spite of it exactly yeah it's like
尽管如此，没错，就像
serves you they do not they don't like
他们不为你服务，他们不喜欢你
it no no people don't want to say that
不，不，人们不想这么说。
they want to be V some people want to be
他们想成为V，有些人想成为
victims of their Prejudice it's true I
的确，我是他们偏见的受害者。
think the tide is turning I mean I for
我觉得风向正在转变，我的意思是，我
the first time ever you know I posted
你知道，我第一次发帖
the other week and I was like well we
前几周，我就想，我们
might get a we might get something
我们可能会得到一些东西
interesting on here and like for
这里的内容很有趣，喜欢。
instance I believe that the word I call
例如，我相信我所说的这个词
it latinx because I think it's funny but
我觉得拉丁裔很有趣，但
Latin X is the most ridiculous thing you
Latin X 是最荒谬的东西
could ever call a Latino why because it
为什么会有人称拉丁裔为拉丁裔呢？因为
doesn't exist in our language Spanish
在我们的语言西班牙语中不存在。
the word Latins makes no sense to
“拉丁人”这个词毫无意义
anybody so I think it was made up by a
所以我觉得这是编造的。
bunch of white people at Berkeley is my
伯克利的一群白人是我的
joke and that in fact if you went to
开玩笑，事实上，如果你去
Latin America and you said you know how
拉丁美洲，你说你知道如何
does it feel to be a latinx person they
身为拉丁裔是什么感觉？
would laugh you out of the room they'd
他们会把你笑出房间的。
have no idea what you're talking about
我完全不知道你在说什么。
and and I said that on social media and
而且我在社交媒体上也说过这话。
I thought I was going to get so much
我以为我会得到很多
hate that I would would like have to not
讨厌我本想这么做，但我不得不这么做
look at it for a while and what happened
仔细观察一会儿，看看发生了什么。
a bunch of people are like you know what
一群人就像，你知道吗？
yeah I agree so I actually think that if
是的，我同意，所以我其实觉得如果
you want to beat the curve today do not
如果你想今天就超越曲线，那就不要
be woke do not be annoying and
保持清醒，但不要令人讨厌。
victimized and woke instead watch what
受害者和觉醒者反而观看什么
happens when you start being a little
当你开始变得有点……的时候就会发生这种情况
based today when you start saying the
基于今天，当你开始说
quiet part out loud and for the first
把安静的部分大声说出来，这是第一次
time in like probably since preco um I
大概从 Preco 开始，时间过得挺快的。
think the world is changing and I don't
我认为世界正在改变，而我并不这么认为。
think that means you should be a jerk or
认为这意味着你应该做个混蛋吗？
be divisive and I think we should like
造成分裂，我认为我们应该喜欢
protect comedy at all costs especially
不惜一切代价保护喜剧，尤其如此。
in dark times but um I do think that
在黑暗时期，但是，嗯，我确实认为
that type of person is no longer
那种人已经不再是了。
interesting and if I'm right that means
有趣，如果我没理解错的话，这意味着
that a lot of young people have to
很多年轻人不得不
change our perspective because for a
改变我们的视角，因为
long time we' have been able to get away
我们已经很久没有逃离了。
with things like saying because I am a
比如说因为我是一个
woman because I am a Latino because of
因为我是拉丁裔，所以我是个女人
this you should give me that and I think
你应该把这个给我，我觉得
the world right now is starting to say I
现在全世界都在说“我”。
don't [__] care we're all human and
我他妈才不在乎，我们都是人，
that's uninteresting to me so we'll see
我对此不感兴趣，所以我们拭目以待吧。
if I'm right or you can tell me in the
如果我没理解错，或者你可以告诉我。
YouTube comments if I'm just a a
YouTube评论区，如果我只是一个……
privileged [__] no it's interesting
那个享有特权的混蛋？不，这很有意思。
because you said something earlier and I
因为你之前说过一些话，而我
remember thinking most people wouldn't
记得当时我想大多数人不会这么做。
have the guts to say that and it was
有胆量说出那番话，而且确实如此。
when you were referring to your working
当你提到你的工作时
culture at your company where you're
你所在公司的文化
saying if you if you talk to me about
我说，如果你跟我谈论……
work life balance in an interview you're
在面试中谈到工作与生活平衡时，你
not going to get the job yeah even
肯定得不到这份工作，真的。
saying that a couple of years ago would
说几年前会
have sparked outrage Cody says that if
科迪表示，如果引发众怒，
you mentioned work life balance in
你提到了工作与生活的平衡
interview but what you're actually being
面试，但你实际经历的是……
is honest honest you're being honest and
诚实就是诚实，你很诚实。
people don't like honest they'd rather
人们不喜欢诚实的人，他们宁愿……
you lie didn't signal did some virtue
你的谎言没有发出信号，也没有展现出任何美德
signaling then just be really honest
发出信号后，一定要非常坦诚。
about how you feel yeah that's true and
关于你的感受，是的，没错。
maybe you're toxic but at least you're
或许你为人有毒，但至少你……
honest about it do you know what I mean
说实话，你明白我的意思吗？
it's it's so true I think the worst
确实如此，我觉得最糟糕的情况是……
thing that you could do is pretend to be
你可以做的一件事就是假装是
something that you're not especially in
你并不特别喜欢的东西
this age of no trust on the internet all
在这个互联网上毫无信任的时代
that means is that you're going to get
这意味着你将会得到
canceled it's like what we saw happen
取消了，就像我们看到的那样。
with Ellen right yeah like everybody was
和艾伦一起，对，就像每个人都一样。
like Ellen's the nicest person in the
艾伦是世界上最善良的人。
world and Ellen is probably like the
世界和艾伦可能就像……
rest of us human we're 20% of the time
我们其余的人，只有20%的时间是人类。
she's crazy or rude or mean or having a
她疯了、粗鲁了、刻薄了，或者有某种……
bad day or gets on her high horse cuz
心情不好或者摆出一副高高在上的样子
she's super successful or gets out of
她要么非常成功，要么逃脱了。
touch and then but what happens because
触摸，然后会发生什么？因为
Ellen said that she was nice all the
艾伦说她一直都很友善。
time she was perfect she was whatever
她曾经完美无瑕，她就是那样
when somebody finds that out about you
当别人发现你的这件事时
then they cancel you because you were a
然后他们取消了你的资格，因为你是……
liar and so instead I think the better
骗子，所以我认为更好的选择是……
thing to do is be like I'm human I'm
应该做的就是像个普通人一样。
flawed I'm really intense I'm kind of
有缺陷，我性格很强烈，我有点……
hard to work for sometimes but I also
有时候工作起来很辛苦，但我也是
help make my people make more money than
帮助我的人民赚更多的钱
they could anywhere else and if you want
他们可能去其他任何地方，如果你想的话
to be exceptional and in a group where
要出类拔萃，并且身处一个这样的群体中
we pride ourselves on being the most
我们以成为最……而自豪
productive people in the world um then
世界上那些富有生产力的人，嗯……
there to love it at my company and let's
在我的公司里，我热爱这份工作，让我们一起努力吧！
just be honest about it we have a
坦诚点，我们有一个
closing tradition where the Las leaves a
结尾的传统是拉斯离开
question for the next the question
下一个问题
that's been left for you is what is one
留给你的就是其中之一。
business idea you've always wanted to
你一直想实现的商业想法
try but never seem to get to what's held
尝试过，但似乎永远无法得到想要的东西。
you back it's almost like they knew you
你回来了，感觉他们好像早就认识你一样。
were coming it is almost like they knew
他们来了，就好像他们早就知道似的。
um K that's a good question I'm really
嗯，好的，这是一个很好的问题，我真的
good at taking my interests to the
善于将我的兴趣爱好发展成……
finish line
终点线
um I think when I get to my Tombstone
嗯，我想当我到达我的墓碑时
there's not going to be much that I
不会有太多……
regret at the end of my days because
临终之际，我感到无比后悔，因为
I've tried just about everything that I
我几乎尝试了所有方法。
wanted to um and I feel very privileged
想说的是，我感到非常荣幸。
to have been able to do that thus
能够做到这一点
far oh I do have one
哦，我确实有一个。
though you know what I've always want to
虽然你知道我一直想做什么
do that maybe at some point I'll get to
也许在某个时候我会那样做。
is what's the most powerful book that's
最有力量的书是什么？
ever lived the Bible arguably right if
如果一个人真的按照圣经生活过，那么圣经或许是对的。
we just say by total viewers over time
我们只是按总观看人数随时间的变化来统计。
and I think the reason why is because
我认为原因在于……
it's a story it's like truth and
这是一个故事，它就像真相一样。
guidance in a story and one thing that
故事中的指引和一件事
I've always wanted to do is write a book
我一直想做的就是写一本书。
that was a story that told people some
那是一个向人们讲述一些故事的故事
truths fiction yeah and so I think at
真相与虚构，是的，所以我认为
some point in my life I'd like to do I
我人生中的某个阶段想做一件事
suppose a parable would be the word that
假设寓言就是这个词……
I'd use I would like to write a book
我想写一本书
that's a that's a fiction story that's
那是一个虚构的故事。
Beau that transcends that lets people
超越这一点的博让人们
escape and like secretly you don't even
逃脱，就像偷偷摸摸地逃走一样，你甚至都不知道自己逃走了。
realize it it's getting into your brain
意识到它正在进入你的大脑吗？
and it's teaching you things and I don't
它教给你一些东西，而我却没有。
know if that's a business but that is
不知道那是不是一家公司，但那是
one thing that I have not done yet Cody
科迪，我还有一件事没做。
thank you so much um you're a real real
非常感谢，你真是个好人。
you're a real Beacon of wisdom and
你真是智慧的灯塔！
inspiration and hope and optimism in a
灵感、希望和乐观
world that needs it so so much and
世界如此迫切地需要它
you're also a wonderful human on and off
你无论在场边还是场边都是个很棒的人。
camera so thank you so much for your um
相机，非常感谢你的嗯
so for just being a wonderful person and
所以，仅仅因为你是一个很棒的人，
doing so much for so many people that
为这么多人做了很多事
I'll never get to say thank you to you
我永远也没机会对你说声谢谢了
but they come up to me all the time in
但他们总是主动来找我。
the gym
健身房
the Chads and they they tell me how much
那些查德们，他们告诉我多少钱
they appreciate you so oh stop it you're
他们很感激你，所以哦，别这样了，你
going to give me allergies then people
会让我过敏的，然后人们
are going to not you know I have a black
你知道我有一个黑色的
heart and they're going to see the truth
他们会看清真相，他们的心会明白的。
that I'm kind of nice you don't have a
我人挺好的，你没有
black heart thank you so much Cody
黑心，非常感谢你，科迪
really appreciate it thanks
非常感谢！
[Music]
[音乐]
oh
哦